<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Phd on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/categories/phd/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Phd on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 05:03:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/categories/phd/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ACEMS Business Analytics Prize 2016</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/acems-prize-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 05:03:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/acems-prize-2016/</guid>
      <description>We have established a new annual prize for research students at Monash University in the general area of business analytics, funded by the Australian Centre of Excellence in Mathematical and Statistical Frontiers (ACEMS). The rules of the award are listed below.
 The student must have submitted a paper to a high quality journal or refereed conference on some topic in the general area of business analytics, computational statistics or data visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travelling Thilaksha</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/travelling-thilaksha/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 07:23:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/travelling-thilaksha/</guid>
      <description>One of my PhD students, Thilaksha Tharanganie, has been very successful in getting travel funding to attend conferences. She was the subject of a write-up in today&amp;rsquo;s Monash News.
We encourage students to attend conferences, and provide funding for them to attend one international conference and one local conference during their PhD candidature. Thilaksha was previously funded to attend last year&amp;rsquo;s COMPSTAT in Geneva, Switzerland and IMS conference in Sydney. Having exhausted local funding, she has now convinced several other organizations to support her conference habit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paperpile makes me more productive</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/paperpile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 02:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/paperpile/</guid>
      <description>One of the first things I tell my new research students is to use a reference management system to help them keep track of the papers they read, and to assist in creating bib files for their bibliography. Most of them use Mendeley, one or two use Zotero. Both do a good job and both are free.
I use neither. I did use Mendeley for several years, but it became slower and slower to sync as my reference collection grew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Establishing priority</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/establishing-priority/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 03:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/establishing-priority/</guid>
      <description>The nature of research is that other people are probably working on similar ideas to you, and it is possible that someone will beat you to publishing them.When I was working on my PhD, I discovered another PhD thesis by Iris Yeung at UKC with almost exactly the same title as mine, and published a year earlier. In those days, a copy of a thesis had to be printed from microfiche, and then posted by snail mail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What you wish you knew before you started a PhD</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/wishlist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 12:34:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/wishlist/</guid>
      <description>I asked my research group recently what they wished they had learned before they started work on a PhD. Here are some of the responses. More mathematics. Particular topics they named included real analysis, functional analysis, measure theory, algebra, linear algebra. That would have been my response also. I still wish I knew more mathematics than I do. I did quite a lot of mathematics as an undergraduate, but every year I need to learn some more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fail a PhD</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/phdfail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 13:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/phdfail/</guid>
      <description>I read an interesting post today by Matt Might on &amp;ldquo;10 reasons PhD students fail&amp;rdquo;, and I thought it might be helpful to reflect on some of the barriers to PhD completion that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen. Matt&amp;rsquo;s ideas are not all relevant to Australian PhDs, so I have come up with my own list below. Here are the seven steps to failure.
1. Wait for your supervisor to tell you what to do A good supervisor will not tell you what to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to do when the PhD is finished?</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 06:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/jobs/</guid>
      <description>So you&amp;rsquo;re wondering what to do once your PhD is finally completed? First, take a holiday. Completing a PhD is an intense and draining exercise, and you should take some time to refresh.
Then you need to decide what career path you prefer. In statistics, there are three choices: the academic route, the semi-academic route and the business route.
Academic route Most PhD students would like an academic job. In fact, I think all of my PhD students have rather fancied my job!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 7 secrets of highly successful PhD students</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/7secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 07:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/7secrets/</guid>
      <description>It seems everyone has 7 secrets to success, and now someone has hopped on the 7-secrets bandwagon with something for PhD students. Thinkwell is an Australian company offering a seminar and associated work book on &amp;ldquo;The 7 secrets of highly successful PhD students&amp;rdquo;. I bought the book out of curiosity, but &amp;ldquo;book&amp;rdquo; is a gross exaggeration &amp;ndash; only eleven pages of fairly simplistic advice. I hope the seminar has more substance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>