<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kaggle on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/categories/kaggle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kaggle on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 09:33:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/categories/kaggle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Seminars in Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/seminars-in-taiwan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 09:33:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/seminars-in-taiwan/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently visiting Taiwan and I&amp;rsquo;m giving two seminars while I&amp;rsquo;m here &amp;mdash; one at the National Tsing Hua University in Hsinchu, and the other at Academia Sinica in Taipei. Details are below for those who might be nearby.Automatic Time Series Forecasting College of Technology Management, Institute of Service Science, National Tsing Hua University, Hsinchu 時間及地點：2015.1.7 (Wed.) 5pm @ TSMC building, 6F, room 622. 台積館6F孫運璿紀念中心 Many applications require a large number of time series to be forecast completely automatically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction competitions</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/prediction-competitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 12:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/prediction-competitions/</guid>
      <description>Competitions have a long history in forecasting and prediction, and have been instrumental in forcing research attention on methods that work well in practice. In the forecasting community, the M competition and M3 competition have been particularly influential. The data mining community have the annual KDD cup which has generated attention on a wide range of prediction problems and associated methods. Recent KDD cups are hosted on kaggle.
In my research group meeting today, we discussed our (limited) experiences in competing in some Kaggle competitions, and we reviewed the following two papers which describe two prediction competitions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GEFCom 2014 energy forecasting competition is underway</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/gefcom-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 05:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/gefcom-2014/</guid>
      <description>GEFCom 2014 is the most advanced energy forecasting competition ever organized, both in terms of the data involved, and in terms of the way the forecasts will be evaluated.
So everyone interested in energy forecasting should head over to the competition webpage and start forecasting: www.gefcom.org.
This time, the competition is hosted on CrowdANALYTIX rather than Kaggle.
Highlights of GEFCom2014:
 An upgraded edition from GEFCom2012
 Four tracks: electric load, electricity price, wind power and solar power forecasting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New jobs in business analytics at Monash</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/monash-business-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 12:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/monash-business-analytics/</guid>
      <description>We have an exciting new initiative at Monash University with some new positions in business analytics. This is part of a plan to strengthen our research and teaching in the data science/computational statistics area. We are hoping to make multiple appointments, at junior and senior levels. These are five-year appointments, but we hope that the positions will continue after that if we can secure suitable funding.What is business analytics? You can think of &amp;ldquo;business analytics&amp;rdquo; as the application of data analysis to business problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global energy forecasting competitions</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/gefcom2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 07:12:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/gefcom2014/</guid>
      <description>The 2012 GEFcom competition was a great success with several new innovative forecasting methods introduced. These have been published in the IJF as follows: Hong, Pinson and Fan. Global Energy Forecasting Competition 2012
 Charleton and Singleton. A refined parametric model for short term load forecasting
 Lloyd. GEFCom2012 hierarchical load forecasting: Gradient boosting machines and Gaussian processes
 Nedelec, Cugliari and Goude: GEFCom2012: Electric load forecasting and backcasting with semi-parametric models</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic Energy Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/probabilistic-energy-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 04:07:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/probabilistic-energy-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>The International Journal of Forecasting is calling for papers on probabilistic energy forecasting. Here are the details (taken from Tao Hong&amp;rsquo;s blog).In today&amp;rsquo;s competitive and dynamic environment, more and more decision making processes in the energy industry are relying on probabilistic forecasts. The applications of probabilistic energy forecasts spread across planning and operations of the entire energy value chain. We are seeking papers from researchers working on the areas of probabilistic energy forecasting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kaggle on TV</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/kaggle-on-tv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2011 23:08:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/kaggle-on-tv/</guid>
      <description>It is good to see forecasting algorithms getting some mainstream exposure on ABC Catalyst.
Update: See also this great talk by Jeremy Howard, a data scientist from Melbourne and now part of Kaggle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crowd sourcing forecasts</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/crowd-sourcing-forecasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2011 04:09:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/crowd-sourcing-forecasts/</guid>
      <description>Forecasting Ace is looking for participants to develop improved methods for predicting future events and outcomes. Their goal is to develop methods for aggregating many individual judgments in a manner that yields more accurate predictions than any one person or small group alone could provide. Potential applications of the system include forecasting economic conditions, political changes, technological development and medical breakthroughs. They are currently seeking to recruit individuals who have interest (and/or expertise) in any of a wide range of current affairs, including but not limited to politics, economics, technology, military affairs, social trends, and science and technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tourism forecasting competition ends</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/tfc2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2010 12:52:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/tfc2/</guid>
      <description>And the winners are &amp;hellip; Jeremy Howard and Lee C Baker. (See my earlier post for information about the competition.)
Jeremy describes his approach to seasonal time series in a blog post on Kaggle.com. Lee described his approach to annual time series in an earlier post.
A few lessons that come out of this:
 For data from a single industry, using a global trend (i.e., estimated across all series) can be useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tourism forecasting competition results: part one</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/tfc1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 09:23:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/tfc1/</guid>
      <description>The first stage of the tourism forecasting competition on kaggle has finished. This stage involved forecasting 518 annual time series. Twenty one teams beat our Theta method benchmark which is a great result, and well beyond our expectations. Congratulations to Lee Baker for winning stage one.
I am yet to learn what methods the top teams were using, but we hope to write up a paper for the IJF describing the results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The tourism forecasting competition</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/tourism-forecasting-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2010 05:08:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/tourism-forecasting-competition/</guid>
      <description>Recently I wrote a paper entitled &amp;ldquo;The tourism forecasting competition&amp;rdquo; in which we (i.e., George Athanasopoulos, Haiyan Song, Doris Wu and I) compared various forecasting methods on a relatively large set of tourism-related time series. The paper has been accepted for publication in the International Journal of Forecasting. (When I submit a paper to the IJF it is always handled by another editor. In this case, Mike Clements handled the paper and it went through several revisions before it was finally accepted.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>