<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technology on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/categories/technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technology on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 12:00:25 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/categories/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Q&amp;A: predictive analytics</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/qa-predictive-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 12:00:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/qa-predictive-analytics/</guid>
      <description>A major news outlet interviewed me on predictive analytics. Here were my responses. Data mining is not just for tech companies, in fact it can be especially useful for industries which are not typically thought of to be &amp;lsquo;innovative&amp;rsquo; such as agriculture. What are some of the main industries that you think benefit from predictive analysis?
 Any industry that collects data can use data mining and statistical modelling.
Agriculture is becoming a heavy user of data science methods, with data being collected on every aspect of crop or livestock health and development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paperpile makes me more productive</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/paperpile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 02:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/paperpile/</guid>
      <description>One of the first things I tell my new research students is to use a reference management system to help them keep track of the papers they read, and to assist in creating bib files for their bibliography. Most of them use Mendeley, one or two use Zotero. Both do a good job and both are free.
I use neither. I did use Mendeley for several years, but it became slower and slower to sync as my reference collection grew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlighting the web</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/highlighting-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 01:29:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/highlighting-the-web/</guid>
      <description>Users of my new online forecasting book have asked about having a facility for personal highlighting of selected sections, as students often do with print books. We have plans to make this a built-in part of the platform, but for now it is possible to do it using a simple browser extension. This approach allows any website to be highlighted, so is even more useful than if we only had the facility on OTexts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet surveys</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/surveys/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 23:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/surveys/</guid>
      <description>I received the following email today:
 I am preparing a thesis &amp;hellip; I need to conduct the widest possible poll, and it occurred to me that perhaps you could guide me toward an internet-based way in which this can be done easily. I have a ten-question questionnaire prepared, that I wish to have an random sample of the population respond to. I have no budget for this, so I hope you can suggest a way in which a good number of responses can be harvested using blogs or sites you may be aware of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizing travel</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2011 13:12:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/travel/</guid>
      <description>Whether travelling to a seminar or conference, or just having a holiday, using a travel organizer can make the process simpler and easier. A good travel organizer keeps all your travel details (flights, hotels, car rentals, meetings, weather forecasts, etc.) organized and synced to whatever devices you use (two computers, an iPad and an iPhone in my case).I am aware of four travel organizers that do this: TripIt, TripCase, WorldMate and Wipolo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social networking for researchers</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/socialnetworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2011 02:39:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/socialnetworks/</guid>
      <description>It would be nice to have a place to share ideas, links, comments in a very informal way with others involved in research in statistical methodology and data science. CrossValidated.com is great for specific questions, but is not suitable for commenting on papers or sharing ideas and links.Although I have a facebook account, this seems the wrong place to carry out a research discussion because my family and friends are generally not interested, and it is messy to restrict posts to groups of friends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In praise of Dropbox</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/dropbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 01:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/dropbox/</guid>
      <description>Every couple of years, a new technology has a big impact on how I work. Gmail was one. My iPhone was another. And I rank Dropbox in the same category.
I get three huge benefits in using Dropbox:
 All my files are backed up online. The house can burn down and I know I can still get my files. Also, if I&amp;rsquo;m away from my desktop or laptop, I can still access my files on my iPhone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematical research and the internet</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/tao-lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 02:21:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/tao-lecture/</guid>
      <description>On Monday night I attended a lecture by Terry Tao on &amp;ldquo;Mathematical research and the internet&amp;rdquo;. Terry is Australia&amp;rsquo;s most famous mathematician, our only Field&amp;rsquo;s medalist, and one of the most active mathematical bloggers in the world. He has been described as the &amp;ldquo;Mozart of mathematics&amp;rdquo; for his remarkable precocity and prolific output. The slides of his talk are available on his blog site.
It was an interesting talk, with excellent slides, marred only by the poor sound system and his bad habit of mumbling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neil Postman on technological change</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/neil-postman-on-technological-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2009 08:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/neil-postman-on-technological-change/</guid>
      <description>Neil Postman was Professor of Communication at New York University until his death in 2003. He wrote many wonderfully insightful and thought-provoking articles and books about television, education, technology and childhood. I recently came across a speech he gave in 1998 on &amp;ldquo;Five things we need to know about technological change&amp;rdquo;. Here is an online transcript. The five things are:
 That we always pay a price for technology; the greater the technology, the greater the price.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>