<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Refereeing on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/categories/refereeing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Refereeing on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 10:50:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/categories/refereeing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice to other journal editors</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/finding-reviewers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 10:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/finding-reviewers/</guid>
      <description>I get asked to review journal papers almost every day, and I have to say no to almost all of them. I know it is hard to find reviewers, but many of these requests indicate very lazy editors. So to all the editors out there looking for reviewers, here is some advice.
 Never ask someone who is an editor for another journal. I am handling about 500 submissions per year for the International Journal of Forecasting, and about 10 per year for the Journal of Statistical Software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common reasons for rejection</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-rejections/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 04:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-rejections/</guid>
      <description>Every week I reject some papers submitted to the International Journal of Forecasting, without sending the papers off to associate editors or reviewers. Here are five of the most common reasons for rejection.1. Wrong Journal Submissions to the IJF should be about forecasting, obviously. But we often get papers on econometrics, or time series analysis, or something else that is not forecasting. Even if a paper has some implications for forecasting, if these are not discussed at all, the paper is not within scope for the journal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing an R package in the Journal of Statistical Software</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/jss-rpackages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 05:41:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/jss-rpackages/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been an editor of JSS for the last few years, and as a result I tend to get email from people asking me about publishing papers describing R packages in JSS. So for all those wondering, here are some general comments.JSS prefers to publish papers about packages where the package is on CRAN and has been there long enough to have matured (i.e., obvious bugs ironed out and a few active users).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get your paper rejected quickly</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/quick-rejection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 01:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/quick-rejection/</guid>
      <description>I sent this rejection letter this morning about a paper submitted to the International Journal of Forecasting.
 Dear XXXXX.
I am writing to you regarding manuscript ????? entitled &amp;ldquo;xxxxxxxxxxxx&amp;rdquo; which you submitted to the International Journal of Forecasting.
It so happens that I am aware that this paper was previously reviewed for the YYYYYYY journal. It seems that you have not bothered to make any of the changes recommended by the reviewers of your submission to YYYYYYY.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Establishing priority</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/establishing-priority/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 03:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/establishing-priority/</guid>
      <description>The nature of research is that other people are probably working on similar ideas to you, and it is possible that someone will beat you to publishing them.When I was working on my PhD, I discovered another PhD thesis by Iris Yeung at UKC with almost exactly the same title as mine, and published a year earlier. In those days, a copy of a thesis had to be printed from microfiche, and then posted by snail mail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read the literature</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/read-the-literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 04:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/read-the-literature/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just finished another reviewer report for a journal, and yet again I&amp;rsquo;ve had to make comments about reading the literature. It&amp;rsquo;s not difficult. Before you write a paper, read what other people have done. A simple search on Google scholar will usually do the trick. And before you submit a paper, check again that you haven&amp;rsquo;t missed anything important.
The paper I reviewed today did not cite a single reference from either of the two most active research groups in the area in the last ten years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refereeing a journal article</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/refereeing2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 02:50:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/refereeing2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written briefly on this before. For an excellent and more detailed discussion of what is involved, there is a series of excellent posts on Pat Thomson&amp;rsquo;s blog:
 Refereeing a journal article part 1: reading
 Refereeing a journal article part 2: making a recommendation
 Refereeing a journal article part 3: writing the feedback
  If every reviewer followed her advice, my life as an editor would be much easier, and the quality of research would be improved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a referee</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/refereeing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2011 22:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/refereeing/</guid>
      <description>I regularly get emails from people wanting to be referees for the International Journal of Forecasting, usually with an accompanying CV. This is not how the process works.
Referees are almost always selected because they have previously written papers on a similar topic to the manuscript under review. If you want to be a referee, then write good papers and get them published in scholarly journals. Very quickly you will be invited to referee papers in the same journals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to avoid annoying a referee</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/how-to-avoid-annoying-a-referee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2010 09:23:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/how-to-avoid-annoying-a-referee/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s not a good idea to annoy the referees of your paper. They make recommendations to the editor about your work and it is best to keep them happy. There is an interesting discussion on stats.stackexchange.com on this subject. This inspired my own list below.
 Explain what you&amp;rsquo;ve done clearly, avoiding unnecessary jargon. Don&amp;rsquo;t claim your paper contributes more than it actually does. (I refereed a paper this week where the author claimed to have invented principal component analysis!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Always listen to reviewers</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/always-listen-to-reviewers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 03:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/always-listen-to-reviewers/</guid>
      <description>This week I was asked to review a paper that I had seen before. It had been submitted to a journal a few months ago and I had written a detailed report describing some problems with the paper, and noting a large number of typos that needed fixing. That journal had rejected the paper, the authors had submitted it to a second journal, and the paper ended up on my desk again for review.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joining an editorial board</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/editorialboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 05:51:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/editorialboards/</guid>
      <description>Being on the editorial board of a journal is a lot of work. I&amp;rsquo;m currently Editor-in-Chief of the International Journal of Forecasting and previously I&amp;rsquo;ve been Theory &amp;amp; Methods Editor of the Australian &amp;amp; New Zealand Journal of Statistics. Although it is time-consuming and often goes un-noticed, there are some important rewards that make it worthwhile in my opinion.
 You are forced to read carefully a lot of papers in your area of interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should you make your working papers public?</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/working-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 08:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/working-papers/</guid>
      <description>There seems to be two points of view on this with different practices in different disciplines.
 Some researchers do not make their work public until after it has been accepted for publication in a journal. Until that time, drafts of papers are only circulated to close confidants and usually marked &amp;ldquo;Do not distribute&amp;rdquo;.
 Working papers are published on web sites and in web repositories (such as arXiv or RePEc) as soon as they are finished, at about the same time they are submitted to a journal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why referee?</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/why-referee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 04:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/why-referee/</guid>
      <description>There are several reasons why researchers should be willing to provide referee reports.
 You learn a lot. If the paper is in your area, then writing a referee report forces you to read it very carefully and engage closely with the research of other people in your field. There&amp;rsquo;s no better way of understand what is going on in your field.
 You get better known by the research leaders in your area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a referee report</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/referee-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 04:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/referee-reports/</guid>
      <description>As an editor, I like to see referee reports comprising three sections:
 A general summary of the paper and the contribution it makes. You need to highlight here what is new and interesting about the paper, as well as give a summary in a few sentences.
 The major problems that need addressing. This is probably the most important section of your report where you explain the main problems. The editor will read this very carefully when deciding whether to accept, reject or invite a revision, so you need to make sure that any problems are clearly explained here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>