<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Latex on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/categories/latex/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Latex on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 23:00:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/categories/latex/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Software for honours students</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/software-for-honours-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 23:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/software-for-honours-students/</guid>
      <description>I spoke to our new crop of honours students this morning. Here are my slides, example files and links.
 
Managing References  Mendeley Zotero Paperpile  Data analysis and computation  Download R Download Rstudio Online R tutorial R packages for time series R packages for econometrics R packages for finance  Writing your thesis LaTeX  Windows: Download MikTeX Mac OSX: Download MacTeX Linux: Check your usual software source for TeXLive; otherwise install TeX Live directly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monash Rmarkdown templates on github</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/monash-rmarkdown-templates-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 21:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/monash-rmarkdown-templates-on-github/</guid>
      <description>Rmarkdown templates for staff and students in my department are now available on github. For a thesis, fork the repository MonashThesis.
For other templates, install the R package MonashEBSTemplates R package. This provides templates for
 beamer slides working papers exams letters  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rmarkdown template for a Monash working paper</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/rmarkdown-template/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2016 10:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/rmarkdown-template/</guid>
      <description>This is only directly relevant to my Monash students and colleagues, but the same idea might be useful for adapting to other institutions.
Some recent changes in the rmarkdown and bookdown packages mean that it is now possible to produce working papers in exactly the same format as we previously used with LaTeX.Just install the MonashEBSTemplates package from github. You also need a recent version of LaTeX.
Then from within RStudio, create a new document by selecting &amp;ldquo;Rmarkdown&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;From Template&amp;rdquo;, and select &amp;ldquo;Monash EBS Working Paper&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducibility in computational research</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/reproducibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 07:31:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/reproducibility/</guid>
      <description>Jane Frazier spoke at our research team meeting today on &amp;ldquo;Reproducibility in computational research&amp;rdquo;. We had a very stimulating and lively discussion about the issues involved. One interesting idea was that reproducibility is on a scale, and we can all aim to move further along the scale towards making our own research more reproducible. For example
 Can you reproduce your results tomorrow on the same computer with the same software installed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematical annotations on R plots</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex2exp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 07:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex2exp/</guid>
      <description>I’ve always struggled with using plotmath via the expression function in R for adding mathematical notation to axes or legends. For some reason, the most obvious way to write something never seems to work for me and I end up using trial and error in a loop with far too many iterations.
So I am very happy to see the new latex2exp package available which translates LaTeX expressions into a form suitable for R graphs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark themes for writing</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/dark-themes-for-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 04:55:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/dark-themes-for-writing/</guid>
      <description>I spend much of my day sitting in front of a screen, coding or writing. To limit the strain on my eyes, I use a dark theme as much as possible. That is, I write with light colored text on a dark background. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why this is not the default in more software as it makes a big difference after a few hours of writing.
Most of the time, I am writing using either Sublime Text, RStudio or TeXstudio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>biblatex for statisticians</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/biblatex-for-statisticians/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2014 03:37:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/biblatex-for-statisticians/</guid>
      <description>I am now using biblatex for all my bibliographic work as it seems to have developed enough to be stable and reliable. The big advantage of biblatex is that it is easy to format the bibliography to conform to specific journal or publisher styles. It is also possible to have structured bibliographies (e.g., divided into sections: books, papers, R packages, etc.) Here is my default setting which should be suitable for almost all statistics and econometrics journals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a handout from beamer slides</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/beamer-handout/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 01:29:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/beamer-handout/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m about to head off on a speaking tour to Europe (more on that in another post) and one of my hosts has asked for my powerpoint slides so they can print them. They have made two false assumptions: (1) that I use powerpoint; (2) that my slides are static so they can be printed.
Instead, I produced a cut-down version of my beamer slides, leaving out some of the animations and other features that will not print easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating tables in LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/generating-tables-in-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 23:23:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/generating-tables-in-latex/</guid>
      <description>Typing tables in LaTeX can get messy, but there are some good tools to simplify the process. One I discovered this week is tablesgenerator.com, a web-based tool for generating LaTeX tables. It also allows the table to saved in other formats including HTML and Markdown. The interface is simple, but it does most things. For complicated tables, some additional formatting may be necessary.
Similar functionality is available via plugins in Excel, OpenOffice and Libreoffice &amp;mdash; useful if the data for the table is already stored in a spreadsheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting a LaTeX system set up</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 02:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex-setup/</guid>
      <description>Today I was teaching the honours students in econometrics and economics about LaTeX. Here are some brief instructions on how to set up a LaTeX system on different operating systems.MS-Windows  Download and run the setup program for MikTeX. Choose the “basic” system. Download and run the installer program for TeXstudio.  Then run TeXstudio and start typing.
Mac OS  Download and install MacTeX.  Then run TeXshop and start typing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online collaborative writing</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/online-collaborative-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 02:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/online-collaborative-writing/</guid>
      <description>Everyone who has written a paper with another author will know it can be tricky making sure you don&amp;rsquo;t end up with two versions that need to be merged. The good news is that the days of sending updated drafts by email backwards and forwards is finally over (having lasted all of 25 years &amp;ndash; I can barely imagine writing papers before email).LaTeX solutions There has been a lot of activity in the development of online LaTeX tools over the last few years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing white space around R figures</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/crop-r-figures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 00:22:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/crop-r-figures/</guid>
      <description>When I want to insert figures generated in R into a LaTeX document, it looks better if I first remove the white space around the figure. Unfortunately, R does not make this easy as the graphs are generated to look good on a screen, not in a document.
There are two things that can be done to fix this problem.First, you can reduce the white space generated by R. I use the following function when saving figures in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Makefiles for R/LaTeX projects</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/makefiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 02:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/makefiles/</guid>
      <description>Updated: 21 November 2012
Make is a marvellous tool used by programmers to build software, but it can be used for much more than that. I use make whenever I have a large project involving R files and LaTeX files, which means I use it for almost all of the papers I write, and almost of the consulting reports I produce.If you are using a Mac or Linux, you will already have make installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX loops</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex-loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2012 01:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex-loops/</guid>
      <description>Today I was writing a report which included 20 figures, with the names demandplot1.pdf, demandplot2.pdf, &amp;hellip;, demandplot20.pdf, and all with similar captions. Clearly a loop was required. After all, LaTeX is a programming language, so we should be able to take advantage of its capabilities.I found the forloop package which handled the problem perfectly. My first attempt looked like this:
\newcommand{\demandplot}[1]{\begin{figure}\centering \includegraphics[width=\textwidth]{./figs/demandplot#1.pdf} \caption{Hourly demand (GW) for zone #1.} \end{figure}} \newcounter{loop} \forloop{loop}{1}{\value{loop}&amp;lt;21}{\demandplot{\arabic{loop}}}  The magic happens in the last line providing a loop from 1 to 20, generating the commands \demandplot{1}, \demandplot{2}, &amp;hellip;, \demandplot{20}.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bare bones beamer</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/beamer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 06:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/beamer/</guid>
      <description>Beamer is far and away the most popular software for presentations amongst researchers in mathematics and statistics. Most conference and seminar talks I attend these days use beamer. Unfortunately, they all look much the same. I think people find beamer themes too hard to modify easily, so a small number of templates get shared around. Even the otherwise wonderful LaTeX Templates site has no beamer examples.
The beamer user guide explains how to make changes but it is not for the faint-hearted (although it is a fantastic resource once you have some expertise).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog aggregators</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/blog-aggregators/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 10:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/blog-aggregators/</guid>
      <description>A very useful way of keeping up with blogs in a particular area is to subscribe to a blog aggregator. These will syndicate posts from a large number of blogs and provide links back to the original sources. So you only need to subscribe once to get all the good stuff in that area.
There are now several blog aggregators available that might be of interest to readers here. And this blog is now syndicated on several other sites including those listed below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m switching to TeXstudio</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/texstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2011 11:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/texstudio/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve happily used WinEdt for all my LaTeX editing for about 15 years and I&amp;rsquo;ve encouraged my whole research team to use it. But I&amp;rsquo;m tired of problems with WinEdt that take up my time.I regularly have requests for help from one of my research team because something in WinEdt is not working properly &amp;mdash; such as pdf synchronization problems, or it is using an old version of MikTeX that no longer updates, or that it has switched to using another pdf viewer without warning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A LaTeX template for a CV</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2010 05:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/cv/</guid>
      <description>Every researcher needs a Curriculum Vitae (Latin for &amp;ldquo;course of life&amp;rdquo;) or CV. You will need it for job applications, for annual performance appraisal, and just for keeping track of your publications. A CV typically contains lists of achievements including qualifications, publications, presentations, awards, plus teaching experience.
I&amp;rsquo;ve created a LaTeX style for a CV to make it easy to produce something that looks good and is easy to maintain. You will need an up-to-date implementation of LaTeX because I&amp;rsquo;m using the wonderful biblatex package (more on that in another post) which has only just become available as part of MikTeX and TeXLive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with XeLaTeX</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/xelatex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2010 13:30:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/xelatex/</guid>
      <description>By now, most LaTeX users have probably heard of XeLaTeX, if only because it is an option in the latest versions of the standard LaTeX editors such as TeXnicCenter, WinEdt and TeXWorks. But most LaTeXers have probably not yet become XeLaTeXers. Why should you?
XeLaTeX is essentially a replacement for pdfLaTeX. It was primarily developed to enable better font handling, especially non-Roman scripts. If you want to write in Telugu, then XeLaTeX is going to make your life much easier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animated plots in R and LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 04:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/animations/</guid>
      <description>I like to use animated plots in my talks on functional time series, partly because it is the only way to really see what is going on with changes in the shapes of curves over time, and also because audiences love them! Here is how it is done.
For LaTeX, you need to create every frame as a separate graphics file. Here is an example. First the R code:
library(demography) nyears &amp;lt;- length(fr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More StackExchange sites</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/more-stackexchange-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2010 05:21:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/more-stackexchange-sites/</guid>
      <description>The StackExchange site on Statistical Analysis is about to go into private beta testing. This is your last chance to commit if you want to be part of the private beta testing. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry if you miss out &amp;mdash; it will only be a week before it is then open to the public.
There is also a StackExchange site proposal for TeX, LaTeX and friends. Presumably that means that most of the LaTeX questions on StackOverflow will then move to this new site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a poster in beamer</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/beamer-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2010 04:57:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/beamer-poster/</guid>
      <description>This week, I made my first poster. Although I&amp;rsquo;ve been an academic for more than 20 years, I&amp;rsquo;ve never had to make a poster before. Some of my coauthors have made posters about our joint research, and two of them have even won prizes (although I can&amp;rsquo;t take any credit for them). But this week, our department is displaying posters from all research staff about our recent work.
Here is my poster (click for pdf version):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My standard LaTeX preamble</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex-preamble/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2010 09:44:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex-preamble/</guid>
      <description>When I was a PhD student, I found I needed a lot of LaTeX functionality that did not then exist. So I wrote my own package which has served me well for about 20 years. It is called HyTeX.sty (the name being a shameless take-off of LaTeX from Leslie Lamport as well as a homonym of High-Tech). The advantage of having my own package is that almost every file starts with</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top four LaTeX mistakes</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/top-four-latex-mistakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2010 23:17:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/top-four-latex-mistakes/</guid>
      <description>There is a nice post today by John Cook on the top four LaTeX mistakes. I see these all the time in draft papers by my students and co-authors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Controlling figure and table placement in LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex-floats/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2009 00:01:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex-floats/</guid>
      <description>It can be frustrating trying to get your figures and tables to appear where you want them in a LaTeX document. Sometimes, they just seem to float off onto another page of their own accord. Here is a collection of tools and ideas that help you get control of those pesky floats.Use the placement options: h, t, b and p. For example
\begin{figure}[htb]  causes LaTeX to try to fit the float &amp;ldquo;here&amp;rdquo;, or at the &amp;ldquo;top&amp;rdquo; of the current page (or the next page), or at the &amp;ldquo;bottom&amp;rdquo; of the current page (or the next page).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Squeezing space with LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/squeezing-space-with-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 05:52:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/squeezing-space-with-latex/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing a grant application with a 10-page limit, and as usual it is difficult to squeeze everything in. No, I can&amp;rsquo;t just change the font as it has to be 12 point with at least 2 cm margins on an A4 page. Fortunately, LaTeX is packed full of powerful features that help in squeezing it all in. Here are some of the tips I&amp;rsquo;ve used over the years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting eps to pdf</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/converting-eps-to-pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 11:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/converting-eps-to-pdf/</guid>
      <description>Simply include the package epstopdf. Then when you use pdflatex, the eps files will be automatically converted to pdf at compile time. (The conversion only happens the first time you process the file, and is skipped if there is already a pdf file with the same name.)
For example:
\documentclass{article} \usepackage{graphicx,epstopdf} \begin{document} \includegraphics[width=\textwidth]{fig1} \end{document}  Then even though the only graphics file available is fig1.eps, this will still be processed ok using pdflatex or pdftexify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintaining local LaTeX files</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/localtexmf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2009 03:46:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/localtexmf/</guid>
      <description>If you use LaTeX, then you probably have a bib file — a data base of all the papers and books that you have cited. It is much more efficient to keep one database in one location, than have multiple copies of it floating around your hard drive. (Or even worse, have different bib files created for different papers.) You might also have a few of your own style files, and again it is best to keep these in a central location and not have duplicates all over the place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing a bibliographic database</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/managing-a-bibliographic-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2009 05:50:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/managing-a-bibliographic-database/</guid>
      <description>All researchers need to maintain a database of papers they have read, cited, or simply noted for later reference. For those of us using LaTeX, the database is in the BibTeX format and is stored as a simple text file (a bib file) that can be edited using a text editor such as WinEdt.
But it is often easier to edit the file using specialist software. My current favourite tool is JabRef.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding LaTeX symbols</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/finding-latex-symbols/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2009 05:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/finding-latex-symbols/</guid>
      <description>All LaTeX users will sometimes need a symbol for which they don&amp;rsquo;t know the command. If you use WinEdt, there is a neat drop-down menu of some common symbols that can be helpful, but it is necessarily limited. What do you do when you want the male and female symbols?
For several years I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the comprehensive symbol list whenever I need a symbol in LaTeX that I can&amp;rsquo;t recall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Word is a bad choice for academic writing</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/why-word-is-a-bad-choice-for-academic-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2009 05:20:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/why-word-is-a-bad-choice-for-academic-writing/</guid>
      <description>For years I&amp;rsquo;ve been telling everyone who would listen that MS-Word may sometimes be useful for short notes or for making a &amp;ldquo;Back in 5 minutes&amp;rdquo; sign to stick on your door, but if you want to write a serious document like an academic paper, a book or a thesis, then you should use a serious tool such as LaTeX. For those who are not yet convinced, Ben Klemens has a nice article entitled &amp;ldquo;Why Word is a terrible program&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX tips</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 08:18:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex-tips/</guid>
      <description>While reading students&amp;rsquo; theses and papers recently, I came across various examples of poor latex-ing that I thought would be useful to catalogue.
 Don&amp;rsquo;t set both width and height when using \includegraphics. It distorts the figure. Instead, I suggest using \includegraphics[width=\textwidth]{..}
 Be consistent in capitalizing section and subsection headings, and titles in the bibliography. My preferences is to use sentence case throughout.
 When using functions such as max, min, log, exp, sin, cos, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking changes in LaTeX files</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/tracking-changes-in-latex-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2008 08:13:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/tracking-changes-in-latex-files/</guid>
      <description>When I write a paper, it usually goes through many versions before being submitted to a journal. I keep track of the different versions by renaming the file when I&amp;rsquo;m about to make major changes, or when I receive a new version from a coauthor. The files are named file1.tex, file2.tex, etc. where &amp;ldquo;file&amp;rdquo; is replaced by something more meaningful.
It is often useful to be able to compare versions to see what changes have been made, especially when working with coauthors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX books</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2008 10:52:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex-books/</guid>
      <description>amzn_assoc_placement = &#34;adunit0&#34;; amzn_assoc_tracking_id = &#34;otexts-20&#34;; amzn_assoc_ad_mode = &#34;manual&#34;; amzn_assoc_ad_type = &#34;smart&#34;; amzn_assoc_marketplace = &#34;amazon&#34;; amzn_assoc_region = &#34;US&#34;; amzn_assoc_title = &#34;LaTeX books&#34;; amzn_assoc_rows = &#34;6&#34;; amzn_assoc_linkid = &#34;837c44f97120fac94a76c36f9781f970&#34;; amzn_assoc_asins = &#34;1847199860,3642238157,0321173856,0201362996,1784395145,0817641319,3319237950,0201529831&#34;;   If you cannot see any books above, please turn off your ad-blocker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX workshop</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex-workshop/</guid>
      <description>I gave a one-day LaTeX workshop today.
Here is the blurb:
 LaTeX is an extremely powerful markup language for creating structured documents. It is particularly well-suited for documents containing mathematics, but can be used for any document. Those whose publications involve a large number of mathematical equations often use LaTeX rather than MS-Word or some other word processing package. It is the standard writing tool for most research in the mathematical sciences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving a research seminar</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/giving-a-research-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 07:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/giving-a-research-seminar/</guid>
      <description>An expanded version of this post is available in my article on “Giving an academic talk”.
With conference season almost upon us, it is timely to discuss what makes a good conference presentation. Here is a suggested structure.
 A motivating example demonstrating the problem you are trying to solve. Explain existing approaches to the problem and their weaknesses. Describe your main contributions. Show how your ideas solve the problem/example you started with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Indexing in LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/indexing-in-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2007 04:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/indexing-in-latex/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m in the final stages of preparing my new exponential smoothing book for publication and have been learning about some LaTeX indexing tools.
The standard subject index is created using the following procedure:
 Include \index{entry} commands wherever you want an index entry.
 Include \usepackage{makeidx} and \makeindex in the preamble.
 Put a \printindex command where the index is to appear, normally before the \end{document} command.
  The details are well-documented in this tutorial (starting on p9).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tables in LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/tables-in-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 04:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/tables-in-latex/</guid>
      <description>(Updated May 2017)
Making tables in LaTeX is one of the few areas where LaTeX can be more difficult than a WYSIWYG editor.
Here are some pointers to tools and packages that I have found useful.
 tablesgenerator.com: a web-based tool for generating LaTeX tables.
 Excel2LaTeX: this excel add-in makes it easy to copy a rectangular array of cells in a spreadsheet into a LaTeX document.
 Calc2LaTeX: a similar extension for LibreOffice and OpenOffice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful LaTeX links</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/useful-latex-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2006 10:07:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/useful-latex-links/</guid>
      <description>Learning LaTeX  Introduction to LaTeX: notes and other materials from a one-day workshop.
 Getting started with LaTeX: an excellent online introduction from David Wilkins.
 Great reference book from the Indian TeX Users Group.
 Excellent on-line tutorials from Andy Roberts.
 More tutorials from the Indian TeX Users Group.
 The TeX Catalogue for finding packages.
  Getting help The first and best place to go is TeX.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>