<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prizes on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/categories/prizes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Prizes on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/categories/prizes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IJF Tao Hong Award 2018</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-hong-nominations-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-hong-nominations-2018/</guid>
      <description>Every two years, the International Journal of Forecasting awards a prize to the best paper on energy forecasting. The prize is generously funded by Professor Tao Hong. This year, we will award the prize to a paper published in the IJF during the period 2015-2016. The prize will be US$1000 plus an engraved plaque. The award committee is Rob J Hyndman, Pierre Pinson and James Mitchell.
Nominations are invited from any reader of the IJF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IJF Best Paper Award 2017</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-best-paper-award-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-best-paper-award-2017/</guid>
      <description>At the recent International Symposium on Forecasting, I announced the awards for the best paper published in the International Journal of Forecasting in the period 2014&amp;ndash;2015.
We make an award every two years to the best paper(s) published in the journal. There is always about 18 months delay after the publication period to allow time for reflection, citations, etc. The selected papers are selected by vote of the editorial board. The best paper wins an engraved bronze plaque and US$1000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IIF Tao Hong Award 2016</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/iif-hong-award-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/iif-hong-award-2016/</guid>
      <description>A generous donation from Professor Tao Hong has funded this new award for papers on energy forecasting published in the International Journal of Forecasting. The award for 2016 is for papers published within 2013&amp;ndash;2014. Next year we will award a paper published in 2015&amp;ndash;2016, and we will make the award every two years after that.
The award decision was made by a committee consisting of Professors Pierre Pinson, James Mitchell and Rob J Hyndman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IIF Fellow Ralph Snyder</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ralph-snyder/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ralph-snyder/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://robjhyndman.com/img/Ralph.jpg&#34; width=200&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the &lt;em&gt;International Symposium on Forecasting&lt;/em&gt; last week, my friend and colleague &lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=mlwKz6cAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&#34;&gt;Ralph Snyder&lt;/a&gt; was made a Fellow of the International Institute of Forecasters.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISI Karl Pearson Prize for 2017</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/kpprize2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/kpprize2017/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was privileged to sit on the committee that selects the winner of the Karl Pearson Prize. KP was, of course, an early mathematical statistician, famous for many commonly-used statistical methods and tools including histograms, the correlation coefficient, the method of moments, p-values, the chi-squared test and principal components analysis. He is also infamous for his highly racist views, support for eugenics, anti-semitism and for refusing a knighthood.
All that aside, the job of the committee was to select an English-language article or book published in the last 30 years that has made a stand-alone research contribution, and which has had major influence on one or more of statistical theory, statistical methodology, statistical practice and application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IJF Best Paper Award 2014-2015</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-nominations1415/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 03:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-nominations1415/</guid>
      <description>Every two years we award a prize for the best paper published in the International Journal of Forecasting. It is now time to identify the best paper published in the IJF during 2014 and 2015. There is always about 18 months delay after the publication period to allow time for reflection, citations, etc. The prize is US$1000 plus an engraved plaque. I will present the prize at the ISF in Cairns in late June.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IJF Tao Hong Award for the best paper in energy forecasting 2013-2014</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-hong-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 04:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-hong-award/</guid>
      <description>Professor Tao Hong has generously funded a new prize for the best IJF paper on energy forecasting, to be awarded every two years. The first award will be for papers published in the International Journal of Forecasting during the period 2013-2014. The prize will be US$1000 plus an engraved plaque. The award committee is Rob J Hyndman, Pierre Pinson and James Mitchell.
Nominations are invited from any reader of the IJF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACEMS Business Analytics Prize 2016</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/acems-prize-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 05:03:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/acems-prize-2016/</guid>
      <description>We have established a new annual prize for research students at Monash University in the general area of business analytics, funded by the Australian Centre of Excellence in Mathematical and Statistical Frontiers (ACEMS). The rules of the award are listed below.
 The student must have submitted a paper to a high quality journal or refereed conference on some topic in the general area of business analytics, computational statistics or data visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IJF best paper awards</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-best-paper-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 21:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-best-paper-awards/</guid>
      <description>Today at the International Symposium on Forecasting, I announced the awards for the best paper published in the International Journal of Forecasting in the period 2012-2013.
We make an award every two years to the best paper(s) published in the journal. There is always about 18 months delay after the publication period to allow time for reflection, citations, etc. The selected papers are selected by vote of the editorial board. The best paper wins an engraved bronze plaque and US$1000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student forecasting awards from the IIF</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/iif-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 03:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/iif-awards/</guid>
      <description>At the IIF annual board meeting last month in Rotterdam, I suggested that we provide awards to the top students studying forecasting at university level around the world, to the tune of $100 plus IIF membership for a year. I&amp;rsquo;m delighted that the idea met with enthusiasm, and that the awards are now available. Even better, my second year forecasting subject has been approved for an award.
The IIF have agreed to fund awards for 20 forecasting courses to start with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supervision award</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/supervision-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 09:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/supervision-award/</guid>
      <description>Last night I received the Vice-Chancellor&amp;rsquo;s postgraduate supervision award at a function at Government House. I am deeply honoured that my students thought to nominate me for the award. I think I was as surprised as anyone to win, and some people have asked me what I did to deserve it. Actually, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that I did deserve it, but I can tell you what I told the award committee who chose me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>