<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Graphics on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/tags/graphics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Graphics on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/tags/graphics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing big energy data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/visualizing-big-energy-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/visualizing-big-energy-data/</guid>
      <description>Visualization is a crucial component of data analysis. It is always a good idea to plot the data before fitting any models, making any predictions, or drawing any conclusions. As sensors of the electric grid are collecting large volumes of data from various sources, power industry professionals are facing the challenge of visualizing such data in a timely fashion. In this article, we demonstrate several data visualization solutions for big energy data through three case studies involving smart meter data, phasor measurement unit (PMU) data, and probabilistic forecasts, respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calendar-based graphics for visualizing people&#39;s daily schedules</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/calendar-vis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/calendar-vis/</guid>
      <description>This paper describes a frame_calendar function that organizes and displays temporal data, collected on sub-daily resolution, into a calendar layout. Calendars are broadly used in society to display temporal information, and events. The frame_calendar uses linear algebra on the date variable to create the layout. It utilizes the grammar of graphics to create the plots inside each cell, and thus synchronizes neatly with ggplot2 graphics. The motivating application is studying pedestrian behavior in Melbourne, Australia, based on counts which are captured at hourly intervals by sensors scattered around the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualising forecasting algorithm performance using time series instance spaces</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/ts-feature-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 21:16:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/ts-feature-space/</guid>
      <description>It is common practice to evaluate the strength of forecasting methods using collections of well-studied time series datasets, such as the M3 data. But how diverse are these time series, how challenging, and do they enable us to study the unique strengths and weaknesses of different forecasting methods? In this paper we propose a visualisation method for a collection of time series that enables a time series to be represented as a point in a 2-dimensional instance space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization of big time series data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/big-time-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 03:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/big-time-series/</guid>
      <description>Talk given to a joint meeting of the Statistical Society of Australia (Victorian branch) and the Melbourne Data Science Meetup Group.It is becoming increasingly common for organizations to collect very large amounts of data over time. Data visualization is essential for exploring and understanding structures and patterns, and to identify unusual observations. However, the sheer quantity of data available challenges current time series visualisation methods.
For example, Yahoo has banks of mail servers that are monitored over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discussion of “High-dimensional autocovariance matrices and optimal linear prediction”</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/mpcomments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2015 16:43:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/mpcomments/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization and forecasting of big time series data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/big-time-series-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 01:11:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/big-time-series-data/</guid>
      <description>Talk given at the ACEMS Big data workshop, QUT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing and forecasting big time series data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/visualizing-and-forecasting-big-time-series-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 15:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/visualizing-and-forecasting-big-time-series-data/</guid>
      <description>Institute of Statistical Science, Academia Sinica 時　間 2015/01/12 11:00 星期一 地　點 中研院-統計所 2F 交誼廳 備　註 茶 會：上午10：40統計所二樓交誼廳
Time series can often be naturally disaggregated in a hierarchical or grouped structure. For example, a manufacturing company can disaggregate total demand for their products by country of sale, retail outlet, product type, package size, and so on. As a result, there can be millions of individual time series to forecast at the most disaggregated level, plus additional series to forecast at higher levels of aggregation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting: principles and practice (UWA course)</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/uwa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 03:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/uwa/</guid>
      <description> Workshop to be held on 23-25 September 2014.
Venue: The University Club, University of Western Australia, Nedlands WA.
Requirements: a laptop with R installed, along with the fpp package and its dependencies. We will also use the hts and vars package on the third day.
Textbook [Hyndman and Athanasopoulos (2014)
Forecasting: principles and practice, OTexts: Melbourne, Australia](http://www.otexts.org/fpp).
Program  Introduction to forecasting [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Forecasting tools [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Exponential smoothing I [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Exponential smoothing II [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Time series decomposition and cross-validation [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Transformations, stationarity and differencing [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Non-seasonal ARIMA models [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Seasonal ARIMA models [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] State space models [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Dynamic regression [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Hierarchical forecasting [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Advanced methods [Slides, R code, Lab solutions]  Course Notes </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory graphics for functional data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/interface2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 08:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/interface2010/</guid>
      <description>We survey some graphical tools for visualizing large sets of functional data represented by smooth curves. These graphical tools include the phase-plane plot, singular value decomposition plot, rainbow plot, functional variants of the bagplot and the highest density region boxplot. The latter two techniques utilize the first two robust principal component scores, Tukey&amp;rsquo;s halfspace location depth and highest density regions.
The computer code and datasets are collected in the rainbow package for R, which is available at the Comprehensive R Archive Network (CRAN).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rainbow plots, bagplots and boxplots for functional data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/rainbow-fda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 23:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/rainbow-fda/</guid>
      <description>We propose new tools for visualizing large numbers of functional data in the form of smooth curves or surfaces. The proposed tools include functional versions of the bagplot and boxplot, and make use of the first two robust principal component scores, Tukey&amp;rsquo;s data depth and highest density regions.
By-products of our graphical displays are outlier detection methods for functional data. We compare these new outlier detection methods with existing methods for detecting outliers in functional data and show that our methods are better able to identify the outliers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bagplots, boxplots and outlier detection for functional data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/fboxplot-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2008 03:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/fboxplot-talk/</guid>
      <description>Australian Statistics Conference. Melbourne, July 2008.  Where: First International Workshop on Functional and Operatorial Statistics, Toulouse Where : Australian Statistical Conference Melbourne, Australia Speakers: Professor Rob&amp;nbsp;J&amp;nbsp;Hyndman, Monash University &amp;amp; Han Lin Shang, Monash University  Abstract: We propose some new tools for visualizing functional data and for identifying functional outliers. The proposed tools make use of robust principal component analysis, data depth and highest density regions. We compare the proposed outlier detection methods with the existing “functional depth” method, and show that our methods have better performance on identifying outliers in French male age-specific mortality data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bagplots, boxplots and outlier detection for functional data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/bagplots-boxplots-and-outlier-detection-for-functional-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2008 03:10:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/bagplots-boxplots-and-outlier-detection-for-functional-data/</guid>
      <description>We propose some new tools for visualizing functional data and for identifying functional outliers. The proposed tools make use of robust principal component analysis, data depth and highest density regions. We compare the proposed outlier detection methods with the existing &amp;ldquo;functional depth&amp;rdquo; method, and show that our methods have better performance on identifying outliers in French male age-specific mortality data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review of &#34;Data Analysis and Graphics Using R: An Example-based Approach&#34; (Maindonald and Braun, 2003)</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/maindonald-and-braun-data-analysis-and-graphics-using-r-an-example-based-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2005 00:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/maindonald-and-braun-data-analysis-and-graphics-using-r-an-example-based-approach/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Residual diagnostic plots for model mis-specification in time series regression</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/residual-diagnostic-plots-for-model-mis-specification-in-time-series-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2000 03:01:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/residual-diagnostic-plots-for-model-mis-specification-in-time-series-regression/</guid>
      <description>This paper considers residuals for time series regression. Despite much literature on visual diagnostics for uncorrelated data, there is little on the autocorrelated case. In order to examine various aspects of the fitted time series regression model, three residuals are considered. The fitted regression model can be checked using orthogonal residuals; the time series error model can be analysed using marginal residuals; and the white noise error component can be tested using conditional residuals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>