<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unbelievable on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unbelievable on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 06:50:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Buy book</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/buy-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 06:50:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/buy-book/</guid>
      <description>If you prefer a print or offline version, you can buy a copy via one of the links below.
Buy a print copy via CreateSpace
Buy a print copy via Amazon
Buy an e-copy via Google Books</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bibliography</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/bibliography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 01:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/bibliography/</guid>
      <description>Books and articles cited Angelakis, A. N. and S. V. Spyridakis (1996). ‘The status of water resources in Minoan times: A preliminary study’. In: Diachronic Climatic Impacts on Water Resources: with emphasis on the Mediterranean region. Edited by A. N. Angelakis and A. S. Issar. Volume 36. NATO ASI Series. Berlin: Springer, pp.161–191.
Archer, G. L. (1982). Encyclopedia of Bible difficulties. Grand Rapids, MI, USA: Zondervan.
Bartholomew, D. J. (2008).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>23. Welcome to the dark side</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 00:33:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch23/</guid>
      <description>This final collection of messages were from people who had already left the Christadelphian community, in some cases many years before me. I know very few of these people, but I appreciated their thoughtfulness in writing to me.
Message 31  I bet you have been getting the emails lately, huh? Some pulling this way, some pulling that way?
I can tell from the comments on the blog that there is a contest going on for the control of your thoughts and mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>22. Me too</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 09:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch22/</guid>
      <description>Several people contacted me to say they were going through a similar process of deconversion. I think it was comforting for them (and for me) to know that the journey need not be a lonely one.
Message 26  I have similar questions, but it is hard for me to break away. I think it would be liberating but not sure I can bear the abject grief of my parents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>21. What now?</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 09:25:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch21/</guid>
      <description>A few of my correspondents wondered about my future. What would I do now I was no longer writing books and giving talks about the Bible? Would I start an atheist crusade with the same energy and enthusiasm I once gave to my preaching? Others wrote to me a few months after I had resigned, asking how I was getting on.
Message 23  I know that you feel as though you have had an epiphany and that you can finally see the ‘truth’ clearly, but from my very simple perspective, it looks more like you have been blinded as a result of your intelligence … that you have had your nose in the books so long that you have forgotten to look up and see the evidence of God all around you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20. You must be ignorant</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 08:33:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch20/</guid>
      <description>A few parcels sent to me contained books and DVDs that were presumably supposed to convince me of my errors. I appreciate the care demonstrated by these gifts, but they do assume that I am misinformed and ignorant about what I believe.
I find it rather insulting to be told that I gave up on a lifetime of faith and religious activity without really thinking through the issues, and without reading widely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>19. Was the pressure too much?</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 08:29:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch19/</guid>
      <description>A lot of people have assumed that something awful must have happened to me, or that all the criticism directed at me has had some cumulative effect that has hurt my faith. It is not like that. I just don’t believe it, and I did not want to spend the rest of my life pretending otherwise.
Message 17 I know you have taken a hammering for having opinions different to some of the more traditional ones and I have to say some of them I share … but having them shouldn’t have made you a target for people’s fear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>18. I&#39;m praying for you</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 08:27:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch18/</guid>
      <description>Understandably, a lot of my religious friends have said they are praying for me. I would have done the same when I was a believer. It was my instinctive response to any problem, and even after I came to the view that God was probably imaginary, I would still find myself occasionally wanting to pray when faced with difficulties. It is comforting to think that someone else might deal with the problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>17. You made me cry</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 08:20:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch17/</guid>
      <description>In contrast to the letters in the previous chapter, most of the messages I received expressed sadness, love and friendship, for which I am deeply grateful.
I have very few comments on these. What can I say? I feel sad too. I have stayed in touch with most of these writers, and they remain dear friends even though we no longer have a shared faith.
Message 4 Just read your latest blog post … firstly wanted to say that I love and respect you and always will regardless of what you call yourself now But secondly you made me cry today … and for that you need a clip over the ears!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>16. Repent or die</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 08:18:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch16/</guid>
      <description>I have received several hundred emails, letters and other messages as a result of my deconversion and resignation. Many of them were from friends, some from people who had read my books or heard me speak, and some were from people who only knew me as a professor of statistics but who were moved to send me their thoughts.
In this last section, I have included a selection of these messages along with some retrospective reflections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>15. I am not an axe-murderer</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch15/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 08:09:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch15/</guid>
      <description>Christians often claim that their beliefs underpin their morality, and those who do not believe in God or the Bible must therefore lack a moral compass. They assume that values and morals are a consequence of holding the true doctrines. Well I have not become an axe-murderer since becoming an unbeliever, I have not suddenly become unfaithful to my wife, nor have I begun torturing kittens, I have not even started swearing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>14. Did you hear about the guy...?</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 07:59:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch14/</guid>
      <description>If the miracles of Jesus happened as reported, then they would provide evidence for him having supernatural power. If he really walked across the Sea of Galilee, provided food for thousands of people from five loaves and two fish, and raised Lazarus from the dead, then of course he is supernatural. If all those things are true, then his claims to be the Son of God would need to be taken seriously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13. Drink the magic potion</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 07:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch13/</guid>
      <description>The Way of Life book (pp.9–10) gives two examples of laws from Leviticus and Deuteronomy that supposedly demonstrate an understanding of science that was not possible for the Israelites to have developed.
Food prohibitions The first example is that the Law of Moses prohibited eating seafood (Leviticus 11:4–8,10–12) which we now know can cause intestinal problems and food poisoning without careful preparation and refrigeration.
However, it was not necessary to understand the science for the Israelites to have noticed that people who ate seafood often became ill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12. Does God make mistakes?</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 07:30:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch12/</guid>
      <description>The contradictions game Three times I have debated skeptics of the Bible, and each time they raised Bible contradictions. I knew they would and I was prepared. I am rather good at reconciling contradictions. Give me a long list of apparent contradictions, and I can usually think of explanations. The difficulty is that the explanations are often contrived, and can seem like a desperate attempt to explain away the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11. Artefacts and anachronisms</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 07:26:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch11/</guid>
      <description>I have given nearly 50 talks on biblical archaeology. One was entitled “Bible skeletons and fingerprints” in which I described some recent archaeological finds that supported and illuminated the biblical record. I showed photographs of the ossuary of Caiaphas from the first century AD, containing a skeleton of a 60 year old man — probably Caiaphas the high priest mentioned in the gospels. I covered the tiny clay seals that were found in Jerusalem from around 586BC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10. Evolving views on creation</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 01:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch10/</guid>
      <description>Sunday School nonsense In my early teens, I was taught in Sunday School that scientists had got it wrong — that the universe was actually a few thousand years old, not the billions of years claimed by the “evolutionists”. I found that confusing. I was aware that the light from the nearest galaxy to our own took at least a few tens of thousands of years to get here, and the light from many other galaxies took millions of years to arrive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9. Legend of the empty tomb</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 01:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch9/</guid>
      <description>The resurrection of Jesus is often cited as evidence of the Bible’s inspiration, or at least of God’s existence. There is an obvious problem here — all we know about the resurrection of Jesus comes from the Bible, so it cannot be used as evidence in support of itself. But leaving that difficulty aside, let’s review what the Bible actually says about it.
Harmonizing the accounts The resurrection accounts are notoriously difficult to harmonize.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>8. The biblical crystal ball</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 01:15:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch8/</guid>
      <description>Forecasting is my area of expertise. I am Editor-in-Chief of the International Journal of Forecasting and I have written several textbooks on statistical forecasting. I spend many hours every week thinking about the probabilities associated with future events. So prophecy, which is closely related to forecasting, has always been of particular interest to me.
When I was a believer, my favourite fulfilled prophecies were
 the return of Israel to their land; Daniel’s prophecies of four empires; the destruction of Tyre; and the crucifixion of Jesus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7. Thank God</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 00:51:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch7/</guid>
      <description>It is natural for believers to thank God when they survive a natural disaster, or even when they avoid the effects of man-made tragedies. When the great tsunami of Boxing Day 2004 wiped out huge areas of Thailand, Indonesia, India and Sri Lanka, many survivors thanked God for protecting them. Others wondered what God was doing while 230,000 people died.
When the Australian Black Saturday bushfires in February 2009 killed 173 people, many survivors thanked God for protecting them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6. What are the chances?</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 00:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch6/</guid>
      <description>One of the first things I have been asked by people who find out that I no longer believe is “What about answered prayers?”.
Prayer is not falsifiable when you already believe Prayer is not falsifiable if you begin by assuming that God exists and is listening. If someone prays that X occurs and it does, then they say that the prayer has been answered. If X does not occur, then they say the answer was no, it wasn’t God’s will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5. Talking to myself</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 00:37:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch5/</guid>
      <description>I tried hard to have an active and regular prayer time every morning for many, many years. I would rise early and spend time jotting some thoughts in my prayer journal. Then I would offer a prayer based on what I had written. For a few months in 2002, when we lived in Canberra, I would walk to the top of a nearby mountain each morning, and surrounded by grazing kangaroos I would say my prayers as the sun rose over Black Mountain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. What would convince you?</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 12:14:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch4/</guid>
      <description>There is an old joke about a psychiatrist working with a patient who was convinced that he was dead. The psychiatrist says “So you think you’re dead. Do dead people bleed?”, to which the patient replies “No, of course not.” Then the psychiatrist takes a sharp needle and pricks the patient’s finger drawing a drop of blood. The shocked patient says “Well, what do you know. Dead people do bleed!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Which is the better story?</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 12:04:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch3/</guid>
      <description>The beautiful movie Life of Pi is a story about a boy (Pi) raised in India where his father owns a small zoo. He is deeply religious and simultaneously embraces Hinduism, Christianity and Islam. At one level, the book is about Pi’s deep faith in the face of his father’s atheist disapproval. When the family and zoo emigrate for Canada, the ship founders in a storm, and Pi finds himself on a lifeboat with a hyena, a chimpanzee, a zebra and a Bengal tiger for company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. An end of faith</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 11:49:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch2/</guid>
      <description>This is the blog post in which I announced my loss of faith and my resignation from the Christadelphian community — 29 July 2013
This week I resigned from the Christadelphian faith after nearly 30 years as a member, and having attended Christadelphian activities almost every week of my life.
I resigned because I no longer believe. I don’t believe the Bible is inspired by God. I am not even sure there is a God.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1. No reason to believe</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 04:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/ch1/</guid>
      <description>Two years after I started my blog, I bumped into an old friend at church one Sunday. I hadn’t seen her for a couple of years and I asked after her family. She told me that Josh, her oldest son, had left the Christadelphian community and that he no longer believed in God. I decided to write to him to ask what had happened. After some correspondence, Josh read my blog, and responded with the following email (slightly edited):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preface</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/preface/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Mar 2016 02:40:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/unbelievable/preface/</guid>
      <description>I was a Christadelphian1 for nearly 30 years, from age 16 until I resigned in July 2013 when I no longer thought that there was sufficient evidence to warrant belief in the Bible or Christianity. This book explains why I changed.
Many of my Christadelphian friends have asked why I no longer believe, and I want to give them the answer they deserve. After many years of speaking at Christadelphian meetings in Australia and in several other countries, there are a lot of people who have heard me talk about my faith, and will have wondered what has happened.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>