<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Supervision on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/categories/supervision/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Supervision on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 11:48:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/categories/supervision/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What not to say in a job interview</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/what-not-to-say-in-a-job-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 11:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/what-not-to-say-in-a-job-interview/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve interviewed a few people for jobs at Monash University, and there&amp;rsquo;s always someone who comes out with something surprising. Here are some real examples.For a post-doctoral research position:
 Q: What would you say were your major weaknesses?
 A: I don&amp;rsquo;t have any.
 Q: Really? You can&amp;rsquo;t think of anything that you could work on, new skills you could develop, anything at all that you might be able to improve?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Establishing priority</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/establishing-priority/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 03:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/establishing-priority/</guid>
      <description>The nature of research is that other people are probably working on similar ideas to you, and it is possible that someone will beat you to publishing them.When I was working on my PhD, I discovered another PhD thesis by Iris Yeung at UKC with almost exactly the same title as mine, and published a year earlier. In those days, a copy of a thesis had to be printed from microfiche, and then posted by snail mail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogs about research</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/blogs-about-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 02:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/blogs-about-research/</guid>
      <description>If you find this blog helpful (or even if you don&amp;rsquo;t but you&amp;rsquo;re interested in blogs on research issues and tools), there are a few other blogs about doing research that you might find useful. Here are a few that I read.
 Patter &amp;ndash; Pat Thomson.
 The Thesis Whisperer &amp;ndash; Inger Mewburn.
 The Research Whisperer &amp;ndash; several RMIT researchers.
 the (research) supervisor&amp;rsquo;s friend &amp;ndash; Geof Hill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking after your supervisor</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/looking-after-your-supervisor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 11:17:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/looking-after-your-supervisor/</guid>
      <description>Some good advice here: The care and maintenance of your adviser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice to PhD applicants</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/phdapplicants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 04:42:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/phdapplicants/</guid>
      <description>For students who are interested in doing a PhD at Monash under my supervision.
First, read the instructions on how to apply.
Second, poke around my website to see the sorts of topics I work on. There&amp;rsquo;s no point asking to do a PhD with me if you want to do research on something I don&amp;rsquo;t know much about. In particular, please note that I&amp;rsquo;m not really interested in finance or economics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fail a PhD</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/phdfail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 13:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/phdfail/</guid>
      <description>I read an interesting post today by Matt Might on &amp;ldquo;10 reasons PhD students fail&amp;rdquo;, and I thought it might be helpful to reflect on some of the barriers to PhD completion that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen. Matt&amp;rsquo;s ideas are not all relevant to Australian PhDs, so I have come up with my own list below. Here are the seven steps to failure.
1. Wait for your supervisor to tell you what to do A good supervisor will not tell you what to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research supervision workshop</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/supervision-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2009 06:00:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/supervision-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Today I gave a workshop for supervisors of postgraduate students. Mostly I talked about creating a team environment for postgraduate students rather than the traditional model (at least in statistics and econometrics) of each student working in isolation.
The slides are available here in presentation form or in handout form. Actually, these are an edited version of the slides as I accidentally left out a couple of the photographs in the workshop, and I&amp;rsquo;ve omitted slides that I didn&amp;rsquo;t end up covering in the workshop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supervision award</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/supervision-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 09:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/supervision-award/</guid>
      <description>Last night I received the Vice-Chancellor&amp;rsquo;s postgraduate supervision award at a function at Government House. I am deeply honoured that my students thought to nominate me for the award. I think I was as surprised as anyone to win, and some people have asked me what I did to deserve it. Actually, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure that I did deserve it, but I can tell you what I told the award committee who chose me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>