<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journals on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/categories/journals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journals on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/categories/journals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IJF Best Paper Award 2017</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-best-paper-award-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-best-paper-award-2017/</guid>
      <description>At the recent International Symposium on Forecasting, I announced the awards for the best paper published in the International Journal of Forecasting in the period 2014&amp;ndash;2015.
We make an award every two years to the best paper(s) published in the journal. There is always about 18 months delay after the publication period to allow time for reflection, citations, etc. The selected papers are selected by vote of the editorial board. The best paper wins an engraved bronze plaque and US$1000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I&#39;m not celebrating the 2016 impact factors</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/2016-impact-factors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/2016-impact-factors/</guid>
      <description>Once every year, the journal citation reports are released including journal impact factors. This year, the International Journal of Forecasting 2-year impact factor has increased to 2.642 which is the highest it has been in the journal’s history, and puts the journal higher than such notable titles as Journal of the American Statistical Association and just below Management Science.
The 2-year impact factor is the average number of citations for articles published in the previous 2 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic phishing</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/academic-phishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 02:25:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/academic-phishing/</guid>
      <description>Invitations to write for bogus journals and speak at bogus conferences keep rolling in. Here is one I received today.
 Dear Dr. Rob J. Hyndman, It is our great pleasure to welcome you to join in Part 2: Knowledge Economy Symposium of GCKE-2017, which will be held in Qingdao, China during September 19-21, 2017. And we cordially invite you to propose a Speech on your recent research of Corrigendum to: “Hierarchical forecasts for Australian domestic tourism” [International Journal of Forecasting 25 (2009) 146–166]&amp;hellip; .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IJF Best Paper Award 2014-2015</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-nominations1415/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 03:54:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-nominations1415/</guid>
      <description>Every two years we award a prize for the best paper published in the International Journal of Forecasting. It is now time to identify the best paper published in the IJF during 2014 and 2015. There is always about 18 months delay after the publication period to allow time for reflection, citations, etc. The prize is US$1000 plus an engraved plaque. I will present the prize at the ISF in Cairns in late June.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is going on?</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-reject/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 02:15:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-reject/</guid>
      <description>I seem to be getting an increasing number of submissions where the author has clearly not bothered to actually check that the paper was submitted correctly. Here is a rejection letter I wrote today.
 Dear xxxxx
I am writing concerning manuscript #INTFOR_16xxxxx entitled &amp;ldquo;xxxxxxxxxxxxxxxx&amp;rdquo; which you submitted to the International Journal of Forecasting.
Thank you for this submission, but as it consists entirely of the IJF author guidelines, it is not suitable for publication in the IJF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The latest IJF issue with GEFCom2014 results</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-gefcom2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 01:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-gefcom2014/</guid>
      <description>The latest issue of the IJF is a bumper issue with over 500 pages of forecasting insights.
The GEFCom2014 papers are included in a special section on probabilistic energy forecasting, guest edited by Tao Hong and Pierre Pinson. This is a major milestone in energy forecasting research with the focus on probabilistic forecasting and forecast evaluation done using a quantile scoring method. Only a few years ago I was having to explain to energy professionals why you couldn&amp;rsquo;t use a MAPE to evaluate a percentile forecast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IJF vol 31(4): Forecasting in telecommunications and ICT</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-vol-314/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 09:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-vol-314/</guid>
      <description>The last issue of the International Journal of Forecasting for 2015 has been released. This one contains the usual mix of topics, plus a special section on Forecasting in telecommunications and ICT including a nice review article by Nigel Meade and Towhidul Islam. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advice to other journal editors</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/finding-reviewers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 10:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/finding-reviewers/</guid>
      <description>I get asked to review journal papers almost every day, and I have to say no to almost all of them. I know it is hard to find reviewers, but many of these requests indicate very lazy editors. So to all the editors out there looking for reviewers, here is some advice.
 Never ask someone who is an editor for another journal. I am handling about 500 submissions per year for the International Journal of Forecasting, and about 10 per year for the Journal of Statistical Software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IJF best paper awards</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-best-paper-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 21:32:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-best-paper-awards/</guid>
      <description>Today at the International Symposium on Forecasting, I announced the awards for the best paper published in the International Journal of Forecasting in the period 2012-2013.
We make an award every two years to the best paper(s) published in the journal. There is always about 18 months delay after the publication period to allow time for reflection, citations, etc. The selected papers are selected by vote of the editorial board. The best paper wins an engraved bronze plaque and US$1000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More changes to the IJF editorial board</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 03:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-board/</guid>
      <description>The editorial board of the International Journal of Forecasting is going through a renewal process with several changes to the team of editors and the team of associate editors in the last few weeks.New Editors Graham Elliott has decided to step down from the IJF editorial board after many years of service. Graham is best known for his research on optimal forecast combination, and forecasting under asymmetric and flexible loss functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nominations for IJF Best Paper 2012-2013</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-nominations2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 07:46:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-nominations2/</guid>
      <description>The following papers have been nominated for the best paper published in the International Journal of Forecasting in 2012-2013. I have included an excerpt from the nomination in each case. The papers in bold have been short-listed for the award, and the editorial board are currently voting on them. Bellotti, T., &amp;amp; Crook, J. (2012). Loss given default models incorporating macroeconomic variables for credit cards. IJF, 28(1), 171-182.
 The first rule for the award of best paper should be that the paper clearly reflects the value of the new method/approach when compared to established alternatives in the particular problem context chosen by the researchers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to cite?</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/what-to-cite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 03:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/what-to-cite/</guid>
      <description>This question comes from a comment on another post:
 I&amp;rsquo;ve seen authors citing as many references as possible to try to please potential referees. Many of those references are low quality papers though. Any general guidance about a typical length for the reference section?
 It depends on the subject and style of the paper. I&amp;rsquo;ve written a paper with over 900 citations, but that was a review of time series forecasting over a 25 year period, and so it had to include a lot of references.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common reasons for rejection</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-rejections/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 04:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-rejections/</guid>
      <description>Every week I reject some papers submitted to the International Journal of Forecasting, without sending the papers off to associate editors or reviewers. Here are five of the most common reasons for rejection.1. Wrong Journal Submissions to the IJF should be about forecasting, obviously. But we often get papers on econometrics, or time series analysis, or something else that is not forecasting. Even if a paper has some implications for forecasting, if these are not discussed at all, the paper is not within scope for the journal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks Paul and welcome Dilek</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-change-of-editors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2015 22:45:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-change-of-editors/</guid>
      <description>Today, there is a change in editors at the International Journal of Forecasting. Paul Goodwin is retiring from the editorial board, and Dilek Önkal is taking his place.Paul Goodwin was appointed as an associate editor in 1999 and as an editor in 2010. Paul is retiring from his position as Professor of Management Science at the University of Bath, UK, and has decided to also retire from the IJF editorial board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSS feeds for statistics and related journals</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/rss-feeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 23:48:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/rss-feeds/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve now resurrected the collection of research journals that I follow, and set it up as a shared collection in feedly. So anyone can easily subscribe to all of the same journals, or select a subset of them, to follow on feedly.There are about 90 journals on the list, mostly in statistics, but some from machine learning, operations research and econometrics. I excluded probability journals, and areas of application that are well outside my research interests (such as bioinformatics, psychology and pharmacology).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honoring Herman Stekler</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/honoring-herman-stekler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 00:11:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/honoring-herman-stekler/</guid>
      <description>The first issue of the IJF for 2015 has just been published, and I&amp;rsquo;m delighted that it includes a special section honoring Herman Stekler. It includes articles covering a range of his forecasting interests, although not all of them (sports forecasting is missing). Herman himself wrote a paper for it looking at &amp;ldquo;Forecasting—Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow&amp;rdquo;.
He is in a unique position to write such a paper as he has been doing forecasting research longer than anyone else on the planet &amp;mdash; his first published paper on forecasting appeared in 1959.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IJF review papers</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-review-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2014 23:50:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-review-papers/</guid>
      <description>Review papers are extremely useful for new researchers such as PhD students, or when you want to learn about a new research field. The International Journal of Forecasting produced a whole review issue in 2006, and it contains some of the most highly cited papers we have ever published. Now, beginning with the latest issue of the journal, we have started publishing occasional review articles on selected areas of forecasting. The first two articles are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publishing an R package in the Journal of Statistical Software</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/jss-rpackages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 05:41:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/jss-rpackages/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been an editor of JSS for the last few years, and as a result I tend to get email from people asking me about publishing papers describing R packages in JSS. So for all those wondering, here are some general comments.JSS prefers to publish papers about packages where the package is on CRAN and has been there long enough to have matured (i.e., obvious bugs ironed out and a few active users).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic forecasting by Gneiting and Katzfuss (2014)</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/gneiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 05:57:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/gneiting/</guid>
      <description>The IJF is introducing occasional review papers on areas of forecasting. We did a whole issue in 2006 reviewing 25 years of research since the International Institute of Forecasters was established. Since then, there has been a lot of new work in application areas such as call center forecasting and electricity price forecasting. In addition, there are areas we did not cover in 2006 including new product forecasting and forecasting in finance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IJF news</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 03:38:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-news/</guid>
      <description>This is a short piece I wrote for the next issue of the Oracle newsletter produced by the International Institute of Forecasters.Special section topics We continue to publish special sections on selected topics. Because of the change in the way regular papers are now handled, we do not publish whole special issues any more. Rather, each issue has regular papers at the front, and if there are any special sections they appear at the back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get your paper rejected quickly</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/quick-rejection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 01:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/quick-rejection/</guid>
      <description>I sent this rejection letter this morning about a paper submitted to the International Journal of Forecasting.
 Dear XXXXX.
I am writing to you regarding manuscript ????? entitled &amp;ldquo;xxxxxxxxxxxx&amp;rdquo; which you submitted to the International Journal of Forecasting.
It so happens that I am aware that this paper was previously reviewed for the YYYYYYY journal. It seems that you have not bothered to make any of the changes recommended by the reviewers of your submission to YYYYYYY.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic Energy Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/probabilistic-energy-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 04:07:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/probabilistic-energy-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>The International Journal of Forecasting is calling for papers on probabilistic energy forecasting. Here are the details (taken from Tao Hong&amp;rsquo;s blog).In today&amp;rsquo;s competitive and dynamic environment, more and more decision making processes in the energy industry are relying on probabilistic forecasts. The applications of probabilistic energy forecasts spread across planning and operations of the entire energy value chain. We are seeking papers from researchers working on the areas of probabilistic energy forecasting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IJF quality indicators</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-quality-indicators/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 00:35:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-quality-indicators/</guid>
      <description>I often receive email asking about IJF quality indicators. Here is one I received today.
 Dear Professor Hyndman,
I recently had a paper published in IJF entitled, &amp;ldquo;xxxxxxxxxxxx&amp;rdquo;. I am very pleased with the publication and consider IJF to be an excellent outlet for my work in time-series econometrics.
I have an unusual request, but I hope you will consider responding. My research is judged by non-economists and IJF is not on their list of &amp;ldquo;quality&amp;rdquo; journals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Establishing priority</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/establishing-priority/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 03:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/establishing-priority/</guid>
      <description>The nature of research is that other people are probably working on similar ideas to you, and it is possible that someone will beat you to publishing them.When I was working on my PhD, I discovered another PhD thesis by Iris Yeung at UKC with almost exactly the same title as mine, and published a year earlier. In those days, a copy of a thesis had to be printed from microfiche, and then posted by snail mail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogs about research</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/blogs-about-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 02:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/blogs-about-research/</guid>
      <description>If you find this blog helpful (or even if you don&amp;rsquo;t but you&amp;rsquo;re interested in blogs on research issues and tools), there are a few other blogs about doing research that you might find useful. Here are a few that I read.
 Patter &amp;ndash; Pat Thomson.
 The Thesis Whisperer &amp;ndash; Inger Mewburn.
 The Research Whisperer &amp;ndash; several RMIT researchers.
 the (research) supervisor&amp;rsquo;s friend &amp;ndash; Geof Hill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Read the literature</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/read-the-literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 04:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/read-the-literature/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve just finished another reviewer report for a journal, and yet again I&amp;rsquo;ve had to make comments about reading the literature. It&amp;rsquo;s not difficult. Before you write a paper, read what other people have done. A simple search on Google scholar will usually do the trick. And before you submit a paper, check again that you haven&amp;rsquo;t missed anything important.
The paper I reviewed today did not cite a single reference from either of the two most active research groups in the area in the last ten years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Put your pre-prints online</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/preprints/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2012 04:13:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/preprints/</guid>
      <description>I have argued previously that research papers should be posted online at the same time as they are submitted to a journal. Sometimes people claim that journals don&amp;rsquo;t allow it, which is nonsense. Almost every journal allows it, and many also allow the published version of a paper to appear on your personal website.
Today I discovered a new tool (thanks to the IMU newsletter) which makes it easy to check a journal&amp;rsquo;s policy on this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog aggregators</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/blog-aggregators/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 10:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/blog-aggregators/</guid>
      <description>A very useful way of keeping up with blogs in a particular area is to subscribe to a blog aggregator. These will syndicate posts from a large number of blogs and provide links back to the original sources. So you only need to subscribe once to get all the good stuff in that area.
There are now several blog aggregators available that might be of interest to readers here. And this blog is now syndicated on several other sites including those listed below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google scholar metrics</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/google-scholar-metrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 02:45:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/google-scholar-metrics/</guid>
      <description>Google has produced another great tool for researchers, this time providing some metrics on journal citations. Google Scholar Metrics allows you to search on journals rather than articles, and to see the average or median h-index for each journal.
For example, a search on &amp;ldquo;forecasting&amp;rdquo; yields the following results:

The h-index is the largest number $h$ such that at least $h$ articles in that publication were cited at least $h$ times each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Following authors on Google Scholar</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/googlescholar2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 01:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/googlescholar2/</guid>
      <description>A great new feature has been added to Google Scholar Citations. For those authors who have set up a citations page, it is now possible to get email alerts for any new articles they publish, or for any new citations of their articles. So you can track citations to your own work this way, and stay up-to-date with key authors in your field.
Setting up a Google Citations page is super-easy and was already worth doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refereeing a journal article</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/refereeing2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2012 02:50:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/refereeing2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written briefly on this before. For an excellent and more detailed discussion of what is involved, there is a series of excellent posts on Pat Thomson&amp;rsquo;s blog:
 Refereeing a journal article part 1: reading
 Refereeing a journal article part 2: making a recommendation
 Refereeing a journal article part 3: writing the feedback
  If every reviewer followed her advice, my life as an editor would be much easier, and the quality of research would be improved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Researcher portals</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/portals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2011 04:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/portals/</guid>
      <description>A researcher portal is a website that attempts to list all the publications of a given researcher. Some portals also allow sharing papers, interacting with other researchers, calculating citation statistics, etc. Every researcher wants their work read and cited, so these websites can be useful tools for getting your work noticed. They can also function as a de facto home page if you don&amp;rsquo;t already have a personal website. Conversely, they can be a good way to find new work by researchers in your field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The scourge of the academic publishers</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/scourge/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2011 05:35:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/scourge/</guid>
      <description>Academic publishing is built on an old model where publishers were needed to print and distribute journals to libraries. Under this system, it makes sense that the journals are distributed by publishing companies who charge fees for their work. On the other hand, the academics who write for the journals, the peer reviewers and (almost all) editors, have always contributed their time and expertise without cost. Essentially, they are being paid by universities and other research organizations to do this work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beware of junk journals and publishers</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/junkjournals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2011 02:14:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/junkjournals/</guid>
      <description>Today I received the following email:
 Dear Professor,
 Antarctica Journal of Mathematics Archimedes Journal of Mathematics Bessel Journal of Mathematics Cayley Journal of Mathematics Diophantus Journal of Mathematics  We are charging only $3 per page, which is very cheap when compared to some money oriented journals.
Further we request you to withdraw your paper from other journals keeping in view of high page charges.
You can submit your research papers to our online journals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recommended survey papers</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/surveypapers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2011 12:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/surveypapers/</guid>
      <description>Survey articles are particularly helpful in getting a foothold in a new research area, or in looking for important papers that you may have overlooked. Whatever area of research you are in, look out for survey papers and journals dedicated to publishing survey papers.The journal Statistics Surveys is relatively new (volume 1 in 2007) and provides very helpful survey articles of areas of statistical research. It is sponsored by the American Statistical Association, the Bernoulli Society, the Institute of Mathematical Statistics, and by the Statistical Society of Canada.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authorship ethics</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/authorship/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2011 00:42:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/authorship/</guid>
      <description>With the constant pressure on academics to publish research papers, there is a temptation for research groups to include &amp;ldquo;coauthors&amp;rdquo; who have not really made any contribution to the manuscript. This seems more prevalent in some fields (e.g., the health sciences) than others.
Occasionally, I am asked to add an author to a paper that has already been accepted for publication in the International Journal of Forecasting. I am very reluctant to do this as it is hard to imagine how someone could be left off a paper while it goes through several revisions, only to be remembered after the paper is accepted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a referee</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/refereeing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2011 22:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/refereeing/</guid>
      <description>I regularly get emails from people wanting to be referees for the International Journal of Forecasting, usually with an accompanying CV. This is not how the process works.
Referees are almost always selected because they have previously written papers on a similar topic to the manuscript under review. If you want to be a referee, then write good papers and get them published in scholarly journals. Very quickly you will be invited to referee papers in the same journals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CrossValidated Journal Club</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/cvjournalclub/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2010 00:01:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/cvjournalclub/</guid>
      <description>Journal Clubs are a great way to learn new research ideas and to keep up with the literature. The idea is that a group of people get together every week or so to discuss a paper of joint interest. This can happen within your own research group or department, or virtually online.
There is now a virtual journal club operating in conjunction with CrossValidated.com. The first paper discussed was on text data mining.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to avoid annoying a referee</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/how-to-avoid-annoying-a-referee/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2010 09:23:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/how-to-avoid-annoying-a-referee/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s not a good idea to annoy the referees of your paper. They make recommendations to the editor about your work and it is best to keep them happy. There is an interesting discussion on stats.stackexchange.com on this subject. This inspired my own list below.
 Explain what you&amp;rsquo;ve done clearly, avoiding unnecessary jargon. Don&amp;rsquo;t claim your paper contributes more than it actually does. (I refereed a paper this week where the author claimed to have invented principal component analysis!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Always listen to reviewers</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/always-listen-to-reviewers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 03:39:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/always-listen-to-reviewers/</guid>
      <description>This week I was asked to review a paper that I had seen before. It had been submitted to a journal a few months ago and I had written a detailed report describing some problems with the paper, and noting a large number of typos that needed fixing. That journal had rejected the paper, the authors had submitted it to a second journal, and the paper ended up on my desk again for review.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joining an editorial board</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/editorialboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 05:51:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/editorialboards/</guid>
      <description>Being on the editorial board of a journal is a lot of work. I&amp;rsquo;m currently Editor-in-Chief of the International Journal of Forecasting and previously I&amp;rsquo;ve been Theory &amp;amp; Methods Editor of the Australian &amp;amp; New Zealand Journal of Statistics. Although it is time-consuming and often goes un-noticed, there are some important rewards that make it worthwhile in my opinion.
 You are forced to read carefully a lot of papers in your area of interest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your name is your brand</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/names/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2010 01:59:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/names/</guid>
      <description>As a researcher, you want to become known as an expert in your field. You need people to recognize your name and associate it with your research. Consequently, it is important to be consistent in the name you use on publications.
For example, I could write under &amp;ldquo;R Hyndman&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;R J Hyndman&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Rob Hyndman&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Rob J Hyndman&amp;rdquo;, etc. I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen the last of these and I try to use it on all publications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twenty rules for good graphics</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 06:34:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/graphics/</guid>
      <description>One of the things I repeatedly include in referee reports, and in my responses to authors who have submitted papers to the International Journal of Forecasting, are comments designed to include the quality of the graphics. Recently someone asked on stats.stackexchange.com aboutbest practices for producing plots. So I thought it might be helpful to collate some of the answers given there and add a few comments of my own taken from things I&amp;rsquo;ve written for authors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The falling standard of English in research</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/english/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2010 00:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/english/</guid>
      <description>It seems that most journals no longer do any serious copy-editing, and the standard of English is falling. Today I was reading an article from the European Journal of Operational Research, which is supposedly a good OR journal (current impact factor over 2). Take this for an example from the first page of this paper:
 If the learned patterns are unstable, the learning tools would produce inconsistent concepts. To overcome this difficult situation, we employed artificial neural networks (ANNs, NNs) for helping the learning task.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should you make your working papers public?</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/working-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 08:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/working-papers/</guid>
      <description>There seems to be two points of view on this with different practices in different disciplines.
 Some researchers do not make their work public until after it has been accepted for publication in a journal. Until that time, drafts of papers are only circulated to close confidants and usually marked &amp;ldquo;Do not distribute&amp;rdquo;.
 Working papers are published on web sites and in web repositories (such as arXiv or RePEc) as soon as they are finished, at about the same time they are submitted to a journal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google scholar alerts</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/google-scholar-alerts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 06:14:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/google-scholar-alerts/</guid>
      <description>A couple of weeks ago, Google scholar added a facility to provide email alerts on new articles associated with specific search queries. First do the search, then click the envelope at top left of screen. For example, here is a search on &amp;ldquo;exponential smoothing&amp;rdquo; since 2000.

Note the envelope at the top marked New! Click it to get the following screen.

Those results show some of the flaws in Google Scholar &amp;ndash; the dates are not always correct (the first paper listed above appeared in 2004) and there are unresolved duplicates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why referee?</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/why-referee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 04:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/why-referee/</guid>
      <description>There are several reasons why researchers should be willing to provide referee reports.
 You learn a lot. If the paper is in your area, then writing a referee report forces you to read it very carefully and engage closely with the research of other people in your field. There&amp;rsquo;s no better way of understand what is going on in your field.
 You get better known by the research leaders in your area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing a referee report</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/referee-reports/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 04:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/referee-reports/</guid>
      <description>As an editor, I like to see referee reports comprising three sections:
 A general summary of the paper and the contribution it makes. You need to highlight here what is new and interesting about the paper, as well as give a summary in a few sentences.
 The major problems that need addressing. This is probably the most important section of your report where you explain the main problems. The editor will read this very carefully when deciding whether to accept, reject or invite a revision, so you need to make sure that any problems are clearly explained here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using DOIs</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/doi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2009 12:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/doi/</guid>
      <description>Almost all papers these days have a DOI and it is worth knowing how to use them.
At the top or bottom of the first page of a paper, you will see something like this:
doi:10.1016/j.csda.2006.07.028  This is a unique and permanent identifier for the paper known as a &amp;ldquo;Digital Object Identifier&amp;rdquo;. The part before the forward slash (10.1016 in the example above) identifies the naming authority (in this case Elsevier) and the part after the forward slash (j.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics education journals</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/statistics-education-journals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 03:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/statistics-education-journals/</guid>
      <description>In many research universities, there can be a tension that arises when great teachers don&amp;rsquo;t publish much. I believe there is a place for excellent teachers who do limited research within a strong research university, but their contribution is considerably enhanced if they share their teaching insights. There are at least three reputable research journals for publishing articles on statistics education:
 Journal of Statistics Education
 Statistics Education Research Journal</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing responses to referee reports</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/responses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2009 03:41:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/responses/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending time writing response letters lately. I&amp;rsquo;ve also been reading lots of response letters from authors wanting their stuff published in the International Journal of Forecasting. I thought it might be useful to collate a few thoughts on the subject.
 No grovelling. I sometimes get response letters that start off with a paragraph of inane and obsequious fawning. The real response only begins after a paragraph of flattery which makes me wonder why I&amp;rsquo;ve never won the Nobel prize.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching the research literature</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/searching-the-research-literature/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 22:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/searching-the-research-literature/</guid>
      <description>Most students seem to go to Google first. This is not a good strategy. Google Scholar is much better as it filters out all the junk. Scopus is another engine that aims to do a similar thing. It is better organized but not so complete. ISI WOK is also not as complete as Google Scholar but is particularly good at tracking citations.
 Google scholar
 Scopus
 ISI Web of Knowledge</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accessing journal articles online</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/accessing-journal-articles-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 08:21:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/accessing-journal-articles-online/</guid>
      <description>When searching for research articles online, I often find that the article is unavailable unless I go through the Monash library website, especially when working from home. Here are two solutions to the problem
 Within Google scholar, go to &amp;ldquo;Scholar preferences&amp;rdquo; and under library links search for &amp;ldquo;Monash&amp;rdquo;. Tick the entry &amp;ldquo;Monash University - Check for full text&amp;rdquo;. Then save your preferences (button at bottom of page). Next time you do a Google scholar search, a link labelled &amp;ldquo;Check for full text&amp;rdquo; will appear beside each entry.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>