<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beamer on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/categories/beamer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Beamer on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 21:53:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/categories/beamer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Monash Rmarkdown templates on github</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/monash-rmarkdown-templates-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 21:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/monash-rmarkdown-templates-on-github/</guid>
      <description>Rmarkdown templates for staff and students in my department are now available on github. For a thesis, fork the repository MonashThesis.
For other templates, install the R package MonashEBSTemplates R package. This provides templates for
 beamer slides working papers exams letters  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a handout from beamer slides</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/beamer-handout/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 01:29:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/beamer-handout/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m about to head off on a speaking tour to Europe (more on that in another post) and one of my hosts has asked for my powerpoint slides so they can print them. They have made two false assumptions: (1) that I use powerpoint; (2) that my slides are static so they can be printed.
Instead, I produced a cut-down version of my beamer slides, leaving out some of the animations and other features that will not print easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing white space around R figures</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/crop-r-figures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 00:22:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/crop-r-figures/</guid>
      <description>When I want to insert figures generated in R into a LaTeX document, it looks better if I first remove the white space around the figure. Unfortunately, R does not make this easy as the graphs are generated to look good on a screen, not in a document.
There are two things that can be done to fix this problem.First, you can reduce the white space generated by R. I use the following function when saving figures in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bare bones beamer</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/beamer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 06:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/beamer/</guid>
      <description>Beamer is far and away the most popular software for presentations amongst researchers in mathematics and statistics. Most conference and seminar talks I attend these days use beamer. Unfortunately, they all look much the same. I think people find beamer themes too hard to modify easily, so a small number of templates get shared around. Even the otherwise wonderful LaTeX Templates site has no beamer examples.
The beamer user guide explains how to make changes but it is not for the faint-hearted (although it is a fantastic resource once you have some expertise).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a poster in beamer</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/beamer-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2010 04:57:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/beamer-poster/</guid>
      <description>This week, I made my first poster. Although I&amp;rsquo;ve been an academic for more than 20 years, I&amp;rsquo;ve never had to make a poster before. Some of my coauthors have made posters about our joint research, and two of them have even won prizes (although I can&amp;rsquo;t take any credit for them). But this week, our department is displaying posters from all research staff about our recent work.
Here is my poster (click for pdf version):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving a research seminar</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/giving-a-research-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 07:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/giving-a-research-seminar/</guid>
      <description>An expanded version of this post is available in my article on “Giving an academic talk”.
With conference season almost upon us, it is timely to discuss what makes a good conference presentation. Here is a suggested structure.
 A motivating example demonstrating the problem you are trying to solve. Explain existing approaches to the problem and their weaknesses. Describe your main contributions. Show how your ideas solve the problem/example you started with.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>