<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>State Space Models on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/tags/state-space-models/</link>
    <description>Recent content in State Space Models on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 03:03:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/tags/state-space-models/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting: principles and practice (UWA course)</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/uwa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 03:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/uwa/</guid>
      <description> Workshop to be held on 23-25 September 2014.
Venue: The University Club, University of Western Australia, Nedlands WA.
Requirements: a laptop with R installed, along with the fpp package and its dependencies. We will also use the hts and vars package on the third day.
Textbook [Hyndman and Athanasopoulos (2014)
Forecasting: principles and practice, OTexts: Melbourne, Australia](http://www.otexts.org/fpp).
Program  Introduction to forecasting [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Forecasting tools [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Exponential smoothing I [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Exponential smoothing II [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Time series decomposition and cross-validation [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Transformations, stationarity and differencing [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Non-seasonal ARIMA models [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Seasonal ARIMA models [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] State space models [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Dynamic regression [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Hierarchical forecasting [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Advanced methods [Slides, R code, Lab solutions]  Course Notes </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State space models</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/abs-state-space-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 01:21:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/abs-state-space-models/</guid>
      <description>Exponential smoothing
 Slides R examples Lab session Solutions to lab session  Structural models
 Slides R examples Lab session Solutions to lab session  ARIMA and RegARMA models, and dlm
 Slides R examples   (Updated: 2 June 2014)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting time series with complex seasonal patterns using exponential smoothing</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/complex-seasonality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2011 02:38:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/complex-seasonality/</guid>
      <description>A new innovations state space modeling framework, incorporating Box-Cox transformations, Fourier series with time varying coefficients and ARMA error correction, is introduced for forecasting complex seasonal time series that cannot be handled using existing forecasting models. Such complex time series include time series with multiple seasonal periods, high frequency seasonality, non-integer seasonality and dual-calendar effects. Our new modelling framework provides an alternative to existing exponential smoothing models, and is shown to have many advantages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The vector innovations structural time series framework: a simple approach to multivariate forecasting</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/vists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2010 23:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/vists/</guid>
      <description>The vector innovations structural time series framework is proposed as a way of modelling a set of related time series. Like all multivariate approaches, the aim is to exploit potential inter-series dependencies to improve the fit and forecasts. The model is based around an unobserved vector of components representing features such as the level and slope of each time series. Equations that describe the evolution of these components through time are used to represent the inter-temporal dependencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exponential smoothing and non-negative data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/expsmooth-nonnegative/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2009 23:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/expsmooth-nonnegative/</guid>
      <description>The most common forecasting methods in business are based on exponential smoothing and the most common time series in business are inherently non-negative. Therefore it is of interest to consider the properties of the potential stochastic models underlying exponential smoothing when applied to non-negative data. We explore exponential smoothing state space models for non-negative data under various assumptions about the innovations, or error, process.
We first demonstrate that prediction distributions from some commonly used state space models may have an infinite variance beyond a certain forecasting horizon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multivariate innovations state space Beveridge-Nelson decomposition</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/vists-beveridge-nelson/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 23:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/vists-beveridge-nelson/</guid>
      <description>The Beveridge-Nelson vector innovations structural time series framework is a new formulation that decomposes a set of variables into their permanent and transitory components. The proposed framework is flexible, modelling inter-series relationships and common features in a simple manner. In particular, it is shown that this new specification is simpler than conventional state space and cointegration approaches. The approach is illustrated using a trivariate data set comprising the GDP of Australia, the USA and the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting time series with multiple seasonal patterns</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/multiple-seasonal-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2008 05:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/multiple-seasonal-patterns/</guid>
      <description>A new approach is proposed for forecasting a time series with multiple seasonal patterns. A state space model is developed for the series using the innovation approach which enables us to develop explicit models for both additive and multiplicative seasonality. Parameter estimates may be obtained using methods from exponential smoothing. The proposed model is used to examine hourly and daily patterns in hourly data for both utility loads and traffic flows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The admissible parameter space for exponential smoothing models</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/the-admissible-parameter-space-for-exponential-smoothing-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2008 06:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/the-admissible-parameter-space-for-exponential-smoothing-models/</guid>
      <description>We discuss the admissible parameter space for some state space models, including the models that underly exponential smoothing methods. We find that the usual parameter restrictions (requiring all smoothing parameters to lie between 0 and 1) do not always lead to stable models. We also find that all seasonal exponential smoothing methods are unstable as the underlying state space models are neither reachable nor observable. This instability does not affect the forecasts, but does corrupt the state estimates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exponential smoothing and non-negative data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/exponential-smoothing-and-non-negative-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 07:51:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/exponential-smoothing-and-non-negative-data/</guid>
      <description>Where: International Symposium on Forecasting, Nice, France  Abstract: The most common forecasting methods in business are based on exponential smoothing and the most common time series in business are inherently non-negative. Therefore it is of interest to consider the properties of the potential stochastic models underlying exponential smoothing when applied to non-negative data. We explore nonlinear exponential smoothing state space models for non-negative data under various assumptions about the innovations, or error, process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A state space model for exponential smoothing with group seasonality</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/a-state-space-model-for-exponential-smoothing-with-group-seasonality/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2007 01:54:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/a-state-space-model-for-exponential-smoothing-with-group-seasonality/</guid>
      <description>We present an approach to improve forecast accuracy by simultaneously forecasting a group of products that exhibit similar seasonal demand patterns. Better seasonality estimates can be made by using information on all products in a group, and using these improved estimates when forecasting at the individual product level. This approach is called the group seasonal indices (GSI) approach, and is a generalization of the classical Holt-Winters procedure. This article describes an underlying state space model for this method and presents simulation results that show when it yields more accurate forecasts than Holt-Winters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time series forecasting: the case for the single source of error state space approach</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/322/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2005 01:48:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/322/</guid>
      <description>The state space approach to modelling univariate time series is now widely used both in theory and in applications. However, the very richness of the framework means that quite different model formulations are possible, even when they purport to describe the same phenomena. In this paper, we examine the single source of error [SSOE] scheme, which has perfectly correlated error components. We then proceed to compare SSOE to the more common version of the state space models, for which all the error terms are independent; we refer to this as the multiple source of error [MSOE] scheme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction intervals for exponential smoothing using two new classes of state space models</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/prediction-intervals-for-exponential-smoothing-using-two-new-classes-of-state-space-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2005 03:53:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/prediction-intervals-for-exponential-smoothing-using-two-new-classes-of-state-space-models/</guid>
      <description>Three general classes of state space models are presented, based upon the single source of error formulation. The first class is the standard linear state space model with homoscedastic errors, the second retains the linear structure but incorporates a dynamic form of heteroscedasticity, and the third allows for non-linear structure in the observation equation as well as heteroscedasticity. These three classes provide stochastic models for a wide variety of exponential smoothing methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A state space framework for automatic forecasting using exponential smoothing methods</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/hksg/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2002 03:21:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/hksg/</guid>
      <description>We provide a new approach to automatic busineswwwwws forecasting based on an extended range of exponential smoothing methods. Each method in our taxonomy of exponential smoothing methods can be shown to be equivalent to the forecasts obtained from a state space model. This allows (1) the easy calculation of the likelihood, the AIC and other model selection criteria; (2) the computation of prediction intervals for each method; and (3) random simulation from the underlying state space model.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>