<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Electricity on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/tags/electricity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Electricity on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/tags/electricity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Probabilistic Forecasting of Electricity Demand with Smart Meter Data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/hpf-electricity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/hpf-electricity/</guid>
      <description>Electricity smart meters record consumption, on a near real-time basis, at the level of individual commercial and residential properties. From this, a hierarchy can be constructed consisting of time series of demand at the smart meter level, and at various levels of aggregation, such as substations, cities and regions. Forecasts are needed at each level to support the efficient and reliable management of consumption. A limitation of previous research in this area is that it considered only deterministic prediction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coherent Probabilistic Forecasts for Hierarchical Time Series</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/probhts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/probhts/</guid>
      <description>Many applications require forecasts for a hierarchy comprising a set of time series along with aggregates of subsets of these series. Although forecasts can be produced independently for each series in the hierarchy, typically this does not lead to coherent forecasts — the property that forecasts add up appropriately across the hierarchy. State-of-the-art hierarchical forecasting methods usually reconcile these independently generated forecasts to satisfy the aggregation constraints. A fundamental limitation of prior research is that it has looked only at the problem of forecasting the mean of each time series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting uncertainty in electricity smart meter data by boosting additive quantile regression</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/smart-meter-quantiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 04:19:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/smart-meter-quantiles/</guid>
      <description>Smart electricity meters are currently deployed in millions of households to collect detailed individual electricity consumption data. Compared to traditional electricity data based on aggregated consumption, smart meter data are much more volatile and less predictable. There is a need within the energy industry for probabilistic forecasts of household electricity consumption to quantify the uncertainty of future electricity demand, in order to undertake appropriate planning of generation and distribution. We propose a probabilistic forecasting method where a different quantile regression model is estimated for each quantile of the future distribution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic Energy Forecasting: Global Energy Forecasting Competition 2014 and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/gefcom2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 00:40:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/gefcom2014/</guid>
      <description>The energy industry has been going through a significant modernization process over the last decade. Its infrastructure is being upgraded rapidly. The supply, demand and prices are becoming more volatile and less predictable than ever before. Even its business model is being challenged fundamentally. In this competitive and dynamic environment, many decision-making processes rely on probabilistic forecasts to quantify the uncertain future. Although most of the papers in the energy forecasting literature focus on point or single-valued forecasts, the research interest in probabilistic energy forecasting research has taken off rapidly in recent years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MEFM: An R package for long-term probabilistic forecasting of electricity demand</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/isf2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 23:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/isf2015/</guid>
      <description>International Symposium on Forecasting Riverside, California
I will describe and demonstrate a new open-source R package that implements the Monash Electricity Forecasting Model, a semi-parametric probabilistic approach to forecasting long-term electricity demand. The underlying model proposed in Hyndman and Fan (2010) is now widely used in practice, particularly in Australia. The model has undergone many improvements and developments since it was first proposed, and these have been incorporated in this R implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic forecasting of peak electricity demand</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/sce2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 23:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/sce2015/</guid>
      <description>Southern California Edison Rosemead, California
Electricity demand forecasting plays an important role in short-term load allocation and long-term planning for future generation facilities and transmission augmentation. It is a challenging problem because of the different uncertainties including underlying population growth, changing technology, economic conditions, prevailing weather conditions (and the timing of those conditions), as well as the general randomness inherent in individual usage. It is also subject to some known calendar effects due to the time of day, day of week, time of year, and public holidays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>STR: A Seasonal-Trend Decomposition Procedure Based on Regression</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/str/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2015 22:50:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/str/</guid>
      <description>We propose new generic methods for decomposing seasonal data: STR (a Seasonal-Trend decomposition procedure based on Regression) and Robust STR. In some ways, STR is similar to Ridge Regression and Robust STR can be related to LASSO. Our new methods are much more general than any alternative time series decomposition methods. They allow for multiple seasonal and cyclic components, and multiple linear regressors with constant, flexible, seasonal and cyclic influence. Seasonal patterns (for both seasonal components and seasonal regressors) can be fractional and flexible over time; moreover they can be either strictly periodic or have a more complex topology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic time series forecasting with boosted additive models: an application to smart meter data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/kdd2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 11:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/kdd2015/</guid>
      <description>A large body of the forecasting literature so far has been focused on forecasting the conditional mean of future observations. However, there is an increasing need for generating the entire conditional distribution of future observations in order to effectively quantify the uncertainty in time series data. We present two different methods for probabilistic time series forecasting that allow the inclusion of a possibly large set of exogenous variables. One method is based on forecasting both the conditional mean and variance of the future distribution using a traditional regression approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic forecasting of long-term peak electricity demand</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/memsi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 07:29:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/memsi/</guid>
      <description>Electricity demand forecasting plays an important role in long-term planning for future generation facilities and transmission augmentation. It is a challenging problem because of the different uncertainties including underlying population growth, changing technology, economic conditions, prevailing weather conditions (and the timing of those conditions), as well as the general randomness inherent in individual usage. It is also subject to some known calendar effects due to the time of day, day of week, time of year, and public holidays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenges in forecasting peak electricity demand</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/swiss-energy-forum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 06:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/swiss-energy-forum/</guid>
      <description>I am giving a two-part seminar at the Energy Forum, Valais/Wallis, Switzerland, on 17 June 2014. (English brochure)
Abstract: Electricity demand forecasting plays an important role in short-term load allocation and long-term planning for future generation facilities and transmission augmentation. It is a challenging problem because of the different uncertainties including underlying population growth, changing technology, economic conditions, prevailing weather conditions (and the timing of those conditions), as well as the general randomness inherent in individual usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monash Electricity Forecasting Model</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/mefm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 01:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/mefm/</guid>
      <description>The model we developed for peak electricity demand forecasting in Hyndman and Fan (2010) is now widely used in practice around Australia, and has undergone many improvements and developments. This document describes the current version of the model. It will be updated from time to time as the model continues to be modified and improved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A gradient boosting approach to the Kaggle load forecasting competition</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/kaggleloadforecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 04:40:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/kaggleloadforecasting/</guid>
      <description>We describe and analyse the approach used by Team TinTin (Souhaib Ben Taieb and Rob&amp;nbsp;J&amp;nbsp;Hyndman) in the Load Forecasting track of the Kaggle Global Energy Forecasting Competition 2012. The competition involved a hierarchical load forecasting problem for a US utility with 20 geographical zones. The available data consisted of the hourly loads for the 20 zones and hourly temperatures from 11 weather stations, for four and a half years. For each zone, the hourly electricity load for nine different weeks needed to be predicted without having the location of zones or stations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short-term load forecasting based on a semi-parametric additive model</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/stlf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 06:37:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/stlf/</guid>
      <description>Short-term load forecasting is an essential instrument in power system planning, operation and control. Many operating decisions are based on load forecasts, such as dispatch scheduling of generating capacity, reliability analysis, and maintenance planning for the generators. Overestimation of electricity demand will cause a conservative operation, which leads to the start-up of too many units or excessive energy purchase, thereby supplying an unnecessary level of reserve. On the contrary, underestimation may result in a risky operation, with insufficient preparation of spinning reserve, causing the system to operate in a vulnerable region to the disturbance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting electricity demand distributions using a semiparametric additive model </title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/electricity-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 03:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/electricity-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>Talk given at
 University of Melbourne, 11 October 2011. University of Adelaide, 16 March 2012 Monash University, 16 May 2012 La Trobe University, 24 May 2012 EDF, Paris. 4 September 2012 University of New South Wales, 1 November 2012  Abstract: Electricity demand forecasting plays an important role in short-term load allocation and long-term planning for future generation facilities and transmission augmentation. Planners must adopt a probabilistic view of potential peak demand levels, therefore density forecasts (providing estimates of the full probability distributions of the possible future values of the demand) are more helpful than point forecasts, and are necessary for utilities to evaluate and hedge the financial risk accrued by demand variability and forecasting uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating extreme quantile forecasts</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/maep/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 11:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/maep/</guid>
      <description>Talk to be given at the International Symposium on Forecasting, Prague, 26–29 June 2011.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The price elasticity of electricity demand in South Australia</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/electricity-price-elasticity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/electricity-price-elasticity/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, the price elasticity of electricity demand, representing the sensitivity of customer demand to the price of electricity, has been estimated for South Australia. We first undertake a review of the scholarly literature regarding electricity price elasticity for different regions and systems. Then we perform an empirical evaluation of the historic South Australian price elasticity, focussing on the relationship between price and demand quantiles at each half-hour of the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short-term load forecasting based on a semi-parametric additive model</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/aupec2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2010 09:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/aupec2010/</guid>
      <description>Short-term load forecasting is an essential instrument in power system planning, operation and control. Many operating decisions are based on load forecasts, such as dispatch scheduling of generating capacity, reliability analysis, and maintenance planning for the generators. Overestimation of electricity demand will cause a conservative operation, which leads to the start-up of too many units or excessive energy purchase, thereby supplying an unnecessary level of reserve. On the contrary, underestimation may result in a risky operation, with insufficient preparation of spinning reserve, causing the system to operate in a vulnerable region to the disturbance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Density forecasting for long-term peak electricity demand</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/peak-electricity-demand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 23:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/peak-electricity-demand/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Long-term electricity demand forecasting plays an important role in planning for future generation facilities and transmission augmentation. In a long term context, planners must adopt a probabilistic view of potential peak demand levels, therefore density forecasts (providing estimates of the full probability distributions of the possible future values of the demand) are more helpful than point forecasts, and are necessary for utilities to evaluate and hedge the financial risk accrued by demand variability and forecasting uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extreme forecasting</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/extreme-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2009 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/extreme-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>Keynote address, International Symposium on Forecasting, June 2009. Abstract
Extremely bad data, extremely poor methods and extremely difficult problems will be used as the basis of some extremely useful lessons. I will describe three cases from my consulting experience and draw some general lessons that are widely applicable.
The first case involved forecasting passenger traffic on an Australian airline. The data showed variations due to school holidays, major sporting events, competitor activity, industrial disputes, changes in fare structures, and other factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting medium- and long-term peak electricity demand</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/forecasting-medium-and-long-term-peak-electricity-demand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2007 08:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/forecasting-medium-and-long-term-peak-electricity-demand/</guid>
      <description>Where: International Symposium on Forecasting, New York  Abstract: Peak electricity demand forecasting is important in medium and long-term planning of electricity supply. Extreme demand often leads to supply failure with consequential business and social disruption. Forecasting extreme demand events is therefore an important problem in energy management.
Electricity demand at a given time is subject to a range of influences, including the ambient temperature, recent past temperatures, time of day, day of week, holidays, economic conditions and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>