<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/categories/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Teaching on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/categories/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting workshop in Perth</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/forecasting-workshop-perth/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/forecasting-workshop-perth/</guid>
      <description>On 26-28 September 2017, I will be running my 3-day workshop in Perth on &amp;ldquo;Forecasting: principles and practice&amp;rdquo; based on my book of the same name.
Topics to be covered include seasonality and trends, exponential smoothing, ARIMA modelling, dynamic regression and state space models, as well as forecast accuracy methods and forecast evaluation techniques such as cross-validation.
Workshop participants are expected to be familiar with basic statistical tools such as multiple regression, but no knowledge of time series or forecasting will be assumed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow-up forecasting forum in Eindhoven</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/eindhoven2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 22:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/eindhoven2/</guid>
      <description>Last October I gave a 3-day masterclass on &amp;ldquo;Forecasting with R&amp;rdquo; in Eindhoven, Netherlands. There is a follow-up event planned for Tuesday 18 April 2017. It is particularly designed for people who attended the 3-day class, but if anyone else wants to attend they would be welcome.
Please register here if you want to attend.The preliminary schedule is as follows.
10.00 -- 11.00  New developments in forecasting using R   forecast v8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Forecasting with R&#34; short course in Eindhoven</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/eindhoven-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/eindhoven-course/</guid>
      <description>I will be giving my 3-day short-course/workshop on &amp;ldquo;Forecasting with R&amp;rdquo; in Eindhoven (Netherlands) from 19-21 October.
Details at https://www.win.tue.nl/~adriemel/shortcourse.html
Register here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The bias-variance decomposition</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/bias-variance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2015 07:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/bias-variance/</guid>
      <description>This week, I am teaching my Business Analytics class about the bias-variance trade-off. For some reason, the proof is not contained in either ESL or ISL, even though it is quite simple. I also discovered that the proof currently provided on Wikipedia makes little sense in places.
So I wrote my own for the class. It is longer than necessary to ensure there are no jumps that might confuse students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources for the FPP book</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/fpp-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 01:59:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/fpp-resources/</guid>
      <description>The FPP resources page has recently been updated with several new additions including
 R code for all examples in the book. This was already available within each chapter, but the examples have been collected into one file per chapter to save copying and pasting the various code fragments.
 Slides from a course on Predictive Analytics from the University of Sydney.
 Slides from a course on Economic Forecasting from the University of Hawaii.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting with R in WA</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/forecasting-with-r-in-wa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 22:53:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/forecasting-with-r-in-wa/</guid>
      <description>On 23-25 September, I will be running a 3-day workshop in Perth on &amp;ldquo;Forecasting: principles and practice&amp;rdquo; mostly based on my book of the same name.
Workshop participants will be assumed to be familiar with basic statistical tools such as multiple regression, but no knowledge of time series or forecasting will be assumed. Some prior experience in R is highly desirable.
Venue: The University Club, University of Western Australia, Nedlands WA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student forecasting awards from the IIF</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/iif-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 03:14:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/iif-awards/</guid>
      <description>At the IIF annual board meeting last month in Rotterdam, I suggested that we provide awards to the top students studying forecasting at university level around the world, to the tune of $100 plus IIF membership for a year. I&amp;rsquo;m delighted that the idea met with enthusiasm, and that the awards are now available. Even better, my second year forecasting subject has been approved for an award.
The IIF have agreed to fund awards for 20 forecasting courses to start with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a handout from beamer slides</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/beamer-handout/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 01:29:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/beamer-handout/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m about to head off on a speaking tour to Europe (more on that in another post) and one of my hosts has asked for my powerpoint slides so they can print them. They have made two false assumptions: (1) that I use powerpoint; (2) that my slides are static so they can be printed.
Instead, I produced a cut-down version of my beamer slides, leaving out some of the animations and other features that will not print easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting noise</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/interpreting-noise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2014 00:04:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/interpreting-noise/</guid>
      <description>When watching the TV news, or reading newspaper commentary, I am frequently amazed at the attempts people make to interpret random noise.
For example, the latest tiny fluctuation in the share price of a major company is attributed to the CEO being ill. When the exchange rate goes up, the TV finance commentator confidently announces that it is a reaction to Chinese building contracts. No one ever says &amp;ldquo;The unemployment rate has dropped by 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast computation of cross-validation in linear models</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/loocv-linear-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 10:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/loocv-linear-models/</guid>
      <description>The leave-one-out cross-validation statistic is given by
 $$ \text{CV} = \frac{1}{N} \sum_{i=1}^N e_{[i]}^2, $$  where ${e_{[i]} = y_{i} - \hat{y}_{[i]}} $, the observations are given by $y_{1},\dots,y_{N}$, and $\hat{y}_{[i]}$ is the predicted value obtained when the model is estimated with the $i\text{th}$ case deleted. This is also sometimes known as the PRESS (Prediction Residual Sum of Squares) statistic.
It turns out that for linear models, we do not actually have to estimate the model $N$ times, once for each omitted case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highlighting the web</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/highlighting-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 01:29:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/highlighting-the-web/</guid>
      <description>Users of my new online forecasting book have asked about having a facility for personal highlighting of selected sections, as students often do with print books. We have plans to make this a built-in part of the platform, but for now it is possible to do it using a simple browser extension. This approach allows any website to be highlighted, so is even more useful than if we only had the facility on OTexts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interview for the Capital of Statistics</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/cos-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2014 00:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/cos-interview/</guid>
      <description>Earo Wang recently interviewed me for the Chinese website Capital of Statistics. The English transcript of the intervew is on Earo&amp;rsquo;s personal website.
This is the third interview I&amp;rsquo;ve done in the last 18 months. The others were for:
 Data Mining Research. Republished in Amstat News.
 DecisionStats.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free books on statistical learning</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/free-books-on-statistical-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2014 01:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/free-books-on-statistical-learning/</guid>
      <description>Hastie, Tibshirani and Friedman&amp;rsquo;s Elements of Statistical Learning first appeared in 2001 and is already a classic. It is my go-to book when I need a quick refresher on a machine learning algorithm. I like it because it is written using the language and perspective of statistics, and provides a very useful entry point into the literature of machine learning which has its own terminology for statistical concepts. A free downloadable pdf version is available on the website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Man vs Wild Data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ysc2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 00:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ysc2013/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m speaking on this topic at the Young Statisticians Conference, 7-8 February 2013.
If you&amp;rsquo;re a young statistician and live in Australia, please book in. It promises to be a great couple of days. Early registrations close on 2 January.
Abstract for my talk:
For 25 years I have been an intrepid statistical consultant, tackling the wild frontiers of real data, real problems and real time constraints. I have faced problems ranging from linguistics to river beds, from making paper plates to selling pies at the MCG, from tax office audits to surveys about the colour purple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics education journals</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/statistics-education-journals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2009 03:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/statistics-education-journals/</guid>
      <description>In many research universities, there can be a tension that arises when great teachers don&amp;rsquo;t publish much. I believe there is a place for excellent teachers who do limited research within a strong research university, but their contribution is considerably enhanced if they share their teaching insights. There are at least three reputable research journals for publishing articles on statistics education:
 Journal of Statistics Education
 Statistics Education Research Journal</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>