<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Neural Networks on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/tags/neural-networks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Neural Networks on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/tags/neural-networks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A note on the validity of cross-validation for evaluating autoregressive time series prediction</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/cv-time-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/cv-time-series/</guid>
      <description>One of the most widely used standard procedures for model evaluation in classification and regression is $K$-fold cross-validation (CV). However, when it comes to time series forecasting, because of the inherent serial correlation and potential non-stationarity of the data, its application is not straightforward and often omitted by practitioners in favour of an out-of-sample (OOS) evaluation. In this paper, we show that in the case of a purely autoregressive model, the use of standard $K$-fold CV is possible as long as the models considered have uncorrelated errors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting: principles and practice (UWA course)</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/uwa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 03:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/uwa/</guid>
      <description> Workshop to be held on 23-25 September 2014.
Venue: The University Club, University of Western Australia, Nedlands WA.
Requirements: a laptop with R installed, along with the fpp package and its dependencies. We will also use the hts and vars package on the third day.
Textbook [Hyndman and Athanasopoulos (2014)
Forecasting: principles and practice, OTexts: Melbourne, Australia](http://www.otexts.org/fpp).
Program  Introduction to forecasting [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Forecasting tools [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Exponential smoothing I [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Exponential smoothing II [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Time series decomposition and cross-validation [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Transformations, stationarity and differencing [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Non-seasonal ARIMA models [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Seasonal ARIMA models [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] State space models [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Dynamic regression [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Hierarchical forecasting [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Advanced methods [Slides, R code, Lab solutions]  Course Notes </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characteristic-based clustering for time series data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/characteristic-based-clustering-for-time-series-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2006 05:52:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/characteristic-based-clustering-for-time-series-data/</guid>
      <description>With the growing importance of time series clustering research, particularly for similarity searches amongst long time series such as those arising in medicine or finance, it is critical for us to find a way to resolve the outstanding problems that make most clustering methods impractical under certain circumstances. When the time series is very long, some clustering algorithms may fail because the very notation of similarity is dubious in high dimension space; many methods cannot handle missing data when the clustering is based on a distance metric.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The accuracy of television network rating forecasts: the effects of data aggregation and alternative models</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/the-accuracy-of-television-network-rating-forecasts-the-effects-of-data-aggregation-and-alternative-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2006 05:47:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/the-accuracy-of-television-network-rating-forecasts-the-effects-of-data-aggregation-and-alternative-models/</guid>
      <description>This paper investigates the effect of aggregation in relation to the accuracy of television network rating forecasts. We compare the forecast accuracy of network ratings using population rating models, rating models for demographic/behavioural segments and individual viewing behaviour models. Models are fitted using neural networks, decision trees and regression. The most accurate forecasts are obtained by aggregating forecasts from segment rating models, with neural networks being used to fit these models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The pricing and trading of options using a hybrid neural network model with historical volatility</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/the-pricing-and-trading-of-options-using-a-hybrid-neural-network-model-with-historical-volatility/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 1997 02:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/the-pricing-and-trading-of-options-using-a-hybrid-neural-network-model-with-historical-volatility/</guid>
      <description>(Later known as Journal of Computational Intelligence in Finance)
The residuals between conventional option pricing models and market prices have persistent patterns or biases. The &amp;ldquo;hybrid&amp;rdquo; method models the residuals using an artificial neural network. The pricing accuracy of the hybrid method is demonstrated on real data using the Australian All Ordinaries Share Price Index options on futures and is compared with all major competing conventional models. The hybrid method is found to be both statistically and economically superior to the conventional models alone.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>