<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Epidemiology on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/tags/epidemiology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Epidemiology on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:54:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/tags/epidemiology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the influence of short-term temperature patterns on temperature-related mortality: a case-study of Melbourne, Australia</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/temperature-mortality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:54:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/temperature-mortality/</guid>
      <description>Background Several studies have identified the association between ambient temperature and mortality; however, several features of temperature behavior and their impacts on health remain unresolved.
We obtain daily counts of nonaccidental all-cause mortality data in the elderly (65 + years) and corresponding meteorological data for Melbourne, Australia during 1999 to 2006. We then characterize the temporal behavior of ambient temperature development by quantifying the rates of temperature change during periods designated by pre-specified windows ranging from 1 to 30 days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do human rhinovirus infections and food allergy modify grass pollen–induced asthma hospital admissions in children?</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/jaci2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 01:48:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/jaci2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outdoor fungal spores are associated with child asthma hospitalisations - a case-crossover study</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/fungal-asthma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 01:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/fungal-asthma/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Asthma can be exacerbated by exposure to various fungal spores and Human Rhinovirus [HRV], but current understanding of the importance of fungal exposure to child asthma hospitalisations is limited. Moreover the interaction between HRV and fungal spore exposure on admission has not been examined.
Aim To investigate the role of outdoor fungal spores in child asthma hospitalisations and if HRV modifies any such effect.
Methods We conducted a case-crossover study of 644 child asthma hospitalisations in Melbourne, Australia (2009–11).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A case-crossover design to examine the role of aeroallergens and respiratory viruses on childhood asthma exacerbations requiring hospitalisation: The MAPCAH study</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/mapcah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 02:26:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/mapcah/</guid>
      <description>Background: Few case-control studies of time dependent environmental exposures and respiratory outcomes have been performed. Small sample sizes pose modeling challenges for estimating interactions. In contrast, case cross-over studies are well suited where control selection and responses are low, time consuming and costly.
Objective: To demonstrate the feasibility and validity of a case crossover study of children admitted to hospital for asthma to examine interacting effects of time varying environmental exposures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasts of COPD mortality in Australia: 2006-2025</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/copdaustralia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 23:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/copdaustralia/</guid>
      <description>Background: Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) is currently the fifth leading cause of death in Australia, and there are marked differences in mortality trends between men and women. In this study, we have sought to model and forecast age related changes in COPD mortality over time for men and women separately over the period 2006–2025.
Methods: Annual COPD death rates in Australia from 1922 to 2005 for age groups (50–54, 55–59, 60–64, 65–69, 70–74, 75–79, 80–84, 85+) were used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting age-related changes in breast cancer mortality among white and black US women</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/brca-bwus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2010 01:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/brca-bwus/</guid>
      <description>The disparity in breast cancer mortality rates among white and black US women is widening, with higher mortality rates among black women. We apply functional time series models on age-specific breast cancer mortality rates for each group of women, and forecast their mortality curves using exponential smoothing state-space models with damping. The data were obtained from the Surveillance, Epidemiology and End Results (SEER) program of the US. Mortality data were obtained from the National Centre for Health Statistics (NCHS) available on the SEER*Stat database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using functional data analysis models to estimate future time trends of age-specific breast cancer mortality for the United States and England-Wales</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/brca-usew/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2010 23:14:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/brca-usew/</guid>
      <description>Background: Mortality/incidence predictions are used for planning public health resources and need to accurately reflect age-related changes through time. We present a new forecasting model to estimate future trends in age-related breast cancer mortality for the United States and England-Wales.
Material and methods: We use functional data analysis techniques to model breast cancer mortality-age relationships in the United States from 1950 to 2001 and England-Wales from 1950 to 2003, and estimate 20-year predictions using a new forecasting method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measurement of changes in antihypertensive drug utilization following primary care educational interventions</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/measurement-of-changes-in-antihypertensive-drug-utilization-following-primary-care-educational-inte/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2007 05:20:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/measurement-of-changes-in-antihypertensive-drug-utilization-following-primary-care-educational-inte/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Purpose To measure changes in drug utilization following a national general practice education program aimed at improving prescribing for hypertension.
Methods A series of nationally implemented, multifaceted educational interventions using social marketing principles focusing on prescribing for hypertension, was commenced in October 1999, and repeated in September 2001 and August 2003. The target group was all primary care prescribers in Australia and interventions were both active (voluntary) and passive. Newsletter and prescribing feedback was mailed in October 1999, September 2001 (newsletter only) and August 2003.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do levels of airborne grass pollen influence asthma hospital admissions?</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/do-levels-of-airborne-grass-pollen-influence-asthma-hospital-admissions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2007 05:27:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/do-levels-of-airborne-grass-pollen-influence-asthma-hospital-admissions/</guid>
      <description>Background: The effects of environmental factors and ambient concentrations of grass pollen on allergic asthma are yet to be established.
Objective: We sought to estimate the independent effects of grass pollen concentrations in the air over Melbourne on asthma hospital admissions, for the 1992-1993 pollen season.
Methods: Daily grass pollen concentrations were monitored over a 24 hr period at three stations in Melbourne. The outcome variable was defined as all-age asthma hospital admissions with ICD9-493 codes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting age-specific breast cancer mortality using functional data models</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/forecasting-age-specific-breast-cancer-mortality-using-functional-data-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2007 05:24:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/forecasting-age-specific-breast-cancer-mortality-using-functional-data-models/</guid>
      <description>Accurate estimates of future age-specific incidence and mortality are critical for allocation of resources to breast cancer control programs and evaluation of screening programs. The purpose of this study is to apply functional data analysis techniques to model age-specific breast cancer mortality time trends, and forecast entire age-specific mortality functions using a state-space approach. We use annual unadjusted breast cancer mortality rates in Australia, from 1921 to 2001 in five year age groups (45 to 85+).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring change in prescription drug utilization in Australia</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/measuring-change-in-prescription-drug-utilization-in-australia/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2006 04:57:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/measuring-change-in-prescription-drug-utilization-in-australia/</guid>
      <description>Purpose: The National Prescribing Service Ltd (NPS) aims to improve prescribing and use of medicines consistent with evidence-based best practice. This study compares two statistical methods used to determine whether multiple educational interventions influenced antibiotic prescribing in Australia.
Methods Monthly data (July 1996 to June 2003) were obtained from a national administrative claims database. The outcome measures were the median number of antibiotic prescriptions per 1,000 consultations for each general practitioner (GP) each month, and the mean proportion (across GPs) of each subgroup of antibiotics (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensitivity of the estimated air pollution-respiratory admissions relationship to statistical model</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/sensitivity-of-the-estimated-air-pollution-respiratory-admissions-relationship-to-statistical-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2005 03:49:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/sensitivity-of-the-estimated-air-pollution-respiratory-admissions-relationship-to-statistical-model/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Study objective: The objective of this study is to demonstrate the methodological shortcomings of currently available analytical methods for single-city time series data, one of the most commonly used ecological study designs in air pollution and respiratory disease research.
Design and Methods: We analyse single city epidemiological time series of daily Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) (ICD codes 490-492, 494, 496) and daily asthma (ICD codes 493) hospital admissions in Melbourne, Australia from July 1989 to December 1992.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data visualization for time series in environmental epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/data-visualization-for-time-series-in-environmental-epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2001 03:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/data-visualization-for-time-series-in-environmental-epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>Data visualization has become an integral part of statistical modelling. Exploratory graphical analysis allows insight into the underlying structure of observations in a data set, and graphical methods for diagnostic purposes after model fitting provide insight into the fitted model and its inadequacies. In this paper we present visualization methods for preliminary exploration of time series data and graphical diagnostic methods for modelling relationships between time series data in medicine. We will use exploratory graphical methods to better understand the relationship between a time series response and a number of potential covariates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical methodological issues in studies of air pollution and respiratory disease</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/statistical-methodological-issues-in-studies-of-air-pollution-and-respiratory-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2001 00:56:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/statistical-methodological-issues-in-studies-of-air-pollution-and-respiratory-disease/</guid>
      <description>Epidemiological studies have consistently shown short term associations between levels of air pollution and respiratory disease in countries of diverse populations, geographical locations and varying levels of air pollution and climate. The aims of this paper are: (1) to assess the sensitivity of the observed pollution effects to model specification, with particular emphasis on the inclusion of seasonally adjusted covariates; and (2) to study the effect of air pollution on respiratory disease in Melbourne, Australia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seasonal adjustment methods for the analysis of respiratory disease in environmental epidemiology</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/seasonal-adjustment-methods-for-the-analysis-of-respiratory-disease-in-environmental-epidemiology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2000 01:46:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/seasonal-adjustment-methods-for-the-analysis-of-respiratory-disease-in-environmental-epidemiology/</guid>
      <description>We study the relationship between daily hospital admissions for respiratory disease and various pollutant and climatic variables, looking particularly at the effect of seasonal adjustment on the estimated models. Often time series exhibit seasonal behaviour and adequate control for the presence of a seasonal component is essential before one attempts to model the complex pollution-health association. We show that if these factors are not adequately controlled for, spurious effects of pollutants and climate on morbidity/mortality can be induced.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>