<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chemistry on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/tags/chemistry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chemistry on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 09:24:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/tags/chemistry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Method for optimizing coating properties based on an evolutionary algorithm approach</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/emma/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 09:24:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/emma/</guid>
      <description>In industry as well as many areas of scientific research, data collected often contain a number of responses of interest for a chosen set of exploratory variables. Optimization of such multivariable multiresponse systems is a challenge well suited to genetic algorithms as global optimization tools. One such example is the optimization of coating surfaces with the required absolute and relative sensitivity for detecting analytes using devices such as sensor arrays. High-throughput synthesis and screening methods can be used to accelerate materials discovery and optimization; however, an important practical consideration for successful optimization of materials for arrays and other applications is the ability to generate adequate information from a minimum number of experiments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functionalization of microarray devices: process optimization using a multiobjective PSO and multiresponse MARS modeling</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/microarray-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2010 23:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/microarray-optimization/</guid>
      <description>An evolutionary approach for the optimization of microarray coatings produced via sol-gel chemistry is presented. The aim of the methodology is to face the challenging aspects of the problem: high dimensional variable space, constraints on the independent variables, multiple responses, expensive or time-consuming experimental trials, expected complexity of the functional relationships between independent and response variables. The proposed approach iteratively select a set of experiments by combining a multiobjective Particle Swarm Optimization (PSO) and a multiresponse Multivariate Adaptive Regression Spines (MARS) model.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>