<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Energy on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/categories/energy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Energy on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/categories/energy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IJF Tao Hong Award 2018</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-hong-nominations-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-hong-nominations-2018/</guid>
      <description>Every two years, the International Journal of Forecasting awards a prize to the best paper on energy forecasting. The prize is generously funded by Professor Tao Hong. This year, we will award the prize to a paper published in the IJF during the period 2015-2016. The prize will be US$1000 plus an engraved plaque. The award committee is Rob J Hyndman, Pierre Pinson and James Mitchell.
Nominations are invited from any reader of the IJF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IIF Tao Hong Award 2016</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/iif-hong-award-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/iif-hong-award-2016/</guid>
      <description>A generous donation from Professor Tao Hong has funded this new award for papers on energy forecasting published in the International Journal of Forecasting. The award for 2016 is for papers published within 2013&amp;ndash;2014. Next year we will award a paper published in 2015&amp;ndash;2016, and we will make the award every two years after that.
The award decision was made by a committee consisting of Professors Pierre Pinson, James Mitchell and Rob J Hyndman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IJF Tao Hong Award for the best paper in energy forecasting 2013-2014</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-hong-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 04:38:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-hong-award/</guid>
      <description>Professor Tao Hong has generously funded a new prize for the best IJF paper on energy forecasting, to be awarded every two years. The first award will be for papers published in the International Journal of Forecasting during the period 2013-2014. The prize will be US$1000 plus an engraved plaque. The award committee is Rob J Hyndman, Pierre Pinson and James Mitchell.
Nominations are invited from any reader of the IJF.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GEFCom2017: Hierarchical Probabilistic Load Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/gefcom2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2016 14:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/gefcom2017/</guid>
      <description>After the great success of the previous two energy forecasting competitions we have run (GEFCom2012 and GEFCom2014), we are holding another one, this time focused on hierarchical probabilistic load forecasting. Check out all the details over on Tao Hong&amp;rsquo;s blog.
The previous GEFComs have led to some major advances in forecasting methodology, available via IJF papers by the winning teams. I expect similar developments to arise out of this competition. Winners get to present their work in Cairns, Australia at ISEA2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The latest IJF issue with GEFCom2014 results</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-gefcom2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 01:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ijf-gefcom2014/</guid>
      <description>The latest issue of the IJF is a bumper issue with over 500 pages of forecasting insights.
The GEFCom2014 papers are included in a special section on probabilistic energy forecasting, guest edited by Tao Hong and Pierre Pinson. This is a major milestone in energy forecasting research with the focus on probabilistic forecasting and forecast evaluation done using a quantile scoring method. Only a few years ago I was having to explain to energy professionals why you couldn&amp;rsquo;t use a MAPE to evaluate a percentile forecast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 International Symposium on Energy Analytics</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/isea2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 02:56:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/isea2017/</guid>
      <description>Predictive Energy Analytics in the Big Data World Cairns, Australia, June 22-23, 2017 ISEA2017 
This will be a great conference, and it is in a great location &amp;mdash; Cairns, Australia, right by the Great Barrier Reef. Even better, if you stay on you can attend the International Symposium on Forecasting which immediately follows the International Symposium on Energy Analytics.
So block out 22-28 June 2017 on your calendars so you can enjoy a tropical paradise in one of the most beautiful parts of Australia, while attending two awesome conferences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Electricity price forecasting competition</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/electricity-price-forecasting-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 05:51:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/electricity-price-forecasting-competition/</guid>
      <description>The GEFCom competitions have been a great success in generating good research on forecasting methods for electricity demand, and in enabling a comprehensive comparative evaluation of various methods. But they have only considered price forecasting in a simplified setting. So I&amp;rsquo;m happy to see this challenge is being taken up as part of the European Energy Market Conference for 2016, to be held from 6-9 June at the University of Porto in Portugal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North American seminars: June 2015</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/northamerica2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 03:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/northamerica2015/</guid>
      <description>For the next few weeks I am travelling in North America and will be giving the following talks.
 19 June: Southern California Edison, Rosemead CA. &amp;ldquo;Probabilistic forecasting of peak electricity demand&amp;rdquo;.
 23 June: International Symposium on Forecasting, Riverside CA. &amp;ldquo;MEFM: An R package for long-term probabilistic forecasting of electricity demand&amp;rdquo;.
 25 June: Google, Mountain View, CA. &amp;ldquo;Automatic algorithms for time series forecasting&amp;rdquo;.
 26 June: Yahoo, Sunnyvale, CA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two new interviews</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/mbs-interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 12:20:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/mbs-interviews/</guid>
      <description> I was recently interviewed as part of a promotion for the Monash Business School. The interviews can be watched below if anyone is interested. The titles chosen weren&amp;rsquo;t my ideas.Predicting the future: pushing the boundaries of electricity forecasting How can you use data science to future-proof your business? </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New R package for electricity forecasting</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/mefm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 06:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/mefm/</guid>
      <description>Shu Fan and I have developed a model for electricity demand forecasting that is now widely used in Australia for long-term forecasting of peak electricity demand. It has become known as the &amp;ldquo;Monash Electricity Forecasting Model&amp;rdquo;. We have decided to release an R package that implements our model so that other people can easily use it. The package is called &amp;ldquo;MEFM&amp;rdquo; and is available on github. We will probably also put in on CRAN eventually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating quantile forecasts in R</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/quantile-forecasts-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 05:36:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/quantile-forecasts-in-r/</guid>
      <description>From today’s email:
 I have just finished reading a copy of ‘Forecasting:Principles and Practice’ and I have found the book really interesting. I have particularly enjoyed the case studies and focus on practical applications.
After finishing the book I have joined a forecasting competition to put what I’ve learnt to the test. I do have a couple of queries about the forecasting outputs required. The output required is a quantile forecast, is this the same as prediction intervals?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GEFCom 2014 energy forecasting competition is underway</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/gefcom-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 05:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/gefcom-2014/</guid>
      <description>GEFCom 2014 is the most advanced energy forecasting competition ever organized, both in terms of the data involved, and in terms of the way the forecasts will be evaluated.
So everyone interested in energy forecasting should head over to the competition webpage and start forecasting: www.gefcom.org.
This time, the competition is hosted on CrowdANALYTIX rather than Kaggle.
Highlights of GEFCom2014:
 An upgraded edition from GEFCom2012
 Four tracks: electric load, electricity price, wind power and solar power forecasting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global energy forecasting competitions</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/gefcom2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 07:12:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/gefcom2014/</guid>
      <description>The 2012 GEFcom competition was a great success with several new innovative forecasting methods introduced. These have been published in the IJF as follows: Hong, Pinson and Fan. Global Energy Forecasting Competition 2012
 Charleton and Singleton. A refined parametric model for short term load forecasting
 Lloyd. GEFCom2012 hierarchical load forecasting: Gradient boosting machines and Gaussian processes
 Nedelec, Cugliari and Goude: GEFCom2012: Electric load forecasting and backcasting with semi-parametric models</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic Energy Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/probabilistic-energy-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 04:07:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/probabilistic-energy-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>The International Journal of Forecasting is calling for papers on probabilistic energy forecasting. Here are the details (taken from Tao Hong&amp;rsquo;s blog).In today&amp;rsquo;s competitive and dynamic environment, more and more decision making processes in the energy industry are relying on probabilistic forecasts. The applications of probabilistic energy forecasts spread across planning and operations of the entire energy value chain. We are seeking papers from researchers working on the areas of probabilistic energy forecasting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>