<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Welfare on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/categories/welfare/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Welfare on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2010 21:36:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/categories/welfare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Do something else</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/do-something-else/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2010 21:36:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/do-something-else/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written about taking a break from research before. Along the same lines, there is some good advice on &amp;ldquo;The Importance of Making Time for &amp;ldquo;Real World&amp;rdquo; Activities in Grad School&amp;rdquo; over at the excellent AMS Graduate Student Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take a break</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/take-a-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2009 13:06:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/take-a-break/</guid>
      <description>Occasionally, the best research is done in long periods of concentrated effort. Allegedly, Isaac Newton used to sometimes write for eight hours standing up without a break.
At other times, taking a break helps the research process. Think of Archimedes and his Eureka moment. Many of my best ideas come while walking, or taking a shower. In fact, I once suggested to my head of department that we should have showers installed in every office as it would increase the quality of our research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seek help when it&#39;s needed</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/seek-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2009 02:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/seek-help/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve had a research student who did not think about giving up at some point. It was part through my second year when I felt like giving up. I felt I was not going to be able to finish my thesis, and that I would be better off throwing in the towel and doing something else. Fortunately, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of anything better to do, plus I hate giving up on anything, so I persevered and it turned out ok.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>