<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Remote Sensing on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/tags/remote-sensing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Remote Sensing on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 08:05:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/tags/remote-sensing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Phenological change detection while accounting for abrupt and gradual trends in satellite image time series</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/bfast2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2010 08:05:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/bfast2/</guid>
      <description>A challenge in phenology studies is understanding what constitutes significant phenological change amidst background variation (e.g. noise) and ecosystem disturbances (e.g. fires). The majority of phenological studies have focussed on extracting critical points in the seasonal growth cycle (e.g. Start-of-spring), without exploiting the full temporal detail. Moreover, the high degree of phenological variability between years demonstrates the necessity of distinguishing long term phenological change from temporal variability. Here, we evaluate the phenological change detection ability of a method for detecting Breaks For Additive Seasonal and Trend (BFAST).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detecting trend and seasonal changes in satellite image time series</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/bfast1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2010 23:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/bfast1/</guid>
      <description>A wealth of remotely sensed time series covering large areas is now available to the earth science community. Change detection methods are often not capable of detecting land cover changes within time series that are heavily influenced by seasonal climatic variations. Detecting change within the trend and seasonal components of time series enables the detection of different types of changes. Changes occurring in the trend component indicate disturbances (e.g., insect attack), while changes occurring in the seasonal component indicate phenological changes (e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>