<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Density Estimation on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/tags/density-estimation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Density Estimation on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/tags/density-estimation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Probabilistic Forecasting of Electricity Demand with Smart Meter Data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/hpf-electricity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/hpf-electricity/</guid>
      <description>Electricity smart meters record consumption, on a near real-time basis, at the level of individual commercial and residential properties. From this, a hierarchy can be constructed consisting of time series of demand at the smart meter level, and at various levels of aggregation, such as substations, cities and regions. Forecasts are needed at each level to support the efficient and reliable management of consumption. A limitation of previous research in this area is that it considered only deterministic prediction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coherent Probabilistic Forecasts for Hierarchical Time Series</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/probhts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/probhts/</guid>
      <description>Many applications require forecasts for a hierarchy comprising a set of time series along with aggregates of subsets of these series. Although forecasts can be produced independently for each series in the hierarchy, typically this does not lead to coherent forecasts — the property that forecasts add up appropriately across the hierarchy. State-of-the-art hierarchical forecasting methods usually reconcile these independently generated forecasts to satisfy the aggregation constraints. A fundamental limitation of prior research is that it has looked only at the problem of forecasting the mean of each time series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic time series forecasting with boosted additive models: an application to smart meter data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/kdd2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2015 11:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/kdd2015/</guid>
      <description>A large body of the forecasting literature so far has been focused on forecasting the conditional mean of future observations. However, there is an increasing need for generating the entire conditional distribution of future observations in order to effectively quantify the uncertainty in time series data. We present two different methods for probabilistic time series forecasting that allow the inclusion of a possibly large set of exogenous variables. One method is based on forecasting both the conditional mean and variance of the future distribution using a traditional regression approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved interval estimation of long run response from a dynamic linear model: a highest density region approach</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/dlm-hdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 00:53:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/dlm-hdr/</guid>
      <description>This paper proposes a new method of interval estimation for the long run response (or elasticity) parameter from a general linear dynamic model. We employ the bias-corrected bootstrap, in which small sample biases associated with the parameter estimators are adjusted in two stages of the bootstrap. As a means of bias-correction, we use alternative analytic and bootstrap methods. To take atypical properties of the long run elasticity estimator into account, the highest density region (HDR) method is adopted for the construction of confidence intervals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Density forecasting for long-term peak electricity demand</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/peak-electricity-demand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 23:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/peak-electricity-demand/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Long-term electricity demand forecasting plays an important role in planning for future generation facilities and transmission augmentation. In a long term context, planners must adopt a probabilistic view of potential peak demand levels, therefore density forecasts (providing estimates of the full probability distributions of the possible future values of the demand) are more helpful than point forecasts, and are necessary for utilities to evaluate and hedge the financial risk accrued by demand variability and forecasting uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projection pursuit estimator for multivariate conditional densities</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/projection-pursuit-estimator-for-multivariate-conditional-densities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2006 02:42:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/projection-pursuit-estimator-for-multivariate-conditional-densities/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Bayesian approach to bandwidth selection for multivariate kernel density estimation</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/bandwidth-selection-for-multivariate-kernel-density-estimation-using-mcmc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2006 06:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/bandwidth-selection-for-multivariate-kernel-density-estimation-using-mcmc/</guid>
      <description>Kernel density estimation for multivariate data is an important technique that has a wide range of applications. However, it has received significantly less attention than its univariate counterpart. The lower level of interest in multivariate kernel density estimation is mainly due to the increased difficulty in deriving an optimal data-driven bandwidth as the dimension of the data increases. We provide Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) algorithms for estimating optimal bandwidth matrices for multivariate kernel density estimation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonparametric estimation and symmetry tests for conditional density functions</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/nonparametric-estimation-and-symmetry-tests-for-conditional-density-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2002 03:23:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/nonparametric-estimation-and-symmetry-tests-for-conditional-density-functions/</guid>
      <description>We suggest two new methods for conditional density estimation. The first is based on locally fitting a log-linear model, and is in the spirit of recent work on locally parametric techniques in density estimation. The second method is a constrained local polynomial estimator. Both methods always produce non-negative estimators. We propose an algorithm suitable for selecting the two bandwidths for either estimator. We also develop a new bootstrap test for the symmetry of conditional density functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bandwidth selection for kernel conditional density estimation</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/bandwidth-selection-for-kernel-conditional-density-estimation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2001 03:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/bandwidth-selection-for-kernel-conditional-density-estimation/</guid>
      <description>We consider bandwidth selection for the kernel estimator of conditional density with one explanatory variable. Several bandwidth selection methods are derived ranging from fast rules-of-thumb which assume the underlying densities are known to relatively slow procedures which use the bootstrap. The methods are compared and a practical bandwidth selection strategy which combines the methods is proposed. The methods are compared using two simulation studies and a real data set.
Keywords: density estimation; kernel smoothing; conditioning; bandwidth selection.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>