<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal forecast reconciliation for hierarchical and grouped time series through trace minimization</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/mint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/mint/</guid>
      <description>Large collections of time series often have aggregation constraints due to product or geographical groupings. The forecasts for the most disaggregated series are usually required to add-up exactly to the forecasts of the aggregated series, a constraint we refer to as &amp;ldquo;coherence&amp;rdquo;. Forecast reconciliation is the process of adjusting forecasts to make them coherent. The reconciliation algorithm proposed by Hyndman et al. (2011) is based on a generalized least squares estimator that requires an estimate of the covariance matrix of the coherency errors (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic outlier detection and visualization of smart metre data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/nzsa2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/nzsa2017/</guid>
      <description>Talk given at meeting of New Zealand Statistical Association and International Association for Statistical Computing (11-14 December 2017), Auckland, New Zealand.
It is always a good idea to plot your data before fitting any models, making any predictions, or drawing any conclusions. But how do you actually plot data on thousands of smart meters, each comprising thousands of observations over time? We cannot simply produce time plots of the demand recorded at each meter, due to the sheer volume of data involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal forecast reconcilation</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/unsw2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/unsw2017/</guid>
      <description>Talk given at UNSW
Abstract
Time series can often be naturally disaggregated in a hierarchical or grouped structure. For example, a manufacturing company can disaggregate total demand for their products by country of sale, retail outlet, product type, package size, and so on. As a result, there can be millions of individual time series to forecast at the most disaggregated level, plus additional series to forecast at higher levels of aggregation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic outlier detection and visualization of smart metre data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/isea2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/isea2017/</guid>
      <description>Talk to be given at International Symposium on Energy Analytics (22-23 June 2017), Cairns, Australia.
Standard time series analysis and visualization tools fail on smart metre data due to the sheer volume of available data (both in the time dimension and due to the large numbers of smart metres providing data). In addition, smart metre data is often messy, with missing observations, periods where some metres are offline, periods of relatively constant low level energy usage, occasional days of unusually high demand, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconciling forecasts: the hts and thief packages</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/erum2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 12:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/erum2016/</guid>
      <description>eRum2016, Poznań, Poland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting large collections of related time series</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/augsburg2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/augsburg2016/</guid>
      <description>Keynote talk given at the German Statistical Week, Augsburg.
Abstract
Time series can often be naturally disaggregated in a hierarchical or grouped structure. For example, a manufacturing company can disaggregate total demand for their products by country of sale, retail outlet, product type, package size, and so on. As a result, there can be millions of individual time series to forecast at the most disaggregated level, plus additional series to forecast at higher levels of aggregation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic foRecasting using R</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/automatic-forecasting-using-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 05:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/automatic-forecasting-using-r/</guid>
      <description>Melbourne Data Science Initiative</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting big time series data using R</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/china2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2015 23:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/china2015/</guid>
      <description>Keynote address given at the Chinese R conference held in Nanchang, Jianxi province. 24-25 October 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning bootcamp</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/machine-learning-bootcamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 02:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/machine-learning-bootcamp/</guid>
      <description>A talk on time series forecasting for the Monash University Machine Learning Bootcamp.
Demo R code</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MEFM: An R package for long-term probabilistic forecasting of electricity demand</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/isf2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 23:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/isf2015/</guid>
      <description>International Symposium on Forecasting Riverside, California
I will describe and demonstrate a new open-source R package that implements the Monash Electricity Forecasting Model, a semi-parametric probabilistic approach to forecasting long-term electricity demand. The underlying model proposed in Hyndman and Fan (2010) is now widely used in practice, particularly in Australia. The model has undergone many improvements and developments since it was first proposed, and these have been incorporated in this R implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic forecasting of peak electricity demand</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/sce2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 23:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/sce2015/</guid>
      <description>Southern California Edison Rosemead, California
Electricity demand forecasting plays an important role in short-term load allocation and long-term planning for future generation facilities and transmission augmentation. It is a challenging problem because of the different uncertainties including underlying population growth, changing technology, economic conditions, prevailing weather conditions (and the timing of those conditions), as well as the general randomness inherent in individual usage. It is also subject to some known calendar effects due to the time of day, day of week, time of year, and public holidays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Large-scale unusual time series detection</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/icdm2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 02:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/icdm2015/</guid>
      <description>It is becoming increasingly common for organizations to collect very large amounts of data over time, and to need to detect unusual or anomalous time series. For example, Yahoo has banks of mail servers that are monitored over time. Many measurements on server performance are collected every hour for each of thousands of servers. We wish to identify servers that are behaving unusually.
We compute a vector of features on each time series, measuring characteristics of the series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization of big time series data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/big-time-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 03:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/big-time-series/</guid>
      <description>Talk given to a joint meeting of the Statistical Society of Australia (Victorian branch) and the Melbourne Data Science Meetup Group.It is becoming increasingly common for organizations to collect very large amounts of data over time. Data visualization is essential for exploring and understanding structures and patterns, and to identify unusual observations. However, the sheer quantity of data available challenges current time series visualisation methods.
For example, Yahoo has banks of mail servers that are monitored over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic forecasting of long-term peak electricity demand</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/memsi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 07:29:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/memsi/</guid>
      <description>Electricity demand forecasting plays an important role in long-term planning for future generation facilities and transmission augmentation. It is a challenging problem because of the different uncertainties including underlying population growth, changing technology, economic conditions, prevailing weather conditions (and the timing of those conditions), as well as the general randomness inherent in individual usage. It is also subject to some known calendar effects due to the time of day, day of week, time of year, and public holidays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization and forecasting of big time series data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/big-time-series-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 01:11:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/big-time-series-data/</guid>
      <description>Talk given at the ACEMS Big data workshop, QUT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing and forecasting big time series data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/visualizing-and-forecasting-big-time-series-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 15:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/visualizing-and-forecasting-big-time-series-data/</guid>
      <description>Institute of Statistical Science, Academia Sinica 時　間 2015/01/12 11:00 星期一 地　點 中研院-統計所 2F 交誼廳 備　註 茶 會：上午10：40統計所二樓交誼廳
Time series can often be naturally disaggregated in a hierarchical or grouped structure. For example, a manufacturing company can disaggregate total demand for their products by country of sale, retail outlet, product type, package size, and so on. As a result, there can be millions of individual time series to forecast at the most disaggregated level, plus additional series to forecast at higher levels of aggregation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R tools for hierarchical time series</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/hts-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 20:07:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/hts-2/</guid>
      <description>Talk given at EURO/INFORMS, Rome, 1 July 2013
And at UseR! 2013, Albacete, Spain, 10 July 2013.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SimpleR: tips, tricks and tools</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/simpler/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 07:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/simpler/</guid>
      <description>Melbourne R Users&amp;rsquo; Group
Deloitte, Level 11, 550 Bourke Street, Melbourne
Examples</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting time series using R</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/melbournerug/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 04:37:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/melbournerug/</guid>
      <description>Melbourne R Users&amp;rsquo; Group Thursday, October 27, 2011, 6:00 PM Deloitte, Level 11 (Culture Room), 550 Bourke Street, Melbourne
I will look at the various facilities for time series forecasting available in R, concentrating on the forecast package. This package implements several automatic methods for forecasting time series including forecasts from ARIMA models, ARFIMA models and exponential smoothing models. I will also look more generally at how to go about forecasting non-seasonal data, seasonal data, seasonal data with high frequency, and seasonal data with multiple frequencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving a useR! talk</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/usertalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 03:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/usertalk/</guid>
      <description>Giving a useR! talk at the international R user conference is a balancing act in which you have to try to impart some new ideas, provide sufficient background and keep the audience interested, all in a very short period of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free open-source forecasting using R</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/r-foresight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Nov 2010 12:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/r-foresight/</guid>
      <description>Summary  R is a free open source statistical computing environment which can be used for forecasting. It is available at www.r-project.org. Advantages of R include its (zero) price, the large number of user-contributed packages, its production-quality graphics and the possibility of extending it by linking fast compiled C/C++/Fortran code. Disadvantages of R include a steep learning curve and a certain slowness when dealing with truly massive amounts of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic time series forecasting: the forecast package for R</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/automatic-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2008 05:29:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/automatic-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>Automatic forecasts of large numbers of univariate time series are often needed in business and other contexts. We describe two automatic forecasting algorithms that have been implemented in the forecast package for R. The first is based on innovation state space models that underly exponential smoothing methods. The second is based on ARIMA models. The algorithms are applicable to both seasonal and non-seasonal data, and are compared and illustrated using four real time series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building R packages for Windows</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/building-r-packages-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2008 04:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/building-r-packages-for-windows/</guid>
      <description> R workshop. Melbourne, 29 June 2008. There was an R workshop on 28-29 June, just before the Australian Statistical Conference. I put in an appearance on the second day.
Building R packages for Windows
 handout slides  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time series and forecasting in R</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/time-series-and-forecasting-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2008 04:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/time-series-and-forecasting-in-r/</guid>
      <description> R workshop. Melbourne, 29 June 2008. There was an R workshop on 28-29 June, just before the Australian Statistical Conference. I put in an appearance on the second day.
Time series and forecasting in R
 handout slides  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book Review of &#34;Data Analysis and Graphics Using R: An Example-based Approach&#34; (Maindonald and Braun, 2003)</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/maindonald-and-braun-data-analysis-and-graphics-using-r-an-example-based-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2005 00:42:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/maindonald-and-braun-data-analysis-and-graphics-using-r-an-example-based-approach/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using R to Teach Econometrics</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/using-r-to-teach-econometrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2002 03:25:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/using-r-to-teach-econometrics/</guid>
      <description>R, an open-source programming environment for data analysis and graphics, has in only a decade grown to become a de-facto standard for statistical analysis against which many popular commercial programs may be measured. The use of R for the teaching of econometric methods is appealing. It provides cutting-edge statistical methods which are, by R&amp;rsquo;s open-source nature, available immediately. The software is stable, available at no cost, and exists for a number of platforms, including various flavors of Unix and Linux, Windows (9x/NT/2000), and the MacOS.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>