<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/categories/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 11:48:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/categories/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s your Hall number?</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/whats-your-hall-number/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 11:48:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/whats-your-hall-number/</guid>
      <description>Today I attended the funeral of Peter Hall, one of the finest mathematical statisticians ever to walk the earth and easily the best from Australia. One of the most remarkable things about Peter was his astonishing productivity, with over 600 papers. As I sat in the audience I realised that many of the people there were probably coauthors of papers with Peter, and I wondered how many statisticians in the world would have been his coauthors or second-degree co-authors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RStudio just keeps getting better</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/rstudio-just-keeps-getting-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 05:36:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/rstudio-just-keeps-getting-better/</guid>
      <description>RStudio has been a life-changer for the way I work, and for how I teach data analysis. I still have a couple of minor frustrations with it, but they are slowly disappearing as RStudio adds features.
I use dual monitors and I like to code on one monitor and have the console and plots on the other monitor. Otherwise I see too little context, and long lines get wrapped making the code harder to read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful tutorials</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/useful-tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 03:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/useful-tutorials/</guid>
      <description>There are some tools that I use regularly, and I would like my research students and post-docs to learn them too. Here are some great online tutorials that might help.
 ggplot tutorial from Winston Chang
 Writing an R package from Karl Broman
 Rmarkdown from RStudio
 Shiny from RStudio
 git/github guide from Karl Broman
 minimal make tutorial from Karl Broman
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping up to date with my research papers</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/new-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 05:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/new-papers/</guid>
      <description>Many people ask me to let them know when I write a new research paper. I can&amp;rsquo;t do that as there are too many people involved, and it is not scalable.
The solution is simple. Take your pick from the following options. Each is automatic and will let you know whenever I produce a new paper.
 Subscribe to the rss feed on my website using feedly or some other rss reader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paperpile makes me more productive</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/paperpile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 02:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/paperpile/</guid>
      <description>One of the first things I tell my new research students is to use a reference management system to help them keep track of the papers they read, and to assist in creating bib files for their bibliography. Most of them use Mendeley, one or two use Zotero. Both do a good job and both are free.
I use neither. I did use Mendeley for several years, but it became slower and slower to sync as my reference collection grew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating tables in LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/generating-tables-in-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 23:23:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/generating-tables-in-latex/</guid>
      <description>Typing tables in LaTeX can get messy, but there are some good tools to simplify the process. One I discovered this week is tablesgenerator.com, a web-based tool for generating LaTeX tables. It also allows the table to saved in other formats including HTML and Markdown. The interface is simple, but it does most things. For complicated tables, some additional formatting may be necessary.
Similar functionality is available via plugins in Excel, OpenOffice and Libreoffice &amp;mdash; useful if the data for the table is already stored in a spreadsheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online collaborative writing</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/online-collaborative-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2014 02:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/online-collaborative-writing/</guid>
      <description>Everyone who has written a paper with another author will know it can be tricky making sure you don&amp;rsquo;t end up with two versions that need to be merged. The good news is that the days of sending updated drafts by email backwards and forwards is finally over (having lasted all of 25 years &amp;ndash; I can barely imagine writing papers before email).LaTeX solutions There has been a lot of activity in the development of online LaTeX tools over the last few years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing research ideas</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/managing-research-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 13:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/managing-research-ideas/</guid>
      <description>I received this email today:
 Dear Professor Hyndman, I was wondering if you could maybe give me some advice on how to organize your research process. I am able to search the literature on a certain topic and identify where there is a question to work with. My main difficult is to organize my paper annotations in order to help me to guide my research process, i.e, how to manage the information gathered in those papers to compose and structure a document which can represent the research developed so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Makefiles for R/LaTeX projects</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/makefiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 02:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/makefiles/</guid>
      <description>Updated: 21 November 2012
Make is a marvellous tool used by programmers to build software, but it can be used for much more than that. I use make whenever I have a large project involving R files and LaTeX files, which means I use it for almost all of the papers I write, and almost of the consulting reports I produce.If you are using a Mac or Linux, you will already have make installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX loops</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex-loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2012 01:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex-loops/</guid>
      <description>Today I was writing a report which included 20 figures, with the names demandplot1.pdf, demandplot2.pdf, &amp;hellip;, demandplot20.pdf, and all with similar captions. Clearly a loop was required. After all, LaTeX is a programming language, so we should be able to take advantage of its capabilities.I found the forloop package which handled the problem perfectly. My first attempt looked like this:
\newcommand{\demandplot}[1]{\begin{figure}\centering \includegraphics[width=\textwidth]{./figs/demandplot#1.pdf} \caption{Hourly demand (GW) for zone #1.} \end{figure}} \newcounter{loop} \forloop{loop}{1}{\value{loop}&amp;lt;21}{\demandplot{\arabic{loop}}}  The magic happens in the last line providing a loop from 1 to 20, generating the commands \demandplot{1}, \demandplot{2}, &amp;hellip;, \demandplot{20}.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogs about research</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/blogs-about-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 02:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/blogs-about-research/</guid>
      <description>If you find this blog helpful (or even if you don&amp;rsquo;t but you&amp;rsquo;re interested in blogs on research issues and tools), there are a few other blogs about doing research that you might find useful. Here are a few that I read.
 Patter &amp;ndash; Pat Thomson.
 The Thesis Whisperer &amp;ndash; Inger Mewburn.
 The Research Whisperer &amp;ndash; several RMIT researchers.
 the (research) supervisor&amp;rsquo;s friend &amp;ndash; Geof Hill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog aggregators</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/blog-aggregators/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2012 10:34:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/blog-aggregators/</guid>
      <description>A very useful way of keeping up with blogs in a particular area is to subscribe to a blog aggregator. These will syndicate posts from a large number of blogs and provide links back to the original sources. So you only need to subscribe once to get all the good stuff in that area.
There are now several blog aggregators available that might be of interest to readers here. And this blog is now syndicated on several other sites including those listed below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking help</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/seeking-help/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2012 13:23:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/seeking-help/</guid>
      <description>Every day I receive emails, or comments on this blog, asking for help with R, forecasting, LaTeX, possible research topics, how to install software, or some other thing I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to know something about. Unfortunately, I cannot provide a one-man help service to the rest of the world. I used to reply to all the requests explaining where to go for help, but I stopped replying a while ago as it took too much time to do even that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Following authors on Google Scholar</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/googlescholar2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 01:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/googlescholar2/</guid>
      <description>A great new feature has been added to Google Scholar Citations. For those authors who have set up a citations page, it is now possible to get email alerts for any new articles they publish, or for any new citations of their articles. So you can track citations to your own work this way, and stay up-to-date with key authors in your field.
Setting up a Google Citations page is super-easy and was already worth doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizing travel</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2011 13:12:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/travel/</guid>
      <description>Whether travelling to a seminar or conference, or just having a holiday, using a travel organizer can make the process simpler and easier. A good travel organizer keeps all your travel details (flights, hotels, car rentals, meetings, weather forecasts, etc.) organized and synced to whatever devices you use (two computers, an iPad and an iPhone in my case).I am aware of four travel organizers that do this: TripIt, TripCase, WorldMate and Wipolo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Researcher portals</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/portals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2011 04:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/portals/</guid>
      <description>A researcher portal is a website that attempts to list all the publications of a given researcher. Some portals also allow sharing papers, interacting with other researchers, calculating citation statistics, etc. Every researcher wants their work read and cited, so these websites can be useful tools for getting your work noticed. They can also function as a de facto home page if you don&amp;rsquo;t already have a personal website. Conversely, they can be a good way to find new work by researchers in your field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In praise of Dropbox</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/dropbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 01:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/dropbox/</guid>
      <description>Every couple of years, a new technology has a big impact on how I work. Gmail was one. My iPhone was another. And I rank Dropbox in the same category.
I get three huge benefits in using Dropbox:
 All my files are backed up online. The house can burn down and I know I can still get my files. Also, if I&amp;rsquo;m away from my desktop or laptop, I can still access my files on my iPhone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hamming on research</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/hamming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2010 09:14:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/hamming/</guid>
      <description>Richard Hamming was an excellent mathematician who worked at the interface of mathematics and computer science. In 1986 he gave a wonderful talk entitled You and Your Research. Derek Smith on the AMS Graduate Student blog reminded me of it today. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t read it previously, stop work immediately and read it now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do something else</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/do-something-else/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2010 21:36:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/do-something-else/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve written about taking a break from research before. Along the same lines, there is some good advice on &amp;ldquo;The Importance of Making Time for &amp;ldquo;Real World&amp;rdquo; Activities in Grad School&amp;rdquo; over at the excellent AMS Graduate Student Blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That syncing feeling</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/syncing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2010 06:18:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/syncing/</guid>
      <description>Like many people, I use more than one computer and I like to have all my files, bookmarks and other settings synchronized across my computers. Fortunately, that is getting easier as more tools are made available for keeping computers synchronized. So I thought it might be timely to review how to keep computers &amp;ldquo;synced&amp;rdquo;.
 Files: By far the best service is Dropbox. All files within the &amp;ldquo;My Dropbox&amp;rdquo; directory are backed up online and synchronized with any other computer associated with your account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to fail a PhD</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/phdfail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2010 13:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/phdfail/</guid>
      <description>I read an interesting post today by Matt Might on &amp;ldquo;10 reasons PhD students fail&amp;rdquo;, and I thought it might be helpful to reflect on some of the barriers to PhD completion that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen. Matt&amp;rsquo;s ideas are not all relevant to Australian PhDs, so I have come up with my own list below. Here are the seven steps to failure.
1. Wait for your supervisor to tell you what to do A good supervisor will not tell you what to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scheduling meetings</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/scheduling-meetings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2010 13:10:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/scheduling-meetings/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t go to many meetings as I find they are largely a waste of time. In fact, I have the following poster on my office wall to remind everyone who walks in not to ask me to attend a meeting!
But I&amp;rsquo;m now a chief investigator of an NHMRC grant and I have to meet with other members of the team from time to time. We&amp;rsquo;ve started using Doodle to schedule our meetings, and it is so good I thought I should share it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 7 secrets of highly successful PhD students</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/7secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 07:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/7secrets/</guid>
      <description>It seems everyone has 7 secrets to success, and now someone has hopped on the 7-secrets bandwagon with something for PhD students. Thinkwell is an Australian company offering a seminar and associated work book on &amp;ldquo;The 7 secrets of highly successful PhD students&amp;rdquo;. I bought the book out of curiosity, but &amp;ldquo;book&amp;rdquo; is a gross exaggeration &amp;ndash; only eleven pages of fairly simplistic advice. I hope the seminar has more substance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workflow in R</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/workflow-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2009 03:21:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/workflow-in-r/</guid>
      <description>This came up recently on StackOverflow. One of the answers was particularly helpful and I thought it might be worth mentioning here. The idea presented there is to break the code into four files, all stored in your project directory. These four files are to be processed in the following order.
 load.R This file includes all code associated with loading the data. Usually, it will be a short file reading in data from files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take a break</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/take-a-break/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2009 13:06:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/take-a-break/</guid>
      <description>Occasionally, the best research is done in long periods of concentrated effort. Allegedly, Isaac Newton used to sometimes write for eight hours standing up without a break.
At other times, taking a break helps the research process. Think of Archimedes and his Eureka moment. Many of my best ideas come while walking, or taking a shower. In fact, I once suggested to my head of department that we should have showers installed in every office as it would increase the quality of our research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backing up</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/backing-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2009 03:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/backing-up/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I deleted the only copy of my honours thesis, one week before it was due to be handed in, I&amp;rsquo;ve been obsessive about backups, often to the amusement of my family and colleagues. But every time one of them loses a file or has a hard-disk fail, the smiles fade and they ask for advice.
I&amp;rsquo;ve used many systems over the years, each one a little better than the last.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time management</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/time-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2008 08:04:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/time-management/</guid>
      <description>I am frequently asked how I manage my time, and how I manage to get so much done. I don&amp;rsquo;t know that my approach is right for everyone, but in case it helps here are some comments on how I work.
One of the main traps that people fall into is to do things that are urgent, but not necessarily important. They react to the urgency of deadlines, and demands of colleagues, and end up spending a lot of time on things that don&amp;rsquo;t really matter much.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>