<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tourism on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/tags/tourism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tourism on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/tags/tourism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal forecast reconciliation for hierarchical and grouped time series through trace minimization</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/mint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/mint/</guid>
      <description>Large collections of time series often have aggregation constraints due to product or geographical groupings. The forecasts for the most disaggregated series are usually required to add-up exactly to the forecasts of the aggregated series, a constraint we refer to as &amp;ldquo;coherence&amp;rdquo;. Forecast reconciliation is the process of adjusting forecasts to make them coherent. The reconciliation algorithm proposed by Hyndman et al. (2011) is based on a generalized least squares estimator that requires an estimate of the covariance matrix of the coherency errors (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization and forecasting of big time series data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/big-time-series-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 01:11:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/big-time-series-data/</guid>
      <description>Talk given at the ACEMS Big data workshop, QUT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing and forecasting big time series data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/visualizing-and-forecasting-big-time-series-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 15:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/visualizing-and-forecasting-big-time-series-data/</guid>
      <description>Institute of Statistical Science, Academia Sinica 時　間 2015/01/12 11:00 星期一 地　點 中研院-統計所 2F 交誼廳 備　註 茶 會：上午10：40統計所二樓交誼廳
Time series can often be naturally disaggregated in a hierarchical or grouped structure. For example, a manufacturing company can disaggregate total demand for their products by country of sale, retail outlet, product type, package size, and so on. As a result, there can be millions of individual time series to forecast at the most disaggregated level, plus additional series to forecast at higher levels of aggregation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tourism forecasting: an introduction</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/tourism-forecasting-an-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2011 09:35:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/tourism-forecasting-an-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to the special issue on Tourism Forecasting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The tourism forecasting competition</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/the-tourism-forecasting-competition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 22:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/the-tourism-forecasting-competition/</guid>
      <description>We evaluate the performance of various methods for forecasting tourism demand. The data used include 366 monthly series, 427 quarterly series and 518 yearly series, all supplied to us by tourism bodies or by academics from previous tourism forecasting studies. The forecasting methods implemented in the competition are univariate and multivariate time series approaches, and econometric models. This forecasting competition differs from previous competitions in several ways: (i) we concentrate only on tourism demand data; (ii) we include approaches with explanatory variables; (iii) we evaluate the forecast interval coverage as well as point forecast accuracy; (iv) we observe the effect of temporal aggregation on forecasting accuracy; and (v) we consider the mean absolute scaled error as an alternative forecasting accuracy measure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical forecasts for Australian domestic tourism</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/hierarchical-tourism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2009 23:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/hierarchical-tourism/</guid>
      <description>In this paper we explore the hierarchical nature of tourism demand time series and produce short-term forecasts for Australian domestic tourism. The data and forecasts are organized in a hierarchy based on disaggregating the data for different geographical regions and for different purposes of travel. We consider five approaches to hierarchical forecasting: two variations of the top-down approach, the bottom-up method, a newly proposed top-down approach where top-level forecasts are disaggregated according to forecasted proportions of lower level series, and a recently proposed optimal combination approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling and forecasting Australian domestic tourism</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/modelling-and-forecasting-australian-domestic-tourism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2008 06:25:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/modelling-and-forecasting-australian-domestic-tourism/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we model and forecast Australian domestic tourism demand. We use a regression framework to estimate important economic relationships for domestic tourism demand. We also identify the impact of world events such as the 2000 Sydney Olympics and the 2002 Bali bombings on Australian domestic tourism. To explore the time series nature of the data, we use innovation state space models to forecast the domestic tourism demand. Combining these two frameworks, we build innovation state space models with exogenous variables.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>