<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Seminars on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/categories/seminars/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Seminars on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 22:35:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/categories/seminars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow-up forecasting forum in Eindhoven</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/eindhoven2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 22:35:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/eindhoven2/</guid>
      <description>Last October I gave a 3-day masterclass on &amp;ldquo;Forecasting with R&amp;rdquo; in Eindhoven, Netherlands. There is a follow-up event planned for Tuesday 18 April 2017. It is particularly designed for people who attended the 3-day class, but if anyone else wants to attend they would be welcome.
Please register here if you want to attend.The preliminary schedule is as follows.
10.00 -- 11.00  New developments in forecasting using R   forecast v8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WOMBAT MeDaScIn 2017</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/wombat-medascin-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2017 06:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/wombat-medascin-2017/</guid>
      <description>Last year we had WOMBAT (Workshop Organized by the Monash Business Analytics Team) at the zoo, and MeDaScIn (Melbourne Data Science Initiative) in the city.
This year we are combining forces to hold WOMBAT MeDaScIn 2017.
There will be four days of tutorials (Monday 29 May to Thursday 1 June), and the main conference on Friday 2 June. We have an impressive range of local and international presenters including Yihui Xie (author of Rmarkdown, Knitr, Bookdown, Blogdown and more), Di Cook (data visualization guru), Stephanie Kovalchik (Data Scientist at Tennis Australia), Amy Shi-Nash (Head of Data Science at Commonwealth Bank of Australia), Graham Williams (Director of Data Science at Microsoft) and many more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hadley Wickham Master R Developer course coming to Melbourne</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/hadley-course-dec-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 19:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/hadley-course-dec-2016/</guid>
      <description>Hadley Wickham&amp;rsquo;s popular R developer course is coming to Melbourne on 12-13 December 2016. Bookings can be made via Eventbrite.Hadley, of course, is the developer of the wonderful tidyverse set of R packages including ggplot2, dplyr, tidyr, readr, purrr, tibble, and many more. He is the author of several books including the new &amp;ldquo;R for Data Science&amp;rdquo;, he is the chief scientist at RStudio, and a fellow cocktail enthusiast.
From the course blurb:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for forecasting workshops in Cairns, Australia</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/cairns-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 15:25:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/cairns-workshops/</guid>
      <description>The 37th annual International Symposium on Forecasting will be held in Cairns, Australia, from 25-28 June 2017. We plan to hold some workshops on Sunday 25 June, before the main conference.We are currently calling for workshop proposals. Proposals can be for a half-day or full-day workshop. As usual, there will be a Practitioner Track at the conference which generally leads to excellent attendance at the workshops.
Though June sounds far away, planning for the conference is well underway!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eindhoven seminar on time series visualization</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/eindhoven-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 08:34:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/eindhoven-seminar/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently in the Netherlands for a few weeks, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be giving a seminar at the Data Science Centre in Eindhoven next Wednesday afternoon on &amp;ldquo;Visualization of big time series data&amp;rdquo;. Details follow.Date: 5 October 2016 Time: 12.30-13.30 Venue: Filmhuis, De Zwarte Doos, 2 Den Dolech, Eindhoven
Registration is required but free. Please book here.
Abstract:
It is becoming increasingly common for organizations to collect very large amounts of data over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Forecasting with R&#34; short course in Eindhoven</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/eindhoven-course/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 00:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/eindhoven-course/</guid>
      <description>I will be giving my 3-day short-course/workshop on &amp;ldquo;Forecasting with R&amp;rdquo; in Eindhoven (Netherlands) from 19-21 October.
Details at https://www.win.tue.nl/~adriemel/shortcourse.html
Register here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melbourne Data Science Initiative 2016</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/medascin2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 03:51:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/medascin2016/</guid>
      <description>In just over three weeks, the inaugural MeDaScIn event will take place. This is an initiative to grow the talent pool of local data scientists and to promote Melbourne as a world city of excellence in Data Science.
The main event takes place on Friday 6th May, with lots of interesting sounding titles and speakers from business and government. I&amp;rsquo;m the only academic speaker on the program, giving the closing talk on &amp;ldquo;Automatic FoRecasting&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making data analysis easier: Hadley Wickham at WOMBAT2016</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/wombat2016-hadley/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 22:25:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/wombat2016-hadley/</guid>
      <description>Slides for Hadley&amp;rsquo;s talk
The slides for all the other talks from the workshop are also now online at wombat2016.org</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stanford seminar</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/stanford-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 06:09:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/stanford-seminar/</guid>
      <description>I gave a seminar at Stanford today. Slides are below. It was definitely the most intimidating audience I&amp;rsquo;ve faced, with Jerome Friedman, Trevor Hastie, Brad Efron, Persi Diaconis, Susan Holmes, David Donoho and John Chambers all present (and probably other famous names I&amp;rsquo;ve missed).
I&amp;rsquo;ll be giving essentially the same talk at UC Davis on Thursday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chinese R conference</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/chinese-r-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 06:42:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/chinese-r-conference/</guid>
      <description>I will be speaking at the Chinese R conference in Nanchang, to be held on 24-25 October, on &amp;ldquo;Forecasting Big Time Series Data using R&amp;rdquo;.
Details (for those who can read Chinese) are at china-r.org.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming talks in California</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/upcoming-talks-in-california/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 06:41:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/upcoming-talks-in-california/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m back in California for the next couple of weeks, and will give the following talk at Stanford and UC-Davis.
Optimal forecast reconciliation for big time series data Time series can often be naturally disaggregated in a hierarchical or grouped structure. For example, a manufacturing company can disaggregate total demand for their products by country of sale, retail outlet, product type, package size, and so on. As a result, there can be millions of individual time series to forecast at the most disaggregated level, plus additional series to forecast at higher levels of aggregation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Yahoo talk is now online</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/yahoo2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 17:12:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/yahoo2015/</guid>
      <description>Last week I gave a talk in the Yahoo! Big Thinkers series. The video of the talk is now online and embedded below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping up to date with my research papers</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/new-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2015 05:22:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/new-papers/</guid>
      <description>Many people ask me to let them know when I write a new research paper. I can&amp;rsquo;t do that as there are too many people involved, and it is not scalable.
The solution is simple. Take your pick from the following options. Each is automatic and will let you know whenever I produce a new paper.
 Subscribe to the rss feed on my website using feedly or some other rss reader.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>North American seminars: June 2015</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/northamerica2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 03:11:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/northamerica2015/</guid>
      <description>For the next few weeks I am travelling in North America and will be giving the following talks.
 19 June: Southern California Edison, Rosemead CA. &amp;ldquo;Probabilistic forecasting of peak electricity demand&amp;rdquo;.
 23 June: International Symposium on Forecasting, Riverside CA. &amp;ldquo;MEFM: An R package for long-term probabilistic forecasting of electricity demand&amp;rdquo;.
 25 June: Google, Mountain View, CA. &amp;ldquo;Automatic algorithms for time series forecasting&amp;rdquo;.
 26 June: Yahoo, Sunnyvale, CA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking big at Yahoo</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/thinking-big-at-yahoo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 23:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/thinking-big-at-yahoo/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m speaking in the &amp;ldquo;Yahoo Labs Big Thinkers&amp;rdquo; series on Friday 26 June. I hope I can live up to the title!
My talk is on &amp;ldquo;Exploring the boundaries of predictability: what can we forecast, and when should we give up?&amp;rdquo; Essentially I will start with some of the ideas in this post, and then discuss the features of hard-to-forecast time series.
So if you&amp;rsquo;re in the San Francisco Bay area, please come along.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical modelling and analysis of big data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/bigdata2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 23:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/bigdata2015/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently attending the one day workshop on this topic at QUT in Brisbane. This morning I spoke on &amp;ldquo;Visualizing and forecasting big time series data&amp;rdquo;. My slides are here.
OVERVIEW Big data is now endemic in business, industry, government, environmental management, medical science, social research and so on. One of the commensurate challenges is how to effectively model and analyse these data.
This workshop will bring together national and international experts in statistical modelling and analysis of big data, to share their experiences, approaches and opinions about future directions in this field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seminars in Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/seminars-in-taiwan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 09:33:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/seminars-in-taiwan/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently visiting Taiwan and I&amp;rsquo;m giving two seminars while I&amp;rsquo;m here &amp;mdash; one at the National Tsing Hua University in Hsinchu, and the other at Academia Sinica in Taipei. Details are below for those who might be nearby.Automatic Time Series Forecasting College of Technology Management, Institute of Service Science, National Tsing Hua University, Hsinchu 時間及地點：2015.1.7 (Wed.) 5pm @ TSMC building, 6F, room 622. 台積館6F孫運璿紀念中心 Many applications require a large number of time series to be forecast completely automatically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect with local employers</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/connect-with-local-employers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 23:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/connect-with-local-employers/</guid>
      <description>I keep telling students that there are lots of jobs in data science (including statistics), and they often tell me they can&amp;rsquo;t find them advertised. As usual, you do have to do some networking, and one of the best ways of doing it is via a Data Science Meetup. Many cities now have them including Melbourne, Sydney, London, etc. It is the perfect opportunity to meet with local employers, many of which are hiring due to the huge expansion in the use of data analysis in business (aka business analytics).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visit of Di Cook</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/visit-of-di-cook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 23:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/visit-of-di-cook/</guid>
      <description>Next week, Professor Di Cook from Iowa State University is visiting my research group at Monash University. Di is a world leader in data visualization, and is especially well-known for her work on interactive graphics and the XGobi and GGobi software. See her book with Deb Swayne for details.
For those wanting to hear her speak, read on.Research seminar She will be giving a seminar at 2pm on Monday 18 August at the Monash Clayton campus (Rm E457, Menzies Building 11).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European talks. June-July 2014</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/europe2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2014 06:44:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/europe2014/</guid>
      <description>For the next month I am travelling in Europe and will be giving the following talks.
17 June. Challenges in forecasting peak electricity demand. Energy Forum, Sierre, Valais/Wallis, Switzerland.
20 June. Common functional principal component models for mortality forecasting. International Workshop on Functional and Operatorial Statistics. Stresa, Italy.
24-25 June. Functional time series with applications in demography. Humboldt University, Berlin.
1 July. Fast computation of reconciled forecasts in hierarchical and grouped time series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a handout from beamer slides</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/beamer-handout/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 01:29:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/beamer-handout/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m about to head off on a speaking tour to Europe (more on that in another post) and one of my hosts has asked for my powerpoint slides so they can print them. They have made two false assumptions: (1) that I use powerpoint; (2) that my slides are static so they can be printed.
Instead, I produced a cut-down version of my beamer slides, leaving out some of the animations and other features that will not print easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic time series forecasting in Granada</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/granada-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 03:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/granada-workshop/</guid>
      <description>In two weeks I am presenting a workshop at the University of Granada (Spain) on Automatic Time Series Forecasting.
Unlike most of my talks, this is not intended to be primarily about my own research. Rather it is to provide a state-of-the-art overview of the topic (at a level suitable for Masters students in Computer Science). I thought I&amp;rsquo;d provide some historical perspective on the development of automatic time series forecasting, plus give some comments on the current best practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing white space around R figures</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/crop-r-figures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 00:22:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/crop-r-figures/</guid>
      <description>When I want to insert figures generated in R into a LaTeX document, it looks better if I first remove the white space around the figure. Unfortunately, R does not make this easy as the graphs are generated to look good on a screen, not in a document.
There are two things that can be done to fix this problem.First, you can reduce the white space generated by R. I use the following function when saving figures in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Man vs Wild Data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ysc2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 00:13:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ysc2013/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m speaking on this topic at the Young Statisticians Conference, 7-8 February 2013.
If you&amp;rsquo;re a young statistician and live in Australia, please book in. It promises to be a great couple of days. Early registrations close on 2 January.
Abstract for my talk:
For 25 years I have been an intrepid statistical consultant, tackling the wild frontiers of real data, real problems and real time constraints. I have faced problems ranging from linguistics to river beds, from making paper plates to selling pies at the MCG, from tax office audits to surveys about the colour purple.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bare bones beamer</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/beamer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 06:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/beamer/</guid>
      <description>Beamer is far and away the most popular software for presentations amongst researchers in mathematics and statistics. Most conference and seminar talks I attend these days use beamer. Unfortunately, they all look much the same. I think people find beamer themes too hard to modify easily, so a small number of templates get shared around. Even the otherwise wonderful LaTeX Templates site has no beamer examples.
The beamer user guide explains how to make changes but it is not for the faint-hearted (although it is a fantastic resource once you have some expertise).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six places left for the forecasting workshop</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/swissworkshop2011a/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2011 00:55:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/swissworkshop2011a/</guid>
      <description>There are six places left for the forecasting workshop I am giving in Switzerland in June. If you were thinking of going, book in fast!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for academic talks</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2011 22:21:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/talks/</guid>
      <description>There is a nice post on Matt Might&amp;rsquo;s blog entitled &amp;ldquo;10 tips on how to give an academic talk&amp;rdquo;. Check it out.
He recommends the following two books by Joey Asher.
See also my article on &amp;ldquo;Giving an academic talk&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting workshop: Switzerland, June 2011</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/swissworkshop2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 08:57:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/swissworkshop2011/</guid>
      <description>I will be running a workshop on Statistical Forecasting: Principles and Practice in Switzerland, 20-22 June 2011. Check out the venue: Waldhotel Doldenhorn, Kandersteg! So if you fancy a trip to the beautiful Swiss Alps next June, read on&amp;hellip;Outline Forecasting is required in many situations: deciding whether to build another power generation plant in the next five years requires forecasts of future demand; scheduling staff in a call centre next week requires forecasts of call volume; stocking an inventory requires forecasts of stock requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data visualization videos</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/data-visualization-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 04:05:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/data-visualization-videos/</guid>
      <description>Probably everyone has seen Hans Rosling&amp;rsquo;s famous TED talk by now. If not, here it is:
  I recently came across a couple of other exceptional talks on data visualization:
Hans Rosling again: &amp;rdquo;Let my dataset change your mindset&amp;rdquo;. If only all statistics lecturers were this dynamic!
  David McCandless: &amp;ldquo;The beauty of data visualization&amp;rdquo;. Not so exciting as Hans, but some great examples.
  And here&amp;rsquo;s an hour-length documentary hosted by Hans Rosling called &amp;ldquo;The Joy of Stats&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animated plots in R and LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 04:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/animations/</guid>
      <description>I like to use animated plots in my talks on functional time series, partly because it is the only way to really see what is going on with changes in the shapes of curves over time, and also because audiences love them! Here is how it is done.
For LaTeX, you need to create every frame as a separate graphics file. Here is an example. First the R code:
library(demography) nyears &amp;lt;- length(fr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attending research seminars</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/attending-research-seminars/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2009 06:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/attending-research-seminars/</guid>
      <description>Most research students don&amp;rsquo;t seem to attend seminars. When asked, they usually say the seminars are not on their topic, or they don&amp;rsquo;t understand them, or they find them boring, or some other similar reason. I think this is because students don&amp;rsquo;t understand the purpose of research seminars, and have not learned how to listen to them.
Admittedly, many research seminars are badly presented, and seminar speakers also frequently misunderstand the purpose of the seminar, which makes the problem worse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 7 secrets of highly successful PhD students</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/7secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 07:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/7secrets/</guid>
      <description>It seems everyone has 7 secrets to success, and now someone has hopped on the 7-secrets bandwagon with something for PhD students. Thinkwell is an Australian company offering a seminar and associated work book on &amp;ldquo;The 7 secrets of highly successful PhD students&amp;rdquo;. I bought the book out of curiosity, but &amp;ldquo;book&amp;rdquo; is a gross exaggeration &amp;ndash; only eleven pages of fairly simplistic advice. I hope the seminar has more substance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giving a research seminar</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/giving-a-research-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 07:59:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/giving-a-research-seminar/</guid>
      <description>An expanded version of this post is available in my article on “Giving an academic talk”.
With conference season almost upon us, it is timely to discuss what makes a good conference presentation. Here is a suggested structure.
 A motivating example demonstrating the problem you are trying to solve. Explain existing approaches to the problem and their weaknesses. Describe your main contributions. Show how your ideas solve the problem/example you started with.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>