<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maxima on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/categories/maxima/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Maxima on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 05:21:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/categories/maxima/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New job opportunities at Monash</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/maxima-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 05:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/maxima-jobs/</guid>
      <description>We are now advertising for various positions in applied statistics, operations research and applied mathematics.
Click here for details These jobs are with MAXIMA (the Monash Academy for Cross &amp;amp; Interdisciplinary Mathematical Applications).
Please do not send any questions to me (I won&amp;rsquo;t answer). Click above and fol­low the instructions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three jobs at Monash</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/three-jobs-at-monash/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2013 04:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/three-jobs-at-monash/</guid>
      <description>We are currently advertising for three academic positions, suitable for recent PhD graduates.
Lecturer (Applied Statistics or Operations Research)  Five-year position with MAXIMA and the School of Mathematical Sciences
 Two positions available.
 Applications close 31 October.
 More information.
  Lecturer (Econometrics/Business Statistics)  Continuing position with the Department of Econometrics and Business Statistics
 Applications close 31 January 2014.
 More information.
  Please don&amp;rsquo;t send any questions to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MAXIMA research centre at Monash Uni</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/maxima/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 01:17:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/maxima/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;ldquo;Monash Academy for Cross and Interdisciplinary Mathematical Applications&amp;rdquo; (MAXIMA) is a new research centre that aims to maximise the potential of mathematics to deliver impact to society. It will be led by Kate Smith-Miles. I will also be involved along with several other mathematicians at Monash. Our mission at MAXIMA is to find solutions to 21st century problems by dismantling mathematical barriers.
MAXIMA will be launched on 25 September at a public lecture on &amp;ldquo;The Role of Embedded Optimization in Smart Systems and Products&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>