<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Isf2017 on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/categories/isf2017/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Isf2017 on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 22:29:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/categories/isf2017/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited sessions at ISF2017</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/invited-sessions-at-isf2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2017 22:29:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/invited-sessions-at-isf2017/</guid>
      <description>We are still looking for a few more invited sessions for the International Symposium on Forecasting, to be held in Cairns, Australia, 25-28 June 2017.An invited session consists of 3 or 4 talks around a specific, forecasting theme. You are allowed to be one of the speakers in a session you organize (although it is not necessary). Therefore, if you know what you are planning to speak about, all you need to do is find 2 or 3 other speakers who will speak on a related topic, and invite them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasters: bring your family to Cairns</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/isf-social/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2017 10:06:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/isf-social/</guid>
      <description>Courtesy of Tourism Tropical North Queensland   We know Australia is a long way to come for many forecasters, so we are making it easy for you to bring your families along to the International Symposium on Forecasting and have a vacation at the same time.
During the International Symposium on Forecasting, there will be a social program organized for family and friends. Monday, 26 June Official Partners Tour: Kuranda, Train &amp;amp; Skyrail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting practitioner talks at ISF 2017</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/isf2017-practitioners/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 23:55:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/isf2017-practitioners/</guid>
      <description>The International Symposium on Forecasting is a little unusual for an academic conference in that it has always had a strong presence of forecasters working in business and industry as well as academic forecasters, mostly at universities. We value the combination and interaction as it helps the academics understand the sorts of problems facing forecasters in practice, and it helps practitioners stay abreast of new methods and developments coming out of forecasting research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited sessions at the International Symposium on Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/isf-invited-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2016 06:55:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/isf-invited-sessions/</guid>
      <description>We are currently calling for invited session proposals for the ISF to be held in Cairns, Australia, in June 2017.
An invited session consists of 3 or 4 talks around a specific forecasting theme. You are allowed to be one of the speakers in a session you organize (although it is not necessary). So if you know what you are planning to speak about, all you need to do is find 2 or 3 other speakers who will speak on something related, and invite them to join you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for forecasting workshops in Cairns, Australia</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/cairns-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 15:25:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/cairns-workshops/</guid>
      <description>The 37th annual International Symposium on Forecasting will be held in Cairns, Australia, from 25-28 June 2017. We plan to hold some workshops on Sunday 25 June, before the main conference.We are currently calling for workshop proposals. Proposals can be for a half-day or full-day workshop. As usual, there will be a Practitioner Track at the conference which generally leads to excellent attendance at the workshops.
Though June sounds far away, planning for the conference is well underway!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sponsorship for the Cairns forecasting conference</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/isf2017-sponsorship/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 02:07:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/isf2017-sponsorship/</guid>
      <description>Regular readers will know that the International Symposium on Forecasting is coming to Australia in June 2017. This is the leading international forecasting conference, and one I&amp;rsquo;ve attended every year for the past 17 years.
It will be held in Cairns, Australia &amp;mdash; one of the most beautiful locations in the country (and there is some stiff competition!) and right next to the Great Barrier Reef. Some further information is available on our website (still in progress).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 International Symposium on Energy Analytics</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/isea2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 02:56:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/isea2017/</guid>
      <description>Predictive Energy Analytics in the Big Data World Cairns, Australia, June 22-23, 2017 ISEA2017 
This will be a great conference, and it is in a great location &amp;mdash; Cairns, Australia, right by the Great Barrier Reef. Even better, if you stay on you can attend the International Symposium on Forecasting which immediately follows the International Symposium on Energy Analytics.
So block out 22-28 June 2017 on your calendars so you can enjoy a tropical paradise in one of the most beautiful parts of Australia, while attending two awesome conferences.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>