<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Seminars on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Seminars on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>High dimensional time series analysis</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/abs-hdts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/abs-hdts/</guid>
      <description>Presentation for the Australian Bureau of Statistics I will provide an overview of some of my recent research on methods to deal with high-dimensional time series.
1. Visualizing many time series
It is becoming increasingly common for organizations to collect very large amounts of data over time. Data visualization is essential for exploring and understanding structures and patterns, and to identify unusual observations. However, the sheer quantity of data available challenges current time series visualisation methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research&#43;&#43;: what you should know about being a researcher but probably don&#39;t</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/research&#43;&#43;/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/research&#43;&#43;/</guid>
      <description> Presentation for my research group about aspects of being a researcher.
Some of this material has appeared as blog posts at some time.
Slides Links  Paperpile My Google Scholar profile How to Write a Lot: A Practical Guide to Productive Academic Writing Monash University authorship policy Antarctica Journal of Mathematics  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic outlier detection and visualization of smart metre data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/nzsa2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/nzsa2017/</guid>
      <description>Talk given at meeting of New Zealand Statistical Association and International Association for Statistical Computing (11-14 December 2017), Auckland, New Zealand.
It is always a good idea to plot your data before fitting any models, making any predictions, or drawing any conclusions. But how do you actually plot data on thousands of smart meters, each comprising thousands of observations over time? We cannot simply produce time plots of the demand recorded at each meter, due to the sheer volume of data involved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2017 Beijing Workshop on Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/beijing2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/beijing2017/</guid>
      <description>Location: Central University of Finance and Economics, Beijing, China.
Slides Forecast Accuracy and Evaluation Automatic Forecasting Algorithms Hierarchical Forecasting Probabilistic Hierarchical Forecasting   Textbook 
 Relevant papers  Rob J Hyndman, Anne B Koehler, Ralph D Snyder, Simone Grose (2002) A state space framework for automatic forecasting using exponential smoothing methods. International Journal of Forecasting 18(3), 439-454. Rob J Hyndman, Anne B Koehler (2006) Another look at measures of forecast accuracy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High dimensional time series analysis</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/acems-hdts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/acems-hdts/</guid>
      <description>Keynote presentation for ACEMS retreat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing sub-daily time series data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/subdaily-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/subdaily-2017/</guid>
      <description>Talk given by me, Earo Wang and Mitchell O&amp;rsquo;Hara-Wild at the Melbourne Users of R Network meeting.
Slides   

&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
Packages</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting: principles and practice (UWA)</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/uwa2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/uwa2017/</guid>
      <description>Date: 26-28 September 2017
Location: The University Club, University of Western Australia
This page is for people enrolled in my UWA 3-day workshop.
Prerequisites Please bring your own laptop with a recent version of R and RStudio installed, along with the following packages and their dependencies:
 fpp2 readxl thief knitr  Participants will be assumed to be familiar with basic statistical tools such as multiple regression, but no knowledge of time series or forecasting will be assumed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-dimensional time series</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/high-dimensional-time-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/high-dimensional-time-series/</guid>
      <description>Presentation for ACEMS Monash node, giving an overview of my current major research interests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biggish time series data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/biggish-time-series-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/biggish-time-series-data/</guid>
      <description>Informal presentation for a UNSW research group, giving an overview of some of my research interests over the last few years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal forecast reconcilation</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/unsw2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/unsw2017/</guid>
      <description>Talk given at UNSW
Abstract
Time series can often be naturally disaggregated in a hierarchical or grouped structure. For example, a manufacturing company can disaggregate total demand for their products by country of sale, retail outlet, product type, package size, and so on. As a result, there can be millions of individual time series to forecast at the most disaggregated level, plus additional series to forecast at higher levels of aggregation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing and forecasting big time series data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/icml2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/icml2017/</guid>
      <description>ICML Time Series Workshop
Sydney, Australia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using data to tackle poverty</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/poverty2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/poverty2017/</guid>
      <description> Talk to Year 11 students as part of the Monash Scholars Knowledge Summit on &amp;ldquo;Ending Global Poverty&amp;rdquo;.
Introductory remarks  &amp;nbsp;
&amp;nbsp;
Hans Rosling: New insights on poverty  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic outlier detection and visualization of smart metre data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/isea2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/isea2017/</guid>
      <description>Talk to be given at International Symposium on Energy Analytics (22-23 June 2017), Cairns, Australia.
Standard time series analysis and visualization tools fail on smart metre data due to the sheer volume of available data (both in the time dimension and due to the large numbers of smart metres providing data). In addition, smart metre data is often messy, with missing observations, periods where some metres are offline, periods of relatively constant low level energy usage, occasional days of unusually high demand, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series in R: Forecasting and Visualisation</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/forecasting-medascin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/forecasting-medascin/</guid>
      <description>This is a one-day workshop given as part of the Melbourne Data Science Week.
Date: 29 May 2017
Presenters: Rob J Hyndman and Earo Wang
Location: KPMG, Tower Two, Collins Square, 727 Collins St, Melbourne
Prerequisites Please bring your own laptop with a recent version of R installed, along with the following packages and their dependencies:
 devtools fpp2 knitr plotly shiny tidyverse  Participants will be assumed to be familiar with basic statistical tools such as multiple regression, but no knowledge of time series or forecasting will be assumed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Follow-up Forecasting Forum</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/eindhoven2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/eindhoven2017/</guid>
      <description>Follow up to my October 2016 3-day workshop in Eindhoven, Netherlands</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software for honours students</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/2017-04-04-software-for-honours-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/2017-04-04-software-for-honours-students/</guid>
      <description>I spoke to our new crop of honours students this morning. Here are my slides, example files and links.
 
Managing References  Mendeley Zotero Paperpile  Data analysis and computation  Download R Download Rstudio Online R tutorial R packages for time series R packages for econometrics R packages for finance  Writing your thesis LaTeX  Windows: Download MikTeX Mac OSX: Download MacTeX Linux: Check your usual software source for TeXLive; otherwise install TeX Live directly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic energy forecasting for smart grids and buildings</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/melbuni-smartgrids/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/melbuni-smartgrids/</guid>
      <description>Energy Systems Integration in smart buildings, communities and microgrids
The University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Australia
21-22 March 2017
Organised by The University of Melbourne and the International Institute for Energy Systems Integration (iiESI)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting Using R (Eindhoven)</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/eindhoven/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/eindhoven/</guid>
      <description>Date: 19-21 October 2016
Location: Eurandom, Metaforum Building MF11-12, Department of Mathematics and Computer Science, TU Eindhoven, the Netherlands
Prerequisites Please bring your own laptop with a recent version of R installed, along with the following packages and their dependencies:
 fpp ggplot2 magrittr readxl thief knitr  Participants will be assumed to be familiar with basic statistical tools such as multiple regression, but no knowledge of time series or forecasting will be assumed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconciling forecasts: the hts and thief packages</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/erum2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 12:04:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/erum2016/</guid>
      <description>eRum2016, Poznań, Poland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting large collections of related time series</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/augsburg2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/augsburg2016/</guid>
      <description>Keynote talk given at the German Statistical Week, Augsburg.
Abstract
Time series can often be naturally disaggregated in a hierarchical or grouped structure. For example, a manufacturing company can disaggregate total demand for their products by country of sale, retail outlet, product type, package size, and so on. As a result, there can be millions of individual time series to forecast at the most disaggregated level, plus additional series to forecast at higher levels of aggregation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring time series collections used for forecast evaluation</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/isf2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 11:08:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/isf2016/</guid>
      <description>International Symposium on Forecasting. Santander, Spain
It is common practice to evaluate the strength of forecasting methods using collections of well-studied time series datasets, such as the M3 data. But how diverse are these time series, how challenging, and do they enable us to study the unique strengths and weaknesses of different forecasting methods? In this paper we propose a visualisation method for a collection of time series that enables a time series to be represented as a point in a 2-dimensional feature space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic foRecasting using R</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/automatic-forecasting-using-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 05:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/automatic-forecasting-using-r/</guid>
      <description>Melbourne Data Science Initiative</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making forecasting easier: forecast v7 for R</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/wombat-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/wombat-2016/</guid>
      <description>Talk given at WOMBAT 2016 conference</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting big time series data using R</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/china2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2015 23:46:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/china2015/</guid>
      <description>Keynote address given at the Chinese R conference held in Nanchang, Jianxi province. 24-25 October 2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal forecast reconciliation for big time series data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/optimal-forecast-reconciliation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2015 05:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/optimal-forecast-reconciliation/</guid>
      <description>Seminar given at Stanford University on 6th October, and University of California (Davis) on 8th October.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google workshop: Forecasting and visualizing big time series data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/google-oct-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 06:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/google-oct-2015/</guid>
      <description>Workshop for Google, Mountain View, California.
 Automatic algorithms for time series forecasting Optimal forecast reconciliation for big time series data Visualization of big time series data  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning bootcamp</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/machine-learning-bootcamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 02:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/machine-learning-bootcamp/</guid>
      <description>A talk on time series forecasting for the Monash University Machine Learning Bootcamp.
Demo R code</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the feature space of large collections of time series</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/banff2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2015 23:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/banff2015/</guid>
      <description>Work­shop on Fron­tiers in Func­tional Data Analy­sis Banff, Canada.
It is becoming increasingly common for organizations to collect very large amounts of data over time. Data visualization is essential for exploring and understanding structures and patterns, and to identify unusual observations. However, the sheer quantity of data available challenges current time series visualisation methods.
For example, Yahoo has banks of mail servers that are monitored over time. Many measurements on server performance are collected every hour for each of thousands of servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the boundaries of predictability: what can we forecast, and when should we give up?</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/yahoo2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2015 23:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/yahoo2015/</guid>
      <description>Yahoo Big Thinkers Sunnyvale, California
Friday 26 June 2015, 3:00-4:00 pm Location: Yahoo Sunnyvale Campus and LIVE at labs.yahoo.com
Why is it that we can accurately forecast a solar eclipse in 1000 years time, but we have no idea whether Yahoo&amp;rsquo;s stock price will rise or fall tomorrow? Or why can we forecast electricity consumption next week with remarkable precision, but we cannot forecast exchange rate fluctuations in the next hour?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic algorithms for time series forecasting</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/google2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2015 23:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/google2015/</guid>
      <description>Google Mountain View, California.
Many applications require a large number of time series to be forecast completely automatically. For example, manufacturing companies often require weekly forecasts of demand for thousands of products at dozens of locations in order to plan distribution and maintain suitable inventory stocks. In these circumstances, it is not feasible for time series models to be developed for each series by an experienced analyst. Instead, an automatic forecasting algorithm is required.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MEFM: An R package for long-term probabilistic forecasting of electricity demand</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/isf2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 23:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/isf2015/</guid>
      <description>International Symposium on Forecasting Riverside, California
I will describe and demonstrate a new open-source R package that implements the Monash Electricity Forecasting Model, a semi-parametric probabilistic approach to forecasting long-term electricity demand. The underlying model proposed in Hyndman and Fan (2010) is now widely used in practice, particularly in Australia. The model has undergone many improvements and developments since it was first proposed, and these have been incorporated in this R implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic forecasting of peak electricity demand</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/sce2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2015 23:00:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/sce2015/</guid>
      <description>Southern California Edison Rosemead, California
Electricity demand forecasting plays an important role in short-term load allocation and long-term planning for future generation facilities and transmission augmentation. It is a challenging problem because of the different uncertainties including underlying population growth, changing technology, economic conditions, prevailing weather conditions (and the timing of those conditions), as well as the general randomness inherent in individual usage. It is also subject to some known calendar effects due to the time of day, day of week, time of year, and public holidays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization of big time series data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/big-time-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 03:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/big-time-series/</guid>
      <description>Talk given to a joint meeting of the Statistical Society of Australia (Victorian branch) and the Melbourne Data Science Meetup Group.It is becoming increasingly common for organizations to collect very large amounts of data over time. Data visualization is essential for exploring and understanding structures and patterns, and to identify unusual observations. However, the sheer quantity of data available challenges current time series visualisation methods.
For example, Yahoo has banks of mail servers that are monitored over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic forecasting of long-term peak electricity demand</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/memsi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 07:29:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/memsi/</guid>
      <description>Electricity demand forecasting plays an important role in long-term planning for future generation facilities and transmission augmentation. It is a challenging problem because of the different uncertainties including underlying population growth, changing technology, economic conditions, prevailing weather conditions (and the timing of those conditions), as well as the general randomness inherent in individual usage. It is also subject to some known calendar effects due to the time of day, day of week, time of year, and public holidays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization and forecasting of big time series data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/big-time-series-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 01:11:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/big-time-series-data/</guid>
      <description>Talk given at the ACEMS Big data workshop, QUT.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualizing and forecasting big time series data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/visualizing-and-forecasting-big-time-series-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 15:33:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/visualizing-and-forecasting-big-time-series-data/</guid>
      <description>Institute of Statistical Science, Academia Sinica 時　間 2015/01/12 11:00 星期一 地　點 中研院-統計所 2F 交誼廳 備　註 茶 會：上午10：40統計所二樓交誼廳
Time series can often be naturally disaggregated in a hierarchical or grouped structure. For example, a manufacturing company can disaggregate total demand for their products by country of sale, retail outlet, product type, package size, and so on. As a result, there can be millions of individual time series to forecast at the most disaggregated level, plus additional series to forecast at higher levels of aggregation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Am I a data scientist?</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/christmasgala2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/christmasgala2014/</guid>
      <description>Talk given at the Melbourne Analytics Charity Christmas Gala, a combined event of the Statistical Society of Australia, Data Science Melbourne, Big Data Analytics and Melbourne Users of R Network.
This is (roughly) what I said.Statisticians seem to go through regular periods of existential crisis as they worry about other groups of people who do data analysis. A common theme is: all these other people (usually computer scientists) are doing our job!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting: principles and practice (UWA course)</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/uwa/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2014 03:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/uwa/</guid>
      <description> Workshop to be held on 23-25 September 2014.
Venue: The University Club, University of Western Australia, Nedlands WA.
Requirements: a laptop with R installed, along with the fpp package and its dependencies. We will also use the hts and vars package on the third day.
Textbook [Hyndman and Athanasopoulos (2014)
Forecasting: principles and practice, OTexts: Melbourne, Australia](http://www.otexts.org/fpp).
Program  Introduction to forecasting [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Forecasting tools [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Exponential smoothing I [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Exponential smoothing II [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Time series decomposition and cross-validation [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Transformations, stationarity and differencing [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Non-seasonal ARIMA models [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Seasonal ARIMA models [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] State space models [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Dynamic regression [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Hierarchical forecasting [Slides, R code, Lab solutions] Advanced methods [Slides, R code, Lab solutions]  Course Notes </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fast computation of reconciled forecasts in hierarchical and grouped time series</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/hgts-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 06:38:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/hgts-2/</guid>
      <description>International Symposium on Forecasting, Rotterdam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional time series with applications in demography</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/fts-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 02:33:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/fts-berlin/</guid>
      <description>This is a short course given at Humboldt University, Berlin, 24-25 June 2014.
Venue: LvB Library, Room 401, Spandauerstr. 1, 10178 Berlin
Time: 24 June 2014, 09:30 - 12:30 and 14:00 - 17:00 25 June 2014, 09:30 - 11:30
Functional time series are curves that are observed sequentially in time, one curve being observed in each time period. In demography, examples include curves formed by annual death rates as a function of age, or annual fertility rates as a function of age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenges in forecasting peak electricity demand</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/swiss-energy-forum/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2014 06:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/swiss-energy-forum/</guid>
      <description>I am giving a two-part seminar at the Energy Forum, Valais/Wallis, Switzerland, on 17 June 2014. (English brochure)
Abstract: Electricity demand forecasting plays an important role in short-term load allocation and long-term planning for future generation facilities and transmission augmentation. It is a challenging problem because of the different uncertainties including underlying population growth, changing technology, economic conditions, prevailing weather conditions (and the timing of those conditions), as well as the general randomness inherent in individual usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State space models</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/abs-state-space-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2014 01:21:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/abs-state-space-models/</guid>
      <description>Exponential smoothing
 Slides R examples Lab session Solutions to lab session  Structural models
 Slides R examples Lab session Solutions to lab session  ARIMA and RegARMA models, and dlm
 Slides R examples   (Updated: 2 June 2014)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic time series forecasting</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/granada/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2014 01:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/granada/</guid>
      <description>Talk presented at the conference &amp;ldquo;New Trends on Intelligent Systems and Soft Computing 2014&amp;rdquo;, University of Granada, Spain. 13-14 February 2014.Abstract Many applications require a large number of time series to be forecast completely automatically. For example, manufacturing companies often require weekly forecasts of demand for thousands of products at dozens of locations in order to plan distribution and maintain suitable inventory stocks. In these circumstances, it is not feasible for time series models to be developed for each series by an experienced analyst.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coherent mortality forecasting using functional time series</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/coherent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2013 05:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/coherent/</guid>
      <description>A talk given today at Macquarie University, Sydney.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting hierarchical time series</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/hts-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2013 05:40:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/hts-3/</guid>
      <description>Talk given at University of Sydney today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R tools for hierarchical time series</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/hts-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 20:07:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/hts-2/</guid>
      <description>Talk given at EURO/INFORMS, Rome, 1 July 2013
And at UseR! 2013, Albacete, Spain, 10 July 2013.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting without forecasters</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/forecasting-without-forecasters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2013 14:15:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/forecasting-without-forecasters/</guid>
      <description>A keynote talk given at the International Symposium on Forecasting, Seoul, South Korea. 25 June 2013.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Man vs wild data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/man-vs-wild-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 21:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/man-vs-wild-data/</guid>
      <description>Keynote address. Young Statisticians Conference 2013.
Abstract: For 25 years I have been an intrepid statistical consultant, tackling the wild frontiers of real data, real problems and real time constraints. I have faced problems ranging from linguistics to river beds, from making paper plates to selling pies at the MCG, from tax office audits to surveys about the colour purple. University education helps prepare you to be a statistical consultant in the same way that Google maps helps prepare you to cross the Simpson Desert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SimpleR: tips, tricks and tools</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/simpler/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 07:00:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/simpler/</guid>
      <description>Melbourne R Users&amp;rsquo; Group
Deloitte, Level 11, 550 Bourke Street, Melbourne
Examples</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advances in automatic time series forecasting</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/automaticforecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2012 08:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/automaticforecasting/</guid>
      <description>Invited talk, Australian Statistical Conference, Adelaide, 10 July 2012.
 COMPSTAT 2012, Cyprus, 29 August 2012.
 Seminar, Lancaster University, 10 September 2012.  Many applications require a large number of time series to be forecast completely automatically. For example, manufacturing companies often require weekly forecasts of demand for thousands of products at dozens of locations in order to plan distribution and maintain suitable inventory stocks. In population forecasting, there are often a few hundred time series to be forecast, representing various components that make up the population dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting time series using R</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/melbournerug/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 04:37:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/melbournerug/</guid>
      <description>Melbourne R Users&amp;rsquo; Group Thursday, October 27, 2011, 6:00 PM Deloitte, Level 11 (Culture Room), 550 Bourke Street, Melbourne
I will look at the various facilities for time series forecasting available in R, concentrating on the forecast package. This package implements several automatic methods for forecasting time series including forecasts from ARIMA models, ARFIMA models and exponential smoothing models. I will also look more generally at how to go about forecasting non-seasonal data, seasonal data, seasonal data with high frequency, and seasonal data with multiple frequencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting electricity demand distributions using a semiparametric additive model </title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/electricity-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 03:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/electricity-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>Talk given at
 University of Melbourne, 11 October 2011. University of Adelaide, 16 March 2012 Monash University, 16 May 2012 La Trobe University, 24 May 2012 EDF, Paris. 4 September 2012 University of New South Wales, 1 November 2012  Abstract: Electricity demand forecasting plays an important role in short-term load allocation and long-term planning for future generation facilities and transmission augmentation. Planners must adopt a probabilistic view of potential peak demand levels, therefore density forecasts (providing estimates of the full probability distributions of the possible future values of the demand) are more helpful than point forecasts, and are necessary for utilities to evaluate and hedge the financial risk accrued by demand variability and forecasting uncertainty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating extreme quantile forecasts</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/maep/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2011 11:27:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/maep/</guid>
      <description>Talk to be given at the International Symposium on Forecasting, Prague, 26–29 June 2011.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demographic forecasting using functional data analysis</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/demographic-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 11:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/demographic-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>University of Wollongong, 8 September 2010. Statistical Society of Australia, Victorian Branch, 28 September 2010. Updated version. September 2012.  Abstract:
Functional time series are curves that are observed sequentially in time. In demography, such data arise as the curves formed by annual death rates as a function of age or annual fertility rates as a function of age. I will discuss methods for describing, modelling and forecasting such functional time series data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coherent functional forecasts of mortality rates and life expectancy</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/isf2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 04:20:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/isf2010/</guid>
      <description>Talk to be given at the International Symposium on Forecasting, San Diego, 20-23 June 2010.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>English academic writing</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/english-academic-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2009 03:47:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/english-academic-writing/</guid>
      <description> Presentation to College of Management, University of Fuzhou, China. 25 June 2009. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extreme forecasting</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/extreme-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2009 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/extreme-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>Keynote address, International Symposium on Forecasting, June 2009. Abstract
Extremely bad data, extremely poor methods and extremely difficult problems will be used as the basis of some extremely useful lessons. I will describe three cases from my consulting experience and draw some general lessons that are widely applicable.
The first case involved forecasting passenger traffic on an Australian airline. The data showed variations due to school holidays, major sporting events, competitor activity, industrial disputes, changes in fare structures, and other factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical support for HDR students</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/statistical-support-for-hdr-students/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 03:52:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/statistical-support-for-hdr-students/</guid>
      <description> Presentation to a meeting of Australian Deans and Directors of Graduate Studies, 1 May 2009. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting and the importance of being uncertain</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/forecasting-and-the-importance-of-being-uncertain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2008 03:54:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/forecasting-and-the-importance-of-being-uncertain/</guid>
      <description> Indian Institute of Management Calcutta. Melbourne, 18 July 2008. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building R packages for Windows</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/building-r-packages-for-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2008 04:07:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/building-r-packages-for-windows/</guid>
      <description> R workshop. Melbourne, 29 June 2008. There was an R workshop on 28-29 June, just before the Australian Statistical Conference. I put in an appearance on the second day.
Building R packages for Windows
 handout slides  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time series and forecasting in R</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/time-series-and-forecasting-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2008 04:00:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/time-series-and-forecasting-in-r/</guid>
      <description> R workshop. Melbourne, 29 June 2008. There was an R workshop on 28-29 June, just before the Australian Statistical Conference. I put in an appearance on the second day.
Time series and forecasting in R
 handout slides  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bagplots, boxplots and outlier detection for functional data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/fboxplot-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2008 03:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/fboxplot-talk/</guid>
      <description>Australian Statistics Conference. Melbourne, July 2008.  Where: First International Workshop on Functional and Operatorial Statistics, Toulouse Where : Australian Statistical Conference Melbourne, Australia Speakers: Professor Rob&amp;nbsp;J&amp;nbsp;Hyndman, Monash University &amp;amp; Han Lin Shang, Monash University  Abstract: We propose some new tools for visualizing functional data and for identifying functional outliers. The proposed tools make use of robust principal component analysis, data depth and highest density regions. We compare the proposed outlier detection methods with the existing “functional depth” method, and show that our methods have better performance on identifying outliers in French male age-specific mortality data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exponential smoothing and non-negative data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/exponential-smoothing-and-non-negative-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2008 07:51:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/exponential-smoothing-and-non-negative-data/</guid>
      <description>Where: International Symposium on Forecasting, Nice, France  Abstract: The most common forecasting methods in business are based on exponential smoothing and the most common time series in business are inherently non-negative. Therefore it is of interest to consider the properties of the potential stochastic models underlying exponential smoothing when applied to non-negative data. We explore nonlinear exponential smoothing state space models for non-negative data under various assumptions about the innovations, or error, process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting functional time series</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/forecasting-functional-time-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2008 07:56:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/forecasting-functional-time-series/</guid>
      <description>Where: Australian Frontiers of Science  Abstract: Functional time series are curves that are observed sequentially in time. For example, the curve of death rate as a function of age is observed annually. Yield curves in finance (essentially interest rates as a function of the term of investment) are observed each week or each day. Electricity consumption as a function of temperature is observed every month. These are all high dimensional functional data, indexed by time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Population forecasting and the importance of being uncertain</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/population-forecasting-and-the-importance-of-being-uncertain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2007 07:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/population-forecasting-and-the-importance-of-being-uncertain/</guid>
      <description>Where: Knibbs Lecture, Statistical Society of Australia  Abstract: Forecasters had an inauspicious beginning, dabbling with divination, sheep&amp;rsquo;s livers and vapour-ridden caves in the mountains of Greece. Then there was a time when forecasters could be charged with vagrancy! Their reputations are still tarnished, but their tools are rather more effective. Professor Rob Hyndman will argue for the importance of statistical modelling in forecasting, and demonstrate the dangers that occur when uncertainty is ignored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduation address</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/graduation-address/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2007 08:02:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/graduation-address/</guid>
      <description>Mr Chancellor, Madam Deputy Vice-Chancellor, colleagues, guests, and especially graduates.
I would like to congratulate all of you who are graduating tonight.
It is a great achievement to have completed a university degree, and you should all feel very, very proud of your accomplishment. This is one of the six great milestones in your life: the others being birth, death, marriage, parenthood and the day you finally pay off your HECS debt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting medium- and long-term peak electricity demand</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/forecasting-medium-and-long-term-peak-electricity-demand/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2007 08:06:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/forecasting-medium-and-long-term-peak-electricity-demand/</guid>
      <description>Where: International Symposium on Forecasting, New York  Abstract: Peak electricity demand forecasting is important in medium and long-term planning of electricity supply. Extreme demand often leads to supply failure with consequential business and social disruption. Forecasting extreme demand events is therefore an important problem in energy management.
Electricity demand at a given time is subject to a range of influences, including the ambient temperature, recent past temperatures, time of day, day of week, holidays, economic conditions and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic population forecasts using functional data models</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/stochastic-population/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2007 08:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/stochastic-population/</guid>
      <description>When: 12.00noon, Thu 22nd February 2007 Where: Room 213, Richard Berry Building, The University of Melbourne When: 2.30pm, Fri 1 June 2007 Where: Room 457, Menzies Building, Monash University (Clayton)  Abstract: I will present a new approach to age-specific forecasting of population based on separate forecasts of mortality, fertility and net migration. Functional data models with time series coefficients will be used to model mortality and fertility rates, and net migration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting and the importance of being uncertain</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/forecasting-and-the-importance-of-being-uncertain-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2006 08:11:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/forecasting-and-the-importance-of-being-uncertain-2/</guid>
      <description>What: 2006 Belz lecture, Statistical Society of Australia (Victorian branch) When: 6.15pm, 24 October 2006 Where: Old Geology Theatre 1, University of Melbourne  Forecasters had an inauspicious beginning, dabbling with divination, sheep&amp;rsquo;s livers and vapour-ridden caves in the mountains of Greece. Then there was a time when forecasters could be charged with vagrancy! Their reputations are still tarnished, but their tools are rather more effective. Professor Rob Hyndman will argue for the importance of statistical modelling in forecasting, and demonstrate the dangers that occur when uncertainty is ignored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic time series forecasting</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/automatic-time-series-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2006 08:10:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/automatic-time-series-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>UseR! conference, Vienna, Austria</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal combination forecasts for hierarchical time series</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/hierarchical2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2006 07:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/hierarchical2/</guid>
      <description>International Symposium on Forecasting, Santander, Spain
Speakers: Rob&amp;nbsp;J&amp;nbsp;Hyndman and Roman A. Ahmed</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>