<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Organization on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/categories/organization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Organization on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 02:42:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/categories/organization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Paperpile makes me more productive</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/paperpile/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 02:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/paperpile/</guid>
      <description>One of the first things I tell my new research students is to use a reference management system to help them keep track of the papers they read, and to assist in creating bib files for their bibliography. Most of them use Mendeley, one or two use Zotero. Both do a good job and both are free.
I use neither. I did use Mendeley for several years, but it became slower and slower to sync as my reference collection grew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing research ideas</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/managing-research-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 13:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/managing-research-ideas/</guid>
      <description>I received this email today:
 Dear Professor Hyndman, I was wondering if you could maybe give me some advice on how to organize your research process. I am able to search the literature on a certain topic and identify where there is a question to work with. My main difficult is to organize my paper annotations in order to help me to guide my research process, i.e, how to manage the information gathered in those papers to compose and structure a document which can represent the research developed so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Makefiles for R/LaTeX projects</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/makefiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2012 02:49:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/makefiles/</guid>
      <description>Updated: 21 November 2012
Make is a marvellous tool used by programmers to build software, but it can be used for much more than that. I use make whenever I have a large project involving R files and LaTeX files, which means I use it for almost all of the papers I write, and almost of the consulting reports I produce.If you are using a Mac or Linux, you will already have make installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogs about research</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/blogs-about-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 02:04:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/blogs-about-research/</guid>
      <description>If you find this blog helpful (or even if you don&amp;rsquo;t but you&amp;rsquo;re interested in blogs on research issues and tools), there are a few other blogs about doing research that you might find useful. Here are a few that I read.
 Patter &amp;ndash; Pat Thomson.
 The Thesis Whisperer &amp;ndash; Inger Mewburn.
 The Research Whisperer &amp;ndash; several RMIT researchers.
 the (research) supervisor&amp;rsquo;s friend &amp;ndash; Geof Hill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Following authors on Google Scholar</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/googlescholar2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2012 01:22:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/googlescholar2/</guid>
      <description>A great new feature has been added to Google Scholar Citations. For those authors who have set up a citations page, it is now possible to get email alerts for any new articles they publish, or for any new citations of their articles. So you can track citations to your own work this way, and stay up-to-date with key authors in your field.
Setting up a Google Citations page is super-easy and was already worth doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizing travel</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2011 13:12:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/travel/</guid>
      <description>Whether travelling to a seminar or conference, or just having a holiday, using a travel organizer can make the process simpler and easier. A good travel organizer keeps all your travel details (flights, hotels, car rentals, meetings, weather forecasts, etc.) organized and synced to whatever devices you use (two computers, an iPad and an iPhone in my case).I am aware of four travel organizers that do this: TripIt, TripCase, WorldMate and Wipolo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Researcher portals</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/portals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2011 04:14:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/portals/</guid>
      <description>A researcher portal is a website that attempts to list all the publications of a given researcher. Some portals also allow sharing papers, interacting with other researchers, calculating citation statistics, etc. Every researcher wants their work read and cited, so these websites can be useful tools for getting your work noticed. They can also function as a de facto home page if you don&amp;rsquo;t already have a personal website. Conversely, they can be a good way to find new work by researchers in your field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In praise of Dropbox</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/dropbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2010 01:49:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/dropbox/</guid>
      <description>Every couple of years, a new technology has a big impact on how I work. Gmail was one. My iPhone was another. And I rank Dropbox in the same category.
I get three huge benefits in using Dropbox:
 All my files are backed up online. The house can burn down and I know I can still get my files. Also, if I&amp;rsquo;m away from my desktop or laptop, I can still access my files on my iPhone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 7 secrets of highly successful PhD students</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/7secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2009 07:04:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/7secrets/</guid>
      <description>It seems everyone has 7 secrets to success, and now someone has hopped on the 7-secrets bandwagon with something for PhD students. Thinkwell is an Australian company offering a seminar and associated work book on &amp;ldquo;The 7 secrets of highly successful PhD students&amp;rdquo;. I bought the book out of curiosity, but &amp;ldquo;book&amp;rdquo; is a gross exaggeration &amp;ndash; only eleven pages of fairly simplistic advice. I hope the seminar has more substance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>