<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Consulting on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/tags/consulting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Consulting on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 21:30:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/tags/consulting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Man vs wild data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/man-vs-wild-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 21:30:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/man-vs-wild-data/</guid>
      <description>Keynote address. Young Statisticians Conference 2013.
Abstract: For 25 years I have been an intrepid statistical consultant, tackling the wild frontiers of real data, real problems and real time constraints. I have faced problems ranging from linguistics to river beds, from making paper plates to selling pies at the MCG, from tax office audits to surveys about the colour purple. University education helps prepare you to be a statistical consultant in the same way that Google maps helps prepare you to cross the Simpson Desert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extreme forecasting</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/extreme-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2009 03:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/extreme-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>Keynote address, International Symposium on Forecasting, June 2009. Abstract
Extremely bad data, extremely poor methods and extremely difficult problems will be used as the basis of some extremely useful lessons. I will describe three cases from my consulting experience and draw some general lessons that are widely applicable.
The first case involved forecasting passenger traffic on an Australian airline. The data showed variations due to school holidays, major sporting events, competitor activity, industrial disputes, changes in fare structures, and other factors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>