<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Seasonality on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/categories/seasonality/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Seasonality on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/categories/seasonality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Monthly seasonality</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/monthly-seasonality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/monthly-seasonality/</guid>
      <description>I regularly get asked why I don&amp;rsquo;t consider monthly seasonality in my models for daily or sub-daily time series. For example, this recent comment on my post on seasonal periods, or this comment on my post on daily data. The fact is, I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen a time series with monthly seasonality, although that does not mean it does not exist.
Monthly seasonality is defined as a regular pattern that recurs every month in data that is observed more frequently than monthly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R package forecast v7.2 now on CRAN</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/forecast-v7-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 10:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/forecast-v7-2/</guid>
      <description>I’ve pushed a minor update to the forecast package to CRAN. Some highlights are listed here.
Plotting time series with ggplot2 You can now facet a time series plot like this:
library(forecast) library(ggplot2) lungDeaths &amp;lt;- cbind(mdeaths, fdeaths) autoplot(lungDeaths, facets=TRUE) So autoplot.mts now behaves similarly to plot.mts
 Multi-step fitted values The fitted function has a new argument h to allow computation of in-sample fitted values of more than one-step-ahead. In time series, fitted values are defined as the one-step-forecasts of the data used in training a model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The thief package for R: Temporal HIErarchical Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/thief/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 07:58:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/thief/</guid>
      <description>I have a new R package available to do temporal hierarchical forecasting, based on my paper with George Athanasopoulos, Nikolaos Kourentzes and Fotios Petropoulos. (Guess the odd guy out there!)
It is called “thief” - an acronym for Temporal HIErarchical Forecasting. The idea is to take a seasonal time series, and compute all possible temporal aggregations that result in an integer number of observations per year. For example, a quarterly time series is aggregated to biannual and annual; while a monthly time series is aggregated to 2-monthly, quarterly, 4-monthly, biannual and annual.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seasonal periods</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/seasonal-periods/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 01:43:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/seasonal-periods/</guid>
      <description>I get questions about this almost every week. Here is an example from a recent comment on this blog:
 I have two large time series data. One is separated by seconds intervals and the other by minutes. The length of each time series is 180 days. I’m using R (3.1.1) for forecasting the data. I’d like to know the value of the “frequency” argument in the ts() function in R, for each data set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ABS seasonal adjustment update</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/abs-seasonal-adjustment-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 04:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/abs-seasonal-adjustment-3/</guid>
      <description>Since my last post on the seasonal adjustment problems at the Australian Bureau of Statistics, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working closely with people within the ABS to help them resolve the problems in time for tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s release of the October unemployment figures.
Now that the ABS has put out a statement about the problem, I thought it would be useful to explain the underlying methodology for those who are interested.The Labour Force Survey The unemployment rate is derived from the monthly Labour Force Survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explaining the ABS unemployment fluctuations</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/abs-seasonal-adjustment-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 07:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/abs-seasonal-adjustment-2/</guid>
      <description>Although the Guardian claimed yesterday that I had explained “what went wrong” in the July and August unemployment figures, I made no attempt to do so as I had no information about the problems. Instead, I just explained a little about the purpose of seasonal adjustment.
However, today I learned a little more about the ABS unemployment data problems, including what may be the explanation for the fluctuations. This explanation was offered by Westpac’s chief economist, Bill Evans (see here for a video of him explaining the issue).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seasonal adjustment in the news</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/abs-seasonal-adjustment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 05:50:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/abs-seasonal-adjustment/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s not every day that seasonal adjustment makes the front page of the newspapers, but it has today with the ABS saying that the recent seasonally adjusted unemployment data would be revised.
I was interviewed about the underlying concepts for the Guardian in this piece.
Further comment from me about users paying for the ABS data is here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>