<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Highest Density Regions on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/tags/highest-density-regions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Highest Density Regions on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 02:08:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/tags/highest-density-regions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Large-scale unusual time series detection</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/icdm2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 02:08:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/icdm2015/</guid>
      <description>It is becoming increasingly common for organizations to collect very large amounts of data over time, and to need to detect unusual or anomalous time series. For example, Yahoo has banks of mail servers that are monitored over time. Many measurements on server performance are collected every hour for each of thousands of servers. We wish to identify servers that are behaving unusually.
We compute a vector of features on each time series, measuring characteristics of the series.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improved interval estimation of long run response from a dynamic linear model: a highest density region approach</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/dlm-hdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2011 00:53:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/dlm-hdr/</guid>
      <description>This paper proposes a new method of interval estimation for the long run response (or elasticity) parameter from a general linear dynamic model. We employ the bias-corrected bootstrap, in which small sample biases associated with the parameter estimators are adjusted in two stages of the bootstrap. As a means of bias-correction, we use alternative analytic and bootstrap methods. To take atypical properties of the long run elasticity estimator into account, the highest density region (HDR) method is adopted for the construction of confidence intervals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory graphics for functional data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/interface2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 08:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/interface2010/</guid>
      <description>We survey some graphical tools for visualizing large sets of functional data represented by smooth curves. These graphical tools include the phase-plane plot, singular value decomposition plot, rainbow plot, functional variants of the bagplot and the highest density region boxplot. The latter two techniques utilize the first two robust principal component scores, Tukey&amp;rsquo;s halfspace location depth and highest density regions.
The computer code and datasets are collected in the rainbow package for R, which is available at the Comprehensive R Archive Network (CRAN).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rainbow plots, bagplots and boxplots for functional data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/rainbow-fda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 23:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/rainbow-fda/</guid>
      <description>We propose new tools for visualizing large numbers of functional data in the form of smooth curves or surfaces. The proposed tools include functional versions of the bagplot and boxplot, and make use of the first two robust principal component scores, Tukey&amp;rsquo;s data depth and highest density regions.
By-products of our graphical displays are outlier detection methods for functional data. We compare these new outlier detection methods with existing methods for detecting outliers in functional data and show that our methods are better able to identify the outliers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bagplots, boxplots and outlier detection for functional data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/fboxplot-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2008 03:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/fboxplot-talk/</guid>
      <description>Australian Statistics Conference. Melbourne, July 2008.  Where: First International Workshop on Functional and Operatorial Statistics, Toulouse Where : Australian Statistical Conference Melbourne, Australia Speakers: Professor Rob&amp;nbsp;J&amp;nbsp;Hyndman, Monash University &amp;amp; Han Lin Shang, Monash University  Abstract: We propose some new tools for visualizing functional data and for identifying functional outliers. The proposed tools make use of robust principal component analysis, data depth and highest density regions. We compare the proposed outlier detection methods with the existing “functional depth” method, and show that our methods have better performance on identifying outliers in French male age-specific mortality data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bagplots, boxplots and outlier detection for functional data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/bagplots-boxplots-and-outlier-detection-for-functional-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2008 03:10:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/bagplots-boxplots-and-outlier-detection-for-functional-data/</guid>
      <description>We propose some new tools for visualizing functional data and for identifying functional outliers. The proposed tools make use of robust principal component analysis, data depth and highest density regions. We compare the proposed outlier detection methods with the existing &amp;ldquo;functional depth&amp;rdquo; method, and show that our methods have better performance on identifying outliers in French male age-specific mortality data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half-life estimation based on the bias-corrected bootstrap: a highest density region approach</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/half-life-estimation-based-on-the-bias-corrected-bootstrap-a-highest-density-region-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2007 06:23:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/half-life-estimation-based-on-the-bias-corrected-bootstrap-a-highest-density-region-approach/</guid>
      <description>The half-life is defined as the number of periods required for the impulse response to a unit shock to a time series to dissipate by half. It is widely used as a measure of persistence, especially in international economics to quantify the degree of mean-reversion of the deviation from an international parity condition. Several studies have proposed bias-corrected point and interval estimation methods. However, they have found that the confidence intervals are rather uninformative with their upper bound being either extremely large or infinite.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>