<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Functional Data on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/tags/functional-data/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Functional Data on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/tags/functional-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Grouped functional time series forecasting: an application to age-specific mortality rates</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/grouped-functional-time-series-forecasting-an-application-to-age-specific-mortality-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/grouped-functional-time-series-forecasting-an-application-to-age-specific-mortality-rates/</guid>
      <description>Age-specific mortality rates are often disaggregated by different attributes, such as sex, state and ethnicity. Forecasting age-specific mortality rates at the national and sub-national levels plays an important role in developing social policy. However, independent forecasts of age-specific mortality rates at the sub-national levels may not add up to the forecasts at the national level. To address this issue, we consider the problem of reconciling age-specific mortality rate forecasts from the viewpoint of grouped univariate time series forecasting methods (Hyndman et al, 2011), and extend these methods to functional time series forecasting, where age is considered as a continuum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-term forecasts of age-specific participation rates with functional data models</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/participation-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 06:33:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/participation-rates/</guid>
      <description>Many countries have implemented social programs providing long-term financial or in-kind entitlements. These programs often focus on specific age-groups and consequently their expenditure streams are subject to demographic change. Given the strains already existing on public budgets, long-term forecasts are an increasingly important instrument to monitor the budgetary consequences of social programs. The expected development of the labour force is a key input to these forecasts. We suggest combining a functional data approach to age-profiles of labour market participation rates with information on education, marital status and other exogenous variables to improve long-term forecasts of labour supply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization of big time series data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/big-time-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 03:51:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/big-time-series/</guid>
      <description>Talk given to a joint meeting of the Statistical Society of Australia (Victorian branch) and the Melbourne Data Science Meetup Group.It is becoming increasingly common for organizations to collect very large amounts of data over time. Data visualization is essential for exploring and understanding structures and patterns, and to identify unusual observations. However, the sheer quantity of data available challenges current time series visualisation methods.
For example, Yahoo has banks of mail servers that are monitored over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Functional time series with applications in demography</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/fts-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 02:33:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/fts-berlin/</guid>
      <description>This is a short course given at Humboldt University, Berlin, 24-25 June 2014.
Venue: LvB Library, Room 401, Spandauerstr. 1, 10178 Berlin
Time: 24 June 2014, 09:30 - 12:30 and 14:00 - 17:00 25 June 2014, 09:30 - 11:30
Functional time series are curves that are observed sequentially in time, one curve being observed in each time period. In demography, examples include curves formed by annual death rates as a function of age, or annual fertility rates as a function of age.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-dimensional decomposition, smoothing and forecasting of sparse functional data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/ropes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2014 03:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/ropes/</guid>
      <description>We propose a new generic method ROPES (Regularized Optimization for Prediction and Estimation with Sparse data) for decomposing, smoothing and forecasting two-dimensional sparse data. In some ways, ROPES is similar to Ridge Regression, the LASSO, Principal Component Analysis (PCA) and Maximum-Margin Matrix Factorisation (MMMF). Using this new approach, we propose a practical method of forecasting mortality rates, as well as a new method for interpolating and extrapolating sparse longitudinal data. We also show how to calculate prediction intervals for the resulting estimates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common functional principal component models for mortality forecasting</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/cfpc-iwfos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2014 01:31:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/cfpc-iwfos/</guid>
      <description>We explore models for forecasting groups of functional time series data that exploit common features in the data. Our models involve fitting common (or partially common) functional principal component models and forecasting the coefficients using univariate time series methods. We illustrate our approach by forecasting age-specific mortality rates for males and females in Australia.
Slides for talk</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coherent mortality forecasting using functional time series</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/coherent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2013 05:12:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/coherent/</guid>
      <description>A talk given today at Macquarie University, Sydney.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coherent mortality forecasting: the product-ratio method with functional time series models</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/coherentfdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 07:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/coherentfdm/</guid>
      <description>When independence is assumed, forecasts of mortality for subpopulations are almost always divergent in the long term. We propose a method for coherent forecasting of mortality rates for two or more subpopulations, based on functional principal components models of simple and interpretable functions of rates. The product-ratio functional forecasting method models and forecasts the geometric mean of subpopulation rates and the ratio of subpopulation rates to product rates. Coherence is imposed by constraining the forecast ratio function through stationary time series models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasts of COPD mortality in Australia: 2006-2025</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/copdaustralia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2012 23:16:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/copdaustralia/</guid>
      <description>Background: Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) is currently the fifth leading cause of death in Australia, and there are marked differences in mortality trends between men and women. In this study, we have sought to model and forecast age related changes in COPD mortality over time for men and women separately over the period 2006–2025.
Methods: Annual COPD death rates in Australia from 1922 to 2005 for age groups (50–54, 55–59, 60–64, 65–69, 70–74, 75–79, 80–84, 85+) were used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Point and interval forecasts of mortality rates and life expectancy: a comparison of ten principal component methods</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/mortality-forecast-comparison/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2011 23:19:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/mortality-forecast-comparison/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: Using the age- and sex-specific data of 14 developed countries, we compare the point and interval forecast accuracy and bias of ten principal component methods for forecasting mortality rates and life expectancy. The ten methods are variants and extensions of the Lee-Carter method. Based on one-step forecast errors, the weighted Hyndman-Ullah method provides the most accurate point forecasts of mortality rates and the Lee-Miller method is the least biased. For the accuracy and bias of life expectancy, the weighted Hyndman-Ullah method performs the best for female mortality and the Lee-Miller method for male mortality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonparametric time series forecasting with dynamic updating</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/dynamic-updating/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 01:12:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/dynamic-updating/</guid>
      <description>Abstract We present a nonparametric method to forecast a seasonal univariate time series, and propose four dynamic updating methods to improve point forecast accuracy. Our methods consider a seasonal univariate time series as a functional time series. We propose first to reduce the dimensionality by applying functional principal component analysis to the historical observations, and then to use univariate time series forecasting and functional principal component regression techniques. When data in the most recent year are partially observed, we improve point forecast accuracy using dynamic updating methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demographic forecasting using functional data analysis</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/demographic-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 11:33:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/demographic-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>University of Wollongong, 8 September 2010. Statistical Society of Australia, Victorian Branch, 28 September 2010. Updated version. September 2012.  Abstract:
Functional time series are curves that are observed sequentially in time. In demography, such data arise as the curves formed by annual death rates as a function of age or annual fertility rates as a function of age. I will discuss methods for describing, modelling and forecasting such functional time series data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory graphics for functional data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/interface2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 08:33:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/interface2010/</guid>
      <description>We survey some graphical tools for visualizing large sets of functional data represented by smooth curves. These graphical tools include the phase-plane plot, singular value decomposition plot, rainbow plot, functional variants of the bagplot and the highest density region boxplot. The latter two techniques utilize the first two robust principal component scores, Tukey&amp;rsquo;s halfspace location depth and highest density regions.
The computer code and datasets are collected in the rainbow package for R, which is available at the Comprehensive R Archive Network (CRAN).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coherent functional forecasts of mortality rates and life expectancy</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/isf2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2010 04:20:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/isf2010/</guid>
      <description>Talk to be given at the International Symposium on Forecasting, San Diego, 20-23 June 2010.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting age-related changes in breast cancer mortality among white and black US women</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/brca-bwus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2010 01:14:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/brca-bwus/</guid>
      <description>The disparity in breast cancer mortality rates among white and black US women is widening, with higher mortality rates among black women. We apply functional time series models on age-specific breast cancer mortality rates for each group of women, and forecast their mortality curves using exponential smoothing state-space models with damping. The data were obtained from the Surveillance, Epidemiology and End Results (SEER) program of the US. Mortality data were obtained from the National Centre for Health Statistics (NCHS) available on the SEER*Stat database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rainbow plots, bagplots and boxplots for functional data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/rainbow-fda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2010 23:17:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/rainbow-fda/</guid>
      <description>We propose new tools for visualizing large numbers of functional data in the form of smooth curves or surfaces. The proposed tools include functional versions of the bagplot and boxplot, and make use of the first two robust principal component scores, Tukey&amp;rsquo;s data depth and highest density regions.
By-products of our graphical displays are outlier detection methods for functional data. We compare these new outlier detection methods with existing methods for detecting outliers in functional data and show that our methods are better able to identify the outliers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using functional data analysis models to estimate future time trends of age-specific breast cancer mortality for the United States and England-Wales</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/brca-usew/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2010 23:14:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/brca-usew/</guid>
      <description>Background: Mortality/incidence predictions are used for planning public health resources and need to accurately reflect age-related changes through time. We present a new forecasting model to estimate future trends in age-related breast cancer mortality for the United States and England-Wales.
Material and methods: We use functional data analysis techniques to model breast cancer mortality-age relationships in the United States from 1950 to 2001 and England-Wales from 1950 to 2003, and estimate 20-year predictions using a new forecasting method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting functional time series</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/forecasting-functional-time-series-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2009 23:12:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/forecasting-functional-time-series-2/</guid>
      <description>We propose forecasting functional time series using weighted functional principal component regression and weighted functional partial least squares regression. These approaches allow for smooth functions, assign higher weights to more recent data, and provide a modeling scheme that is easily adapted to allow for constraints and other information. We illustrate our approaches using age-specific French female mortality rates from 1816 to 2006 and age-specific Australian fertility rates from 1921 to 2006, and show that these weighted methods improve forecast accuracy in comparison to their unweighted counterparts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonparametric time series forecasting with dynamic updating</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/dynamic-updating1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2009 23:46:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/dynamic-updating1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic population forecasts using functional data models for mortality, fertility and migration</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/stochastic-population-forecasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2008 05:33:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/stochastic-population-forecasts/</guid>
      <description>Age-sex-specific population forecasts are derived through stochastic population renewal using forecasts of mortality, fertility and net migration. Functional data models with time series coefficients are used to model age-specific mortality and fertility rates. As detailed migration data are lacking, net migration by age and sex is estimated as the difference between historic annual population data and successive populations one year ahead derived from a projection using fertility and mortality data. This estimate, which includes error, is also modeled using a functional data model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bagplots, boxplots and outlier detection for functional data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/fboxplot-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2008 03:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/fboxplot-talk/</guid>
      <description>Australian Statistics Conference. Melbourne, July 2008.  Where: First International Workshop on Functional and Operatorial Statistics, Toulouse Where : Australian Statistical Conference Melbourne, Australia Speakers: Professor Rob&amp;nbsp;J&amp;nbsp;Hyndman, Monash University &amp;amp; Han Lin Shang, Monash University  Abstract: We propose some new tools for visualizing functional data and for identifying functional outliers. The proposed tools make use of robust principal component analysis, data depth and highest density regions. We compare the proposed outlier detection methods with the existing “functional depth” method, and show that our methods have better performance on identifying outliers in French male age-specific mortality data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bagplots, boxplots and outlier detection for functional data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/bagplots-boxplots-and-outlier-detection-for-functional-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2008 03:10:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/bagplots-boxplots-and-outlier-detection-for-functional-data/</guid>
      <description>We propose some new tools for visualizing functional data and for identifying functional outliers. The proposed tools make use of robust principal component analysis, data depth and highest density regions. We compare the proposed outlier detection methods with the existing &amp;ldquo;functional depth&amp;rdquo; method, and show that our methods have better performance on identifying outliers in French male age-specific mortality data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting functional time series</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/forecasting-functional-time-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2008 07:56:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/forecasting-functional-time-series/</guid>
      <description>Where: Australian Frontiers of Science  Abstract: Functional time series are curves that are observed sequentially in time. For example, the curve of death rate as a function of age is observed annually. Yield curves in finance (essentially interest rates as a function of the term of investment) are observed each week or each day. Electricity consumption as a function of temperature is observed every month. These are all high dimensional functional data, indexed by time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robust forecasting of mortality and fertility rates: a functional data approach</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/funcfor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2007 05:16:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/funcfor/</guid>
      <description>Abstract: A new method is proposed for forecasting age-specific mortality and fertility rates observed over time. This approach allows for smooth functions of age, is robust for outlying years due to wars and epidemics, and provides a modelling framework that is easily adapted to allow for constraints and other information. Ideas from functional data analysis, nonparametric smoothing and robust statistics are combined to form a methodology that is widely applicable to any functional time series data observed discretely and possibly with error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic population forecasts using functional data models</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/stochastic-population/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2007 08:14:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/seminars/stochastic-population/</guid>
      <description>When: 12.00noon, Thu 22nd February 2007 Where: Room 213, Richard Berry Building, The University of Melbourne When: 2.30pm, Fri 1 June 2007 Where: Room 457, Menzies Building, Monash University (Clayton)  Abstract: I will present a new approach to age-specific forecasting of population based on separate forecasts of mortality, fertility and net migration. Functional data models with time series coefficients will be used to model mortality and fertility rates, and net migration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecasting age-specific breast cancer mortality using functional data models</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/forecasting-age-specific-breast-cancer-mortality-using-functional-data-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2007 05:24:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/forecasting-age-specific-breast-cancer-mortality-using-functional-data-models/</guid>
      <description>Accurate estimates of future age-specific incidence and mortality are critical for allocation of resources to breast cancer control programs and evaluation of screening programs. The purpose of this study is to apply functional data analysis techniques to model age-specific breast cancer mortality time trends, and forecast entire age-specific mortality functions using a state-space approach. We use annual unadjusted breast cancer mortality rates in Australia, from 1921 to 2001 in five year age groups (45 to 85+).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lee-Carter mortality forecasting: a multi-country comparison of variants and extensions</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/lee-carter-mortality-forecasting-a-multi-country-comparison-of-variants-and-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2006 04:24:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/lee-carter-mortality-forecasting-a-multi-country-comparison-of-variants-and-extensions/</guid>
      <description>We compare the short- to medium- term accuracy of five variants or extensions of the Lee-Carter method for mortality forecasting. These include the original Lee-Carter, the Lee-Miller and Booth-Maindonald-Smith variants, and the more flexible Hyndman-Ullah and De Jong-Tickle extensions. These methods are compared by applying them to sex-specific populations of 10 developed countries using data for 1986-2000 for evaluation. All variants and extensions are more accurate than the original Lee-Carter method for forecasting log death rates, by up to 61%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robust forecasting of mortality and fertility rates: a functional data approach</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/robust-forecasting-of-mortality-and-fertility-rates-a-functional-data-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2005 01:35:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/robust-forecasting-of-mortality-and-fertility-rates-a-functional-data-approach/</guid>
      <description>We propose a new method for forecasting age-specific mortality and fertility rates observed over time. We combine ideas from functional data analysis, nonparametric smoothing and robust statistics to form a methodology that is widely applicable to any functional time series data, and age-specific mortality and fertility in particular. Our approach provides a modelling framework that is easily adapted to allow for constraints and other information. The model used can be considered a generalization of the Lee-Carter model commonly used in mortality and fertility forecasting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>