<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Econometrics on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/tags/econometrics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Econometrics on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/tags/econometrics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Macroeconomic forecasting for Australia using a large number of predictors</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/ausmacrofcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/ausmacrofcast/</guid>
      <description>A popular approach to forecasting macroeconomic variables is to utilize a large number of predictors. Several regularization and shrinkage methods can be used to exploit such high-dimensional datasets, and have been shown to improve forecast accuracy for the US economy. To assess whether similar results hold for economies with different characteristics, an Australian dataset containing observations on 151 aggregate and disaggregate economic series as well as 185 international variables, is introduced.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Australian Macro Database: An online resource for macroeconomic research in Australia</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/ausmacrodata/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2017 05:26:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/ausmacrodata/</guid>
      <description>A website that encourages and facilities the use of quantitative, publicly available Australian macroeconomic data is introduced. The Australian Macro Database hosted at ausmacrodata.org provides a user friendly front end for searching among over 40000 economic variables, sourced from the Australian Bureau of Statistics and the Reserve Bank of Australia. The search box, tags and categories used to facilitate data retrieval, are described in detail. Known issues with the website and future plans are discussed in the conclusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian rank selection in multivariate regression</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/bayesian-rank-selection-in-multivariate-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/bayesian-rank-selection-in-multivariate-regression/</guid>
      <description>Estimating the rank of the coefficient matrix is a major challenge in multivariate regression, including vector autoregression (VAR). In this paper, we develop a novel fully Bayesian approach that allows for rank estimation. The key to our approach is reparameterizing the coefficient matrix using its singular value decomposition and conducting Bayesian inference on the decomposed parameters. By implementing a stochastic search variable selection on the singular values of the coefficient matrix, the ultimate selected rank can be identified as the number of nonzero singular values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long-term forecasts of age-specific participation rates with functional data models</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/participation-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 06:33:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/participation-rates/</guid>
      <description>Many countries have implemented social programs providing long-term financial or in-kind entitlements. These programs often focus on specific age-groups and consequently their expenditure streams are subject to demographic change. Given the strains already existing on public budgets, long-term forecasts are an increasingly important instrument to monitor the budgetary consequences of social programs. The expected development of the labour force is a key input to these forecasts. We suggest combining a functional data approach to age-profiles of labour market participation rates with information on education, marital status and other exogenous variables to improve long-term forecasts of labour supply.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The price elasticity of electricity demand in South Australia</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/electricity-price-elasticity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2011 00:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/electricity-price-elasticity/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, the price elasticity of electricity demand, representing the sensitivity of customer demand to the price of electricity, has been estimated for South Australia. We first undertake a review of the scholarly literature regarding electricity price elasticity for different regions and systems. Then we perform an empirical evaluation of the historic South Australian price elasticity, focussing on the relationship between price and demand quantiles at each half-hour of the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multivariate innovations state space Beveridge-Nelson decomposition</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/vists-beveridge-nelson/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 23:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/vists-beveridge-nelson/</guid>
      <description>The Beveridge-Nelson vector innovations structural time series framework is a new formulation that decomposes a set of variables into their permanent and transitory components. The proposed framework is flexible, modelling inter-series relationships and common features in a simple manner. In particular, it is shown that this new specification is simpler than conventional state space and cointegration approaches. The approach is illustrated using a trivariate data set comprising the GDP of Australia, the USA and the UK.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using R to Teach Econometrics</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/using-r-to-teach-econometrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2002 03:25:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/using-r-to-teach-econometrics/</guid>
      <description>R, an open-source programming environment for data analysis and graphics, has in only a decade grown to become a de-facto standard for statistical analysis against which many popular commercial programs may be measured. The use of R for the teaching of econometric methods is appealing. It provides cutting-edge statistical methods which are, by R&amp;rsquo;s open-source nature, available immediately. The software is stable, available at no cost, and exists for a number of platforms, including various flavors of Unix and Linux, Windows (9x/NT/2000), and the MacOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book review of &#34;Nonparametric econometrics&#34; (Pagan and Ullah, 1999)</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/pagan-and-ullah-nonparametric-econometrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2000 00:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/pagan-and-ullah-nonparametric-econometrics/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The pricing and trading of options using a hybrid neural network model with historical volatility</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/the-pricing-and-trading-of-options-using-a-hybrid-neural-network-model-with-historical-volatility/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 1997 02:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/publications/the-pricing-and-trading-of-options-using-a-hybrid-neural-network-model-with-historical-volatility/</guid>
      <description>(Later known as Journal of Computational Intelligence in Finance)
The residuals between conventional option pricing models and market prices have persistent patterns or biases. The &amp;ldquo;hybrid&amp;rdquo; method models the residuals using an artificial neural network. The pricing accuracy of the hybrid method is demonstrated on real data using the Australian All Ordinaries Share Price Index options on futures and is compared with all major competing conventional models. The hybrid method is found to be both statistically and economically superior to the conventional models alone.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>