<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jobs on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/categories/jobs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jobs on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/categories/jobs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Come and work with me</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/acems-postdoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/acems-postdoc/</guid>
      <description>I have funding for a new post-doctoral research fellow, on a 2-year contract, to work with me and Professor Kate Smith-Miles on analysing large collections of time series data. We are particularly seeking someone with a PhD in computational statistics or statistical machine learning.
Desirable characteristics:
 Experience with time series data. Experience with R package development. Familiarity with reproducible research practices (e.g., git, rmarkdown, etc). A background in machine learning or computational statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking for a new research assistant</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ra-wanted/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 13:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ra-wanted/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently looking for a new research assistant to help (primarily) with some modelling and R coding as part of a project on forecasting mobile phone sales. The position is likely to last for about 6&amp;ndash;9 months, and will be casual.
 Requirements  Based in Melbourne. I&amp;rsquo;d rather not communicate remotely. Able to work at least 20 hours per week. Some of that can be from home if necessary, but you do need to be at Monash University (Clayton campus) at least some of the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic vacancies at Monash</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/jobs-may-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/jobs-may-2017/</guid>
      <description>We are hiring again, at all academic levels. While all fields of specialisation within econometrics and statistics are open, expertise in any of Business Analytics, Data Science, Applied Econometrics and Actuarial Science is particularly encouraged.
All positions are full-time and continuing (i.e., tenured after a probation period).
Applications close at 11:55pm AEST, Friday 30 June 2017.
Please direct initial questions to Liam Mahon.
Lecturer  Suitable for someone just completing a PhD or a post-doc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Come to Melbourne, even if not to Monash</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/unimelb-prof-datascience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 08:00:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/unimelb-prof-datascience/</guid>
      <description>The University of Melbourne is advertising for a &amp;ldquo;Professor in Statistics (Data Science)&amp;rdquo;. Melbourne (the city) is fast becoming a vibrant centre for data science and applied statistics, with more than 4700 people signed up for the Data Science Meetup Group, a thriving start-up scene, the group at Monash Business School (including Di Cook and me), and the Monash Centre for Data Science (including Geoff Webb and Wray Buntine). Not to mention that Melbourne is a wonderful place to live, having won the &amp;ldquo;World&amp;rsquo;s most liveable city&amp;rdquo; award from the Economist for the last 6 years in a row.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics positions available at Monash University</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/jobs2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 23:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/jobs2017/</guid>
      <description>We are hiring again, and looking for people in statistics, econometrics and related fields (such as actuarial science, machine learning, and business analytics). We have a strong business analytics group (with particular expertise in data visualization, machine learning, statistical computing, R, and forecasting), and it would be great to see it grow. The official advert follows.
The Department of Econometrics and Business Statistics at Monash Business School in Melbourne, Australia, invites applications for full-time tenure-track positions at the Senior Lecturer level (equivalent to North American/European Assistant Professor with some post-doctoral academic experience) and Associate Professor level.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSA helping you find a job</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ssa-jobs-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 02:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ssa-jobs-board/</guid>
      <description>One of the great services of the Statistical Society of Australia is an excellent jobs board advertising available jobs for statisticians, data analysts, data scientists, etc. Jobs can be filtered by industry, location and job function.
Today the SSA announced a new service to job seekers: CV/Resume Critique. As a job seeker, registered on the SSA Job Board, you now have the option to request a free, confidential CV/resume evaluation from an expert and writer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting a career in data science</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/starting-a-career-in-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2015 04:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/starting-a-career-in-data-science/</guid>
      <description>I received this email from one of my undergraduate students:
 I&amp;rsquo;m writing to you asking for advice on how to start a career in Data Science. Other professions seem a bit more straight forward, in that accountants for example simply look for Internships and ways into companies from there. From my understanding, the nature of careers in data science seem to be on a project-to-project basis. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how to get my foot stuck in the door.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The hidden benefits of open-source software</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/oss-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 23:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/oss-benefits/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been having discussions with colleagues and university administration about the best way for universities to manage home-grown software.
The traditional business model for software is that we build software and sell it to everyone willing to pay. Very often, that leads to a software company spin-off that has little or nothing to do with the university that nurtured the development. Think MATLAB, S-Plus, Minitab, SAS and SPSS, all of which grew out of universities or research institutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ODI looking for young postgrad statisticians</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/odi-fellowships/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 00:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/odi-fellowships/</guid>
      <description>The Overseas Development Institute Fellowship Scheme sends young postgraduate statisticians (and economists) to work in the public sectors of developing countries in Africa, the Caribbean and the Pacific on two-year contracts. This is a great way to develop skills and gain experience working within a developing country&amp;rsquo;s government. And you get to live in a fascinating place!
The application process for the 2016-2018 Fellowship Scheme is now open. Students are advised to apply before 17 December 2015 for a chance to be part of the ODI Fellowship Scheme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New job opportunities at Monash</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/maxima-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2015 05:21:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/maxima-jobs/</guid>
      <description>We are now advertising for various positions in applied statistics, operations research and applied mathematics.
Click here for details These jobs are with MAXIMA (the Monash Academy for Cross &amp;amp; Interdisciplinary Mathematical Applications).
Please do not send any questions to me (I won&amp;rsquo;t answer). Click above and fol­low the instructions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ABS seasonal adjustment update</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/abs-seasonal-adjustment-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 04:56:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/abs-seasonal-adjustment-3/</guid>
      <description>Since my last post on the seasonal adjustment problems at the Australian Bureau of Statistics, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working closely with people within the ABS to help them resolve the problems in time for tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s release of the October unemployment figures.
Now that the ABS has put out a statement about the problem, I thought it would be useful to explain the underlying methodology for those who are interested.The Labour Force Survey The unemployment rate is derived from the monthly Labour Force Survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jobs at Amazon</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/jobs-at-amazon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 02:13:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/jobs-at-amazon/</guid>
      <description>I do not normally post job adverts, but this was very specifically targeted to &amp;ldquo;applied time series candidates&amp;rdquo; so I thought it might be of sufficient interest to readers of this blog.Here is an excerpt from an email I received from someone at Amazon:
 Amazon is aggressively recruiting in the data sciences, and we have found that applied economists compare quite favorably with the machine learning specialists and statisticians that are sometimes recruited for such roles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explaining the ABS unemployment fluctuations</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/abs-seasonal-adjustment-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 07:06:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/abs-seasonal-adjustment-2/</guid>
      <description>Although the Guardian claimed yesterday that I had explained “what went wrong” in the July and August unemployment figures, I made no attempt to do so as I had no information about the problems. Instead, I just explained a little about the purpose of seasonal adjustment.
However, today I learned a little more about the ABS unemployment data problems, including what may be the explanation for the fluctuations. This explanation was offered by Westpac’s chief economist, Bill Evans (see here for a video of him explaining the issue).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seasonal adjustment in the news</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/abs-seasonal-adjustment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 05:50:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/abs-seasonal-adjustment/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s not every day that seasonal adjustment makes the front page of the newspapers, but it has today with the ABS saying that the recent seasonally adjusted unemployment data would be revised.
I was interviewed about the underlying concepts for the Guardian in this piece.
Further comment from me about users paying for the ABS data is here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect with local employers</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/connect-with-local-employers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 23:07:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/connect-with-local-employers/</guid>
      <description>I keep telling students that there are lots of jobs in data science (including statistics), and they often tell me they can&amp;rsquo;t find them advertised. As usual, you do have to do some networking, and one of the best ways of doing it is via a Data Science Meetup. Many cities now have them including Melbourne, Sydney, London, etc. It is the perfect opportunity to meet with local employers, many of which are hiring due to the huge expansion in the use of data analysis in business (aka business analytics).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What not to say in a job interview</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/what-not-to-say-in-a-job-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 11:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/what-not-to-say-in-a-job-interview/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve interviewed a few people for jobs at Monash University, and there&amp;rsquo;s always someone who comes out with something surprising. Here are some real examples.For a post-doctoral research position:
 Q: What would you say were your major weaknesses?
 A: I don&amp;rsquo;t have any.
 Q: Really? You can&amp;rsquo;t think of anything that you could work on, new skills you could develop, anything at all that you might be able to improve?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data science market places</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/marketplaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 02:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/marketplaces/</guid>
      <description>Some new websites are being established offering &amp;ldquo;market places&amp;rdquo; for data science. Two I&amp;rsquo;ve come across recently are Experfy and SnapAnalytx.Experfy provides a way for companies to find statisticians and other data scientists, either for short-term consultancies, or to fill full-time positions. They describe their &amp;ldquo;providers&amp;rdquo; as &amp;ldquo;Data Engineers, Data Scientists, Data Mining Experts, Data Analyst/Modelers, Big Data Solutions Architects, Visualization Designers, Statisticians, Applied Physicists, Mathematicians, Econometricians and Bioinformaticians.&amp;rdquo; Data scientists can sign up as &amp;ldquo;Providers&amp;rdquo;, companies can sign up as &amp;ldquo;Clients&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions on the business analytics jobs</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/business-analytics-jobs-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2014 02:27:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/business-analytics-jobs-questions/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve received a few questions on the business analytics jobs advertised last week. I think it is best if I answer them here so other potential candidates can have the same information. I will add to this post if I receive more questions.1. What are your expectations in terms of outputs (KPIs)? Typically, a person at Level B (Lecturer) in our department would be producing at least one refereed article in a good scholarly journal per year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New jobs in business analytics at Monash</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/monash-business-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2014 12:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/monash-business-analytics/</guid>
      <description>We have an exciting new initiative at Monash University with some new positions in business analytics. This is part of a plan to strengthen our research and teaching in the data science/computational statistics area. We are hoping to make multiple appointments, at junior and senior levels. These are five-year appointments, but we hope that the positions will continue after that if we can secure suitable funding.What is business analytics? You can think of &amp;ldquo;business analytics&amp;rdquo; as the application of data analysis to business problems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Job at Center for Open Science</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/cos-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 22:36:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/cos-job/</guid>
      <description>This looks like an interesting job.
 Dear Dr. Hyndman,
I write from the Center for Open Science, a non-profit organization based in Charlottesville, Virginia in the United States, which is dedicated to improving the alignment between scientific values and scientific practices. We are dedicated to open source and open science.
We are reaching out to you to find out if you know anyone who might be interested in our Statistical and Methodological Consultant position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking for a new post-doc</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/postdoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 02:50:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/postdoc/</guid>
      <description>We are looking for a new post-doctoral research fellow to work on the project &amp;ldquo;Macroeconomic Forecasting in a Big Data World&amp;rdquo;. Details are given at the link below
jobs.monash.edu.au/jobDetails.asp?sJobIDs=519824
This is a two year position, funded by the Australian Research Council, and working with me, George Athanasopoulos, Farshid Vahid and Anastasios Panagiotelis. We are looking for someone with a PhD in econometrics, statistics or machine learning, who is well-trained in computationally intensive methods, and who has a background in at least one of time series analysis, macroeconomic modelling, or Bayesian econometrics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three jobs at Monash</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/three-jobs-at-monash/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2013 04:02:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/three-jobs-at-monash/</guid>
      <description>We are currently advertising for three academic positions, suitable for recent PhD graduates.
Lecturer (Applied Statistics or Operations Research)  Five-year position with MAXIMA and the School of Mathematical Sciences
 Two positions available.
 Applications close 31 October.
 More information.
  Lecturer (Econometrics/Business Statistics)  Continuing position with the Department of Econometrics and Business Statistics
 Applications close 31 January 2014.
 More information.
  Please don&amp;rsquo;t send any questions to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A LaTeX template for a CV</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2010 05:00:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/cv/</guid>
      <description>Every researcher needs a Curriculum Vitae (Latin for &amp;ldquo;course of life&amp;rdquo;) or CV. You will need it for job applications, for annual performance appraisal, and just for keeping track of your publications. A CV typically contains lists of achievements including qualifications, publications, presentations, awards, plus teaching experience.
I&amp;rsquo;ve created a LaTeX style for a CV to make it easy to produce something that looks good and is easy to maintain. You will need an up-to-date implementation of LaTeX because I&amp;rsquo;m using the wonderful biblatex package (more on that in another post) which has only just become available as part of MikTeX and TeXLive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Job advertisements</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/job-advertisements/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2010 01:41:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/job-advertisements/</guid>
      <description>Employers often contact me asking how to find a good statistician, econometrician or forecaster for their organization. Students also ask me how to go about finding a job when they finish their degree. This post is for both groups, hopefully making it easier for them to pair up appropriately.
First, the mainstream media outlets are not usually good places to advertise. It seems that few people read printed newspapers anymore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to do when the PhD is finished?</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2010 06:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/jobs/</guid>
      <description>So you&amp;rsquo;re wondering what to do once your PhD is finally completed? First, take a holiday. Completing a PhD is an intense and draining exercise, and you should take some time to refresh.
Then you need to decide what career path you prefer. In statistics, there are three choices: the academic route, the semi-academic route and the business route.
Academic route Most PhD students would like an academic job. In fact, I think all of my PhD students have rather fancied my job!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>