<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Graphics on Rob J Hyndman</title>
    <link>https://robjhyndman.com/categories/graphics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Graphics on Rob J Hyndman</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 14:00:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://robjhyndman.com/categories/graphics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>forecast 8.0</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/forecast8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2017 14:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/forecast8/</guid>
      <description>In what is now a roughly annual event, the forecast package has been updated on CRAN with a new version, this time 8.0.
A few of the more important new features are described below.
Check residuals A common task when building forecasting models is to check that the residuals satisfy some assumptions (that they are uncorrelated, normally distributed, etc.). The new function checkresiduals makes this very easy: it produces a time plot, an ACF, a histogram with super-imposed normal curve, and does a Ljung-Box test on the residuals with appropriate number of lags and degrees of freedom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eindhoven seminar on time series visualization</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/eindhoven-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 08:34:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/eindhoven-seminar/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently in the Netherlands for a few weeks, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be giving a seminar at the Data Science Centre in Eindhoven next Wednesday afternoon on &amp;ldquo;Visualization of big time series data&amp;rdquo;. Details follow.Date: 5 October 2016 Time: 12.30-13.30 Venue: Filmhuis, De Zwarte Doos, 2 Den Dolech, Eindhoven
Registration is required but free. Please book here.
Abstract:
It is becoming increasingly common for organizations to collect very large amounts of data over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R package forecast v7.2 now on CRAN</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/forecast-v7-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 10:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/forecast-v7-2/</guid>
      <description>I’ve pushed a minor update to the forecast package to CRAN. Some highlights are listed here.
Plotting time series with ggplot2 You can now facet a time series plot like this:
library(forecast) library(ggplot2) lungDeaths &amp;lt;- cbind(mdeaths, fdeaths) autoplot(lungDeaths, facets=TRUE) So autoplot.mts now behaves similarly to plot.mts
 Multi-step fitted values The fitted function has a new argument h to allow computation of in-sample fitted values of more than one-step-ahead. In time series, fitted values are defined as the one-step-forecasts of the data used in training a model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forecast v7 (part 2)</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/forecast7-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 07:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/forecast7-part-2/</guid>
      <description>As mentioned in my previous post on the forecast package v7, the most visible feature was the introduction of ggplot2 graphics. This post briefly summarizes the remaining new features of forecast v7. library(forecast) library(ggplot2) tslm rewritten The tslm function is designed to fit linear models to time series data. It is intended to approximately mimic lm (and calls lm to do the estimation), but to package the output to remember the ts attributes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explore Australian Elections Data with R</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/eechidna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2016 04:07:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/eechidna/</guid>
      <description>This is a guest post by my colleague Professor Di Cook, cross-posted from her Visiphilia blog. Di and I are two of the authors of the new eechidna package for R, now on CRAN.The eechidna package has just been posted on CRAN, in time for the longest election campaign in Australia since the 1950s. The next Federal election scheduled for 2nd July was announced a few weeks ago. A little before this a handful of academics met at the first ever Australian ROpenSci Unnconference at the Microsoft headquarters in Brisbane in an event primarily organised by students at the Queensland University of Technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>forecast v7 and ggplot2 graphics</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/forecast7-ggplot2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2016 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/forecast7-ggplot2/</guid>
      <description>Version 7 of the forecast package was released on CRAN about a month ago, but I’m only just getting around to posting about the new features.
The most visible feature was the introduction of ggplot2 graphics. I first wrote the forecast package before ggplot2 existed, and so only base graphics were available. But I figured it was time to modernize and use the nice features available from ggplot2. The following examples illustrate the main new graphical functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting overlapping prediction intervals</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/overlappingpi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2016 10:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/overlappingpi/</guid>
      <description>I often see figures with two sets of prediction intervals plotted on the same graph using different line types to distinguish them. The results are almost always unreadable. A better way to do this is to use semi-transparent shaded regions. Here is an example showing two sets of forecasts for the Nile River flow.
library(forecast) f1 = forecast(auto.arima(Nile, lambda=0), h=20, level=95) f2 = forecast(ets(Nile), h=20, level=95) plot(f1, shadecol=rgb(0,0,1,.4), flwd=1, main=&amp;quot;Forecasts of Nile River flow&amp;quot;, xlab=&amp;quot;Year&amp;quot;, ylab=&amp;quot;Billions of cubic metres&amp;quot;) polygon(c(time(f2$mean),rev(time(f2$mean))), c(f2$lower,rev(f2$upper)), col=rgb(1,0,0,.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematical annotations on R plots</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex2exp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 07:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex2exp/</guid>
      <description>I’ve always struggled with using plotmath via the expression function in R for adding mathematical notation to axes or legends. For some reason, the most obvious way to write something never seems to work for me and I end up using trial and error in a loop with far too many iterations.
So I am very happy to see the new latex2exp package available which translates LaTeX expressions into a form suitable for R graphs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Murphy diagrams in R</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/murphy-diagrams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2015 07:57:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/murphy-diagrams/</guid>
      <description>At the recent International Symposium on Forecasting, held in Riverside, California, Tillman Gneiting gave a great talk on “Evaluating forecasts: why proper scoring rules and consistent scoring functions matter”. It will be the subject of an IJF invited paper in due course.
One of the things he talked about was the “Murphy diagram” for comparing forecasts, as proposed in Ehm et al (2015). Here’s how it works for comparing mean forecasts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical modelling and analysis of big data</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/bigdata2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2015 23:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/bigdata2015/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently attending the one day workshop on this topic at QUT in Brisbane. This morning I spoke on &amp;ldquo;Visualizing and forecasting big time series data&amp;rdquo;. My slides are here.
OVERVIEW Big data is now endemic in business, industry, government, environmental management, medical science, social research and so on. One of the commensurate challenges is how to effectively model and analyse these data.
This workshop will bring together national and international experts in statistical modelling and analysis of big data, to share their experiences, approaches and opinions about future directions in this field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seminars in Taiwan</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/seminars-in-taiwan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2015 09:33:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/seminars-in-taiwan/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently visiting Taiwan and I&amp;rsquo;m giving two seminars while I&amp;rsquo;m here &amp;mdash; one at the National Tsing Hua University in Hsinchu, and the other at Academia Sinica in Taipei. Details are below for those who might be nearby.Automatic Time Series Forecasting College of Technology Management, Institute of Service Science, National Tsing Hua University, Hsinchu 時間及地點：2015.1.7 (Wed.) 5pm @ TSMC building, 6F, room 622. 台積館6F孫運璿紀念中心 Many applications require a large number of time series to be forecast completely automatically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Di Cook is moving to Monash</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/di-cook-is-moving-to-monash/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2014 05:29:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/di-cook-is-moving-to-monash/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m delighted that Professor Dianne Cook will be joining Monash University in July 2015 as a Professor of Business Analytics. Di is an Australian who has worked in the US for the past 25 years, mostly at Iowa State University. She is moving back to Australia and joining the Department of Econometrics and Business Statistics in the Monash Business School, as part of our initiative in Business Analytics.
Di is a world leader in data visu­al­iza­tion, and is well-​​known for her work on inter­ac­tive graph­ics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization of probabilistic forecasts</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/visualization-of-probabilistic-forecasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 06:40:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/visualization-of-probabilistic-forecasts/</guid>
      <description>This week my research group discussed Adrian Raftery’s recent paper on “Use and Communication of Probabilistic Forecasts” which provides a fascinating but brief survey of some of his work on modelling and communicating uncertain futures. Coincidentally, today I was also sent a copy of David Spiegelhalter’s paper on “Visualizing Uncertainty About the Future”. Both are well-worth reading.
It made me think about my own efforts to communicate future uncertainty through graphics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new candidate for worst figure</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/worst-figure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 05:03:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/worst-figure/</guid>
      <description>Today I read a paper that had been submitted to the IJF which included the following figure

along with several similar plots. (Click for a larger version.) I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen anything this bad for a long time. In fact, I think I would find it very difficult to reproduce using R, or even Excel (which is particularly adept at bad graphics).
A few years ago I produced &amp;ldquo;Twenty rules for good graphics&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visit of Di Cook</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/visit-of-di-cook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2014 23:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/visit-of-di-cook/</guid>
      <description>Next week, Professor Di Cook from Iowa State University is visiting my research group at Monash University. Di is a world leader in data visualization, and is especially well-known for her work on interactive graphics and the XGobi and GGobi software. See her book with Deb Swayne for details.
For those wanting to hear her speak, read on.Research seminar She will be giving a seminar at 2pm on Monday 18 August at the Monash Clayton campus (Rm E457, Menzies Building 11).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on UseR! 2013</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/user2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2013 22:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/user2013/</guid>
      <description>This week I&amp;rsquo;ve been at the R Users conference in Albacete, Spain. These conferences are a little unusual in that they are not really about research, unlike most conferences I attend. They provide a place for people to discuss and exchange ideas on how R can be used.
Here are some thoughts and highlights of the conference, in no particular order. Håvard Rue spoke on Bayesian computing with INLA and the R-INLA package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing white space around R figures</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/crop-r-figures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2013 00:22:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/crop-r-figures/</guid>
      <description>When I want to insert figures generated in R into a LaTeX document, it looks better if I first remove the white space around the figure. Unfortunately, R does not make this easy as the graphs are generated to look good on a screen, not in a document.
There are two things that can be done to fix this problem.First, you can reduce the white space generated by R. I use the following function when saving figures in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX loops</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex-loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2012 01:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/latex-loops/</guid>
      <description>Today I was writing a report which included 20 figures, with the names demandplot1.pdf, demandplot2.pdf, &amp;hellip;, demandplot20.pdf, and all with similar captions. Clearly a loop was required. After all, LaTeX is a programming language, so we should be able to take advantage of its capabilities.I found the forloop package which handled the problem perfectly. My first attempt looked like this:
\newcommand{\demandplot}[1]{\begin{figure}\centering \includegraphics[width=\textwidth]{./figs/demandplot#1.pdf} \caption{Hourly demand (GW) for zone #1.} \end{figure}} \newcounter{loop} \forloop{loop}{1}{\value{loop}&amp;lt;21}{\demandplot{\arabic{loop}}}  The magic happens in the last line providing a loop from 1 to 20, generating the commands \demandplot{1}, \demandplot{2}, &amp;hellip;, \demandplot{20}.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Young Stats Communication Challenge</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ysc2013comp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 22:07:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/ysc2013comp/</guid>
      <description>The Australian Young Statisticians Conference (Feb 2013) is organizing a communication competition. They invite all early-career statisticians (studying, or within 5 years of graduation) to produce a short (3-5 minute) video for the ABS YSC2013 Video Competition, or a static infographic for the ABS YSC2013 Infographic Competition.
Both competitions have a 1st prize of $500, and 2nd prize of $250.
Entries close 16th November, and winners will be notified by mid-December.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data visualization</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/data-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2012 22:37:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/data-visualization/</guid>
      <description>For those who have not read the seminal works of Tufte and Cleveland, please hang your heads in shame. To salvage some sense of self-worth, you can then head over to Solomon Messing&amp;rsquo;s blog where he is starting a series on data visualization based on the principles developed by Tufte and Cleveland (with R examples).
The classics are also worth reading, and remain relevant despite the 20 or 30 years that have elapsed since they appeared.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data visualization videos</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/data-visualization-videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 04:05:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/data-visualization-videos/</guid>
      <description>Probably everyone has seen Hans Rosling&amp;rsquo;s famous TED talk by now. If not, here it is:
  I recently came across a couple of other exceptional talks on data visualization:
Hans Rosling again: &amp;rdquo;Let my dataset change your mindset&amp;rdquo;. If only all statistics lecturers were this dynamic!
  David McCandless: &amp;ldquo;The beauty of data visualization&amp;rdquo;. Not so exciting as Hans, but some great examples.
  And here&amp;rsquo;s an hour-length documentary hosted by Hans Rosling called &amp;ldquo;The Joy of Stats&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animated plots in R and LaTeX</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Oct 2010 04:45:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/animations/</guid>
      <description>I like to use animated plots in my talks on functional time series, partly because it is the only way to really see what is going on with changes in the shapes of curves over time, and also because audiences love them! Here is how it is done.
For LaTeX, you need to create every frame as a separate graphics file. Here is an example. First the R code:
library(demography) nyears &amp;lt;- length(fr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twenty rules for good graphics</title>
      <link>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2010 06:34:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://robjhyndman.com/hyndsight/graphics/</guid>
      <description>One of the things I repeatedly include in referee reports, and in my responses to authors who have submitted papers to the International Journal of Forecasting, are comments designed to include the quality of the graphics. Recently someone asked on stats.stackexchange.com aboutbest practices for producing plots. So I thought it might be helpful to collate some of the answers given there and add a few comments of my own taken from things I&amp;rsquo;ve written for authors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>